When building clean components, we want to
ensure everything is strongly typed, our
styles are encapsulated, we respond to
appropriate life cycle events, and we
transform data to user friendly values as
needed. Welcome back to Angular: Getting
Started from Pluralsight. My name is
Deborah Kurata, and in this module we
learn several ways to approve upon our
components. Components are one of the key
building blocks of our application. The
cleaner, stronger and more durable we make
these blocks, the better our application.
So how can we make our components better?
Strong typing helps minimize errors
through better syntax checking and
improved tooling. But what if there is no
predefined type for a property? To
strongly type a property that has no
predefined type, we define the type
ourselves using an interface. If a
component needs special styles, we can
encapsulate those styles within the
component to ensure they don't leak out to
any other component in the application. A
component has a lifecycle managed by
Angular. Angular provides a set of
lifecycle hooks we can use to tap into key
points in that lifecycle, adding
flexibility and responsiveness to our
application. As we saw in the last module,
pipes provide a convenient way to
transform bound data before displaying it
in the view. We may have other application
unique data transformation requirements.
Luckily, we can build our own custom
pipes. Any time we build and test a
component once and nest it in several
places in the application, we have
minimized development time and improve the
overall quality of the application. In
this module, we explain interfaces and
demonstrate how to use them to strongly
type our objects. We look at how to
encapsulate component styles. We introduce
the component lifecycle and how to hook
into its events, and we detail how to
build a custom pipe. We cover building
nested components in the next module.
Looking at our application architecture,
in this module we'll add features to
improve the product list component. Let's get started.