One of the benefits of using TypeScript is
its strong typing. Every property has a
type, every method has a return type, and
every method parameter has a type. The
strong typing helps minimize errors
through better syntax, checking, and
tooling. In some cases, however, we have a
property or method that does not have a
predefined type such as our products array
here. We defined our products array as
any, which negates the benefits of strong
typing. To specify custom types, we can
define an interface. An interface is a
specification identifying a related set of
properties and methods. A class commits to
supporting the specification by
implementing the interface. That means the
class includes code for each property and
method identified in the interface. We can
then use the interface as a data type. ES5
and ES2015 do not support interfaces, but
TypeScript does, so interfaces are
transpiled out and are not found in the
resulting JavaScript. This means that
interfaces are development time only.
Their purpose is to provide strong typing
and better tooling support as we build,
debug, and maintain our code. Here is an
example of a TypeScript interface. We
define an interface using the interface
keyword, followed by the interface name,
which is often the name of the business
object that the interface describes. By
many naming conventions, the interface is
prefixed with an I for interface, though
some TypeScript developers leave off this
prefix. The export keyword here at the
front exports this interface, thereby
making it available for use anywhere in
the application. The body of the interface
defines the set of properties and methods
appropriate for this business object. For
each property, the interface includes
property name, a colon, and the property
data type. For each method, the interface
includes the method name, the list of
parameters, along with their data types, a
colon, and the method return type. To use
the interface as a data type, we import
the interface, then use the interface name
as the data type. Looks easy enough, let's
try it out. We are back in the sample
application, looking at the ProductList
component. Here we see that we defined our
products array as any, so let's create an
interface that defines what a product is.
We'll put the interface into its own file
in the products folder. We'll name that
file product.ts after the business object
it defines. We first type the export
keyword to ensure the other parts of the
application can use this interface. That
is, after all, why we are creating it.
Next, we type in the interface keyword,
then the name of the interface. I like to
use the I prefix to distinguish the
interface from the business object, and we
are defining a product, so IProduct.
Inside the interface, we define the
properties and methods appropriate for the
business object. For our sample
application, we only need properties. For
each property, we define the property
name, a colon, and the type of the
property. Notice that we are typing the
releaseDate as a string. If we later work
with this value as a date object, we could
change this type to a date. That's it.
That's all we have to do to define an
interface. Now we can use this interface
as our data type in the ProductList
component. Before we do though, let's try
something. Let's introduce a typographical
error into our products array. No error is
detected. We won't even know we made a
mistake until we see the application in
the browser. And we notice that no image
is displayed for one of the products. As
you can imagine, these kinds of errors
could cause hard‑to‑find bugs. Now let's
replace the any with IProduct. We get a
syntax error. What did we miss? Yep, we
need an import, and bang. Now that our
array of products is strongly typed, we
are notified that we made an error in our
product array property. We don't even have
to view it in the browser to see that
something is amiss. So this is a good
demonstration of one of the benefits of
strong typing. Let's fix that error.
Notice that we get IntelliSense now for
these properties, another great benefit of
strong typing. Let's check this out in the
browser. Now everything works as it did.
In our interface file, we could define a
class for the product business object here
as well, something like this. In general,
we only create a business object class if
that class provides some functionality
that we want to use throughout our
application, such as this
calculateDiscount method. And if we think
we might want to create a business object
at some point in the future, then we
definitely want to add the I prefix to our
interface, but for our sample application,
we don't need any product methods, so we
don't really need a product class. We will
use this interface throughout the
application to strongly type our products.
Next, let's look at encapsulating components styles.