When we build a template for a component,
we sometimes need styles unique to that
template. For example, if we build a
sidebar navigation component, we may want
special LI or dev element styles. When we
nest a component that requires special
styles within a container component, we
need a way to bring in those unique
styles. One option is to define those
styles directly in the templates HTML, but
that makes it harder to see, reuse, and
maintain those styles. Another option is
to define the styles in an external style
sheet. That makes them easier to maintain,
but that puts the burden on the container
component to ensure the external style
sheet is linked in the index.html. That
makes our nested components somewhat more
difficult to reuse, but there is a better
way. To help us out with this issue, the
Component decorator has properties to
encapsulate styles as part of the
component definition. These properties are
styles and styleUrls. We add unique styles
directly to the component using the styles
property. This property is an array, so we
can add multiple styles separated by
commas. A better solution is to create one
or more external style sheets and identify
them with the styleUrls property. This
property is an array, so we can add
multiple style sheets separated by commas.
By encapsulating the styles within the
component, any defined selectors or style
classes are only applicable to the
component's template and won't leak out
into any other part of the application.
Let's try this out. Before we change any
code, let's look again at our ProductList
view in the browser. Notice the table
headers, they could use a little color, so
let's build an external style sheet for
our ProductList component. We'll add a new
file in the products folder, and since
this file only contains the styles for our
ProductList component, we'll call it
product‑list.component.css. In the style
sheet, we add a table header style. We can
modify the thead element styles directly
because the style sheet is encapsulated in
this component, and the styles defined
here won't affect any other component in
the application. We could add any other
styles as needed to jazz up our
ProductList component. To use this new
style sheet, we modify the ProductList
component. In the Component decorator, we
specify our unique style sheet. We add the
styleUrls property and pass it an array.
In the first element to the array, we
specify the path to our style sheet. Since
we defined the CSS file in the same folder
as the component, we can use the ./
relative pass syntax. We could add more
style sheets here separated with commas.
Let's review the result in the browser,
and we see that the table header is now a
nice blue color. We can use the styles or
styleUrls property of the Component
decorator anytime we want to encapsulate
unique styles for our component. Next up, let's dive into lifecycle hooks.