A component has a lifecycle managed by
Angular. Angular creates the component,
renders it, creates and renders its
children, processes changes when it's data
bound properties change, and then destroys
it before removing its template from the
DOM. Angular provides a set of lifecycle
hooks we can use to tap into this
lifecycle and perform operations as
needed. Since this is a Getting Started
course, we'll limit our focus to the three
most commonly used lifecycle hooks. Use
the OnInit lifecycle hook to perform any
component initialization after Angular has
initialized the data bound properties.
This is a good place to retrieve the data
for the template from a backend service,
as we'll see later in this course. Use the
OnChanges lifecycle hook to perform any
action after Angular sets data bound input
properties. We have not yet covered input
properties, we'll see those in the next
module. Use the OnDestroy lifecycle hook
to perform any cleanup before Angular
destroys the component. To use a lifecycle
hook, we implement the lifecycle hook
interface. We talked about interfaces
earlier in this module. Since Angular
itself is written in TypeScript, it
provides several interfaces we can
implement, including one interface for
each lifecycle hook. For example, the
interface for the OnInit lifecycle hook is
OnInit. Notice that it is not prefixed
with an I. We are using the OnInit
interface from Angular. So any guesses as
to our next step? Yep, we need to import
the lifecycle hook interface. We can then
write the hook method. Each lifecycle hook
interface defines one method whose name is
the interface name prefixed with ng for
Angular. For example, the OnInit interface
hook method is named ngOnInit. Our first
step here of implementing the interface is
actually optional. Recall from our
discussion of interfaces earlier in this
module that neither ES5 nor ES2015 support
interfaces. They are features of
TypeScript. That means that the interfaces
are transpiled out of the resulting
JavaScript, so we don't really have to
implement the interface to use lifecycle
hooks. We can simply write code for the
hook method. However, it is good practice
and provides better tooling when the
implement the interface. At this point in
our application, we don't need to
implement any lifecycle hooks, but we'll
use them in later modules, so let's try
them out now. We are looking at the
ProductList Component. We'll add the
OnInit lifecycle hook to this component.
First we implement the interface by adding
it to the class signature. Type implements
and the name of the interface, OnInit. The
interface name is showing an error, and we
know why, we don't have the import. Let's
add that now. Since OnInit is also
imported from Angular Core, we simply add
it to our first import statement. Now we
have another syntax error here. Class
ProductListComponent incorrectly
implements interface OnInit. As the
message states, now that we've implemented
the interface, we must write code for
every property and method in that
interface. The OnInit interface only
defines one method, ngOnInit, so we need
to write the code for the ngOnInit method.
We'll add it down here by the other
methods. Since we don't really need to do
anything with this at this point, we'll
just use cconsole.log to log a message to
the console. We can view the application
in the browser, and use the F12 developer
tools to open the console and view the
logged message. We can see our message
here. We'll use ngOnInit later in this
course. Up next, we'll build a custom pipe.