As we saw in the last module, we used
pipes for transforming bound properties
before displaying them in a view. There
are built‑in pipes that transform a single
value or an iterable list of data. We
covered these in the last module. In this
module, we want to build our own custom
pipe. For our sample application, the
product code is stored with a dash and
displayed that way here, but the users
would prefer to see the product code with
a space instead. We could build a custom
pipe to replace the dashes with spaces,
but let's build a more generalized custom
pipe that transforms any specified
character in a string to a space. The code
required to build a custom pipe may look
somewhat familiar at this point. It uses
patterns similar to other code we've
created in this course. Here is the class.
We add a Pipe decorator to the class to
define it as a pipe. Similar to the other
decorators we've used, this is a function,
so we add parentheses. We pass an object
to the function specifying the name of the
pipe. This is the name for the pipe used
in the template, as we'll see shortly. We
implement a PipeTransform interface, which
has one method, transform. We write code
in the transform method to transform a
value and return it. The first parameter
of the transform method is the value we
are transforming. In this example, we
transform a string. Any additional
parameters define arguments we can use to
perform the transformation. In our case,
we want to pass in the character that we
want to replace with spaces. The method
return type is also defined as a string
because we are returning the transformed
string. And of course, we have our import
to import what we need. Notice how similar
this looks to the components we've created
in this course. Angular provides a very
consistent coding experience. To use a
custom pipe in a template, simply add a
pipe and the pipe name. Include any
arguments required by the transformation
separated by colons. The value being
converted, our productCode here, is passed
in as the first argument to the transform
method. This is our pipe name. The colon
identifies a pipe parameter, so our dash
is passed in as the second argument to the
transform method. The passed‑in value is
then transformed as defined by the logic
within this method, and the transform
string is returned and displayed here. But
of course, that is not enough. We also
need to tell Angular where to find this
pipe. We add the pipe to an Angular
module. How do we know which Angular
module? Well, at this point, that's easy
because we only have one, AppModule. But
if we had multiple modules, we'd added to
the module that declares the component
that needs the pipe. In our example, the
ProductList‑Component's template needs the
pipe, so we add the declaration to the
same Angular module that declares the
ProductList‑Component. We define the pipe
in the declarations array of the NgModule
decorator. Now let's build our custom
pipe. Recall that our requirement is to
transform a string so that any dashes on
the string are instead displayed as
spaces. But we are going to build a more
generic pipe that can replace any
specified character with a space. Since
our custom pipe is somewhat general, we'll
add it to the shared folder. We'll create
a new file and call it
convert‑to‑spaces.pipe.ts, following our
naming conventions. First, let's write the
code for the class. Export so we can
import this pipe where we need it, class,
and the class name. We'll call it
ConvertToSpacesPipe. We decorate the class
with the Pipe decorator and import Pipe
from Angular/core. We set the name
property of the object passed into the
Pipe decorator, defining the pipe's name.
That's the name we'll use when we
reference the pipe in the HTML. Next,
we'll implement the PipeTransform
interface. This syntax error is because we
don't have the import statement, so let's
add that next. We still have a syntax
error because when we implement the
PipeTransform interface, we are required
to implement every property and method
defined in that interface. For the
PipeTransform interface, there is only one
method, transform. We'll define the string
value to transform as the first parameter
and the character string to use in the
transformation as the second parameter,
and we can add a return statement to get
rid of this last syntax error. Now, what
do we want to transform method to do? Our
goal is to replace any of the specified
characters in a string with spaces. We'll
use the JavaScript string replace method
to replace the specified character with a
space. That's it. Now we are ready to use
our pipe. In the product‑list template,
we'll add our pipe to the productCode. But
the productCode already has a pipe. That's
okay. We can add any number of pipes.
First, we specify the pipe name and then
any pipe parameters. In this case, we want
to replace a dash with the space, so we
pass in a dash here as the parameter. Are
we done? Let's check by opening the
Terminal window. We see an error. No pipe
found with name convertToSpaces. What did
we forget? Recall from the slides that we
need to tell Angular about our new pipe.
We do that by declaring the pipe in an
Angular module. Our
product‑list.component's template wants to
use the convertToSpaces pipe, so we open
the Angular module that declares the
product‑list.component, which in our
example is the app.module. We then add
ConvertToSpacesPipe to the declarations
and add the needed import. Now any
component declared in app.module can use
the ConvertToSpacesPipe. Are we ready to
try again? Success. Our product code now
appears with spaces instead of dashes.
Build a custom pipe anytime you need to
perform application‑unique data
transformations. Notice, however, that our
page interactivity is still not complete.
The product list is not yet filtering
based on the user‑entered filter criteria. Let's look at that next.