We have an input box here for the user to
enter a filtered string. The list of
products should then be filtered on the
entered string. How do we do that? One way
we can filter our list of products is to
use a pipe; however, Angular doesn't come
with a built‑in pipe to provide filtering
or sorting. As of the time of this
recording, the Angular documentation at
angular.io stated, "Angular doesn't offer
such pipes because they perform poorly and
prevent aggressive minification." If we
have a small amount of data that we are
filtering or sorting, we could build a
custom pipe anyway. But is there a better
way? Again from the Angular documentation,
the Angular team and many experienced
Angular developers strongly recommend
moving filtering and sorting logic into
the component itself. Okay, let's do that.
But how? Before we answer that question,
let's take a moment to talk about
JavaScript getters and setters. In
JavaScript, and hence in TypeScript, there
are two ways to define a property in a
class. We can declare a simple variable
for a property, as we have done previously
in this course, or we can define a getter
or a setter, or both. A getter defines a
read‑only property. A getter is useful if
we want to provide a property whose value
can be dynamically computed or when we
want to expose the value of an internal
variable, such as a property from a
service. Though it looks like a function,
a getter cannot have parameters, must have
a return type, and is accessed as a
property. Notice that there are no
parentheses here. A setter defines a
write‑only property. A setter is useful if
we want to execute code every time a
property is modified. It too looks like a
function. It must have one and only one
parameter, the set value, and no return
type. It is also accessed as a property.
Notice that there are no parentheses here.
We are assigning a value just like a
simple property, but a setter can't hold
an actual value. For that, we often need
what's called a backing field. The backing
field is often private and retains the set
value. I use an underscore to denote
private variables. Defining a getter and
setter with the same name results in a
property that we can read or write to, and
defining a backing field allows us to
retain the set value. Now let's see how
this helps us filter our list. Here is our
ProductListComponent. Let's think through
what we need to do. First, we need a
filtered list of products that we can bind
to. We can define a property for that
here. Why don't we just filter our
products array? Because once we filter the
products array, we lose our original data
and can't get it back without re‑getting
the data from its source. Next, we need a
way to know when the user changes the
filter criteria. We could use event
binding and watch for key presses or value
changes, but an easier way is to change
our listFilter property into a getter and
setter, like this. The property getter and
setter work just like the simple property.
When the data binding needs the value, it
will call the getter and get the value.
Every time the user modifies the value,
the data binding calls the setter, passing
in the changed value. If we want to
perform some logic every time the value is
changed, we can add it here in the setter.
We want to set our filtered products array
to the filtered list of products, like
this. Here, we are using the JavaScript
conditional operator to handle the
possibility that the listFilter string is
empty, null, or undefined. If there is a
listFilter value, this code filters on
that value. If the listFilter is not set,
the filtered products property is assigned
to the entire set of products, and that
makes sense. If there is no filter, we
should display all of the products. But we
skipped the messy part. What about this
performFilter method? I'll paste the code
and we can talk through it. This code
starts by converting the filter criteria
to lowercase. Why? So we can compare
apples to apples when we filter the
product list. We want a case insensitive
comparison. Then we return the filtered
list of products. Let's look closer at the
filter method call. We are using the array
filter method to create a new array with
elements that pass the test defined in the
provided function. We used the ES2015
arrow syntax to define that filter
function. For each product in the list,
the product name is converted to lowercase
and indexOf is used to determine if the
filter text is found in the product name.
If so, the element is added to the
filtered list. See the MDN entry for
filter at this link for more information
on the array filter function. There is one
more bit of code we need here. We want to
set default values for both the filtered
products and the listFilter properties.
The best place to set default values for
more complex properties is in the class
constructor. The class constructor is a
function that is executed when the
component is first initialized. We want to
set the filtered products to the full list
of products, and the default listFilter to
cart, like we had earlier. Our last step
then is to change our template to bind to
our filteredProducts property instead of
the products property. Now let's give it a
try. Our default filter is cart, so now we
only see the Garden Cart. Change the
filter, and we see different entries. It's
working! Not too shabby, not too shabby at
all. Let's finish up this module with some
checklists we can use as we work more with components.