We've covered several discrete topics in
this module, so we have a checklist for
each one. First interfaces. We use
interfaces to specify custom types such as
product in our sample application.
Interfaces are a great way to promote
strong typing in our applications. When
creating an interface, use the interface
keyword, in the body of the interface
define the appropriate properties and
methods, along with their types. And don't
forget to export the interface so it can
be used anywhere in our application. We
implement an interface, including built‑in
Angular interfaces, to ensure that our
class defines every property and method
identified in that interface. Add the
implements keyword and the interface name
to the class signature, then be sure to
write code for every property and method
in the interface. Otherwise, typescript
displays a syntax error. We can
encapsulate the styles for our component
in the component itself. That way, the
styles required for the component are
associated with the component alone and
don't leak into any other parts of the
application. Use the styles property of
the component decorator to specify the
template styles as an array of strings.
Use the styleUrls property of the
component decorator to identify an array
of external stylesheet paths. The
specified styles are then encapsulated in
the component. Lifecycle hooks allow us to
tap into a component's lifecycle to
perform operations. The steps for using a
lifecycle hook are import the lifecycle
hook interface, implement the lifecycle
hook interface in the component class.
This step is not required, but highly
recommended. Then write the code for the
hook method defined in the lifecycle hook
interface. To build a custom pipe, import
Pipe and PipeTransform. Create a class
that implements the PipeTransform
interface. This interface has one method,
Transform. Be sure to export the class of
the pipe can be imported from other
components. Write code in the Transform
method to perform the needed
transformation, and decorate the class
with the Pipe decorator. We can use a
custom pipe in any template anywhere we
can specify a pipe. In an Angular module,
import the pipe. In the metadata, declare
the pipe in the declarations array, then
any template associated with a component
declared in that Angular module can use
that pipe. In a template, immediately
after the property to transform, type a
pipe character, specify the pipe name, and
enter the pipe arguments, if any,
separated by colons. This module provided
a set of techniques for improving our
components. We walk through how to use an
interface to strongly type our custom
objects. We saw how to encapsulate styles
within a component. We were introduced to
the component lifecycle and how to tap
into that lifecycle with lifecycle hooks.
And we discovered how to build a custom
pipe that we can use in any component
template. So in this module we've
completed the product list component. Yay.
Next up, we'll see how to build nested components and build the star component.