Our user interface design may include
features that are complex enough to be
separate components or that are reusable
across our views. Welcome back to Angular:
Getting Started from Pluralsight. My name
is Deborah Kurata, and in this module, we
see how to build components designed to be
nested within other components, and we'll
discover how to establish communication
between the nested component and its
container component. Just like nesting
dolls, we can nest our components. We can
nest a component within another component,
and nest that component within yet another
component, and so on. And because each
component is fully encapsulated, we expose
specific inputs and outputs for
communication between a nested component
and its container, allowing them to pass
data back and forth. There are two ways to
use a component and display the
component's template. We can use the
component as a directive. We saw how to
use a component as a directive when we
displayed the app component template in
the index.html file. The pm‑root directive
is defined as the app component selector.
The template is then displayed within the
directive tags. We use the same technique
with nested components. Alternatively, we
can use a component as a routing target,
so it appears to the user that they've
traveled to another view. The template is
then displayed in a full‑page style view.
We'll use this technique later in this
course to route to our product list view.
Our product list view is currently used as
a directive, but that's only because we
have not yet covered routing. In this
course module, we'll focus on building a
nested component. So what makes a
component nestable? Technically speaking,
any of our components could be nested if
they have a selector to find in the
component decorator. But does it really
make sense to nest a large view such as
our product list? For our purposes, we'll
define a component as nestable if it's
template only manages a fragment of a
larger view, if it has a selector so it
can be used as a directive, and,
optionally, if it communicates with its
container. In this module, we'll build a
nested component. Then we'll review how to
use that nested component as a directive
in a container component. We'll examine
how to pass data to the nested component
using a property with the input decorator
and how to pass data out of the nested
component by raising an event to find with
the output decorator. In our sample
application, to improve the user
experience, we want to replace the rating
number displayed in the product list
component with stars. In this module,
we'll build the star component and nest it
within the product list component. Let's get started.