Here is a visual representation of a
component that is nestable. Here is
another component. It wants to use the
nestable component in its template. We
then refer to the outer component as the
container or a parent component, and we
refer to the inner component as the nested
or child component. When building an
interactive application, the nested
component often needs to communicate with
its container. The nested component
receives information from its container
using input properties, and the nested
component outputs information back to its
container by raising events. In our sample
application, we want to change the display
of the five‑star rating from this to this.
Displaying the rating number using a
visual representation such as stars makes
it quicker and easier for the user to
interpret the meaning of the number. This
is the nested component we'll build in
this module. For the star component to
display the correct number of stars, the
container must provide the rating number
to our star component as an input. And if
the user clicks on the stars, we want to
raise an event to notify the container.
Let's jump right in and build our star
component. When we last saw our sample
application, we had completed the product
list component. Now, of course, we want to
change it. Instead of displaying a number
for the rating here, we want to display
stars. Instead of adding a code to the
product list component to display the
stars, we want to build it as a separate
component. This keeps the template and
logic for that feature encapsulated and
makes it reusable. So let's begin by
creating a star component. The star
component can be used by any feature of
the outfit application so it really
doesn't belong in our products folder.
We'll instead put it in a shared folder
where we'll put all our shared components.
If you are using the starter files. I've
already created this folder and included
the template and style sheet for our
component here. Let's take a quick look at
the style sheet. Notice that we have a
style here that helps with cropping our
stars. Now we are ready to build the star
component. We begin by creating a new
file. We'll name its star.component.ts. We
then create this component just like we'd
create any other component, starting with
the class. Export class starComponent.
What's next? Yes. We decorate the class
with the component decorator. Recall that
it is this component decorator that makes
this class a component. As always, it
shows us a syntax error here, because
we're missing, yes, our import. Time to
set the component decorator properties.
For the selector, we'll set pm‑star. For
the template URL, we provide the path to
the HTML file provided with the starter
files. We'll add the style URL's property,
and in the array we'll set the first
element to the path of the style sheet
that was also provided. Since both files
are in the same folder as the component,
we can use relative pathing. Now let's
take a peek at the star component
template. Here it displays five stars. It
then crops the stars based on a defined
width. This technique can then display
partial stars such as 4‑1/2 of the 5 stars
by setting the with such that only 4‑1/2
of the stars appear. Recall what this
syntax is called? This is property
binding. We're using it here to set the
style width, and here to bind the title
property to display the numeric rating
value. For these bindings to work, we need
two properties in the components class;
the rating and the star width. Let's add
these two properties. We want a rating
property, which is a number and defines
the rating value. Since we don't yet have
a way to get this value, let's hard code
it to four for now so we'll see some
stars, and we need the star width. This
value is calculated based on the rating.
So where do we put that calculation? Well,
we'd want the star width recalculated
anytime the container changed the rating
number. So let's tap into the OnChanges
lifecycle hook as we discussed in the last
module. We'll implement the OnChanges
interface, and we'll write code for the
ngOnChanges method identified in the
onChanges interface. In this method, we'll
convert the rating number to a star width
based on the width of our stars. Our
component is now complete and we're ready
to nest it in another component. How do we do that?