Now we are ready to nest our new component
within another component. We do that by
using our nested component as a directive
and following the same steps we covered
earlier in this course. Here is a
shortened form of the code for a container
component and its template. And here is
the nested component we just created.
Instead of displaying the starRating
number, we want to display the stars. So
the container component uses the nested
component by specifying its directive
here. This identifies where in the
container to place the nested components
template. As we've seen in prior demos,
when we use the component as a directive,
we need to tell Angular how to find that
directive. We do that by declaring the
nested component in an Angular module. How
do we know which Angular module? Well, we
still only have one Angular module,
AppModule. In our example, the ProductList
components template wants to use the
StarComponent, so we add the declaration
to the same Angular module that declares
the ProductList component. We define the
nested component in the declarations array
of the NgModule decorator and, as always,
define what we need by adding an import
statement. Let's jump right back to our
demo. Our star.component is now shown here
on the right. We want to use our
StarComponent in the ProductList template
that is here on the left. In the table
data element, we want to replace the
display of the starRating number with our
StarComponent. To do that, we simply
replace the binding with our directive.
Now our ProductList template will display
our stars here. Next, we need to tell
Angular where to find this directive.
Since we only have one Angular module,
we'll add the declaration for the nested
component there. Add the StarComponent to
the declarations array passed into the
NgModule decorator. These are the same
steps we followed earlier in this course
to use a component as a directive. Nothing
new here so far. Let's see what we did. We
have stars, yes, hmm, but we see five of
them. Let's clear out the filter. Yes, we
see five every time. Hover over the stars,
and we see our hard coded starRating is
four. It seems that our starWidth is not
being set. Let's look at the code again.
We set the starWidth property in the
ngOnChanges method when the OnChanges life
cycle event occurs, but the OnChanges life
cycle event never occurs because OnChanges
only watches for changes to input
properties. We don't have any input
properties, so we have two problems here.
Our OnChanges event does not fire, and we
don't currently have a way to get the
correct rating number from the container.
Let's see how input properties can solve both of these issues.