If a nested component wants to receive
Input from its container, it must expose a
property to that container. The nested
component exposes a property it can use to
receive Input from its container, using
the app we named Input decorator. We use
the Input decorator to decorate any
property in the nested components class.
This works with any property type,
including an object. In this example, we
want the rating number passed into the
nested component. So we mark that property
with the Input decorator. The container
component then passes data to the nested
component by setting this property with
property binding. When using property
binding we enclose the binding target in
square brackets. We set the binding source
to the data that the container wants to
pass to the nested component. In this
example, the product‑list template passes
the product's starRating number, the only
time we can specify a nested components'
property as a property binding target on
the left side of an equals, is when that
property is decorated with the Input
decorator. So in this example, the
product‑list template can bind to the
rating, but not the starWidth. Let's give
this a try. The StarComponent wants to
expose the rating property to its
container, so the container can provide
the rating number. We'll add the Input
decorator than to the rating property. The
Input decorator is a function, so we add
parentheses. We don't need to pass
anything to this function, so that's it.
And let's remove this default value, now
that we can get the value from the
container we don't need that here. In our
example, we decorate only one property of
the nested component with the Input
decorator, but we are not limited to one.
We can expose multiple Input properties as
needed. In the containers' template we use
property binding and define the nested
components Input property as the target of
the binding. Then we set the binding
source to the value we want to pass into
the nested component. In this example we
pass the product's starRating. That's it.
The product starRating property is now
bound to the rating Input property of the
nested component. Any time the container
data changes, the OnChanges life‑cycle
event is generated, and the starWidth is
recalculated. The appropriate number of
stars are then displayed. Let's check it
out in the browser. That looks better, but
what if we want to send data back from our
nested component to our container? Let's look at that next.