We just saw how the container passes data
to the nested component by binding to a
nested component property that is
decorated with the Input decorator. If the
nested component wants to send information
back to its container, it can raise an
event. The nested component exposes an
event it can use to pass output to its
container using the aptly named Output
decorator. We can use the Output decorator
to decorate any property of the nested
component's class. However, the property
type must be an event. The only way a
nested component can pass data back to its
container is with an event. The data to
pass becomes the event payload. In
Angular, an event is defined with an
EventEmitter object. So here we create a
new instance of an EventEmitter. Notice
the syntax here. TypeScript supports
generics. If you are not familiar with
generics, this syntax allows us to
identify a specific type that the object
instance will work with. When creating an
EventEmitter, the generic argument
identifies the type of the event payload.
If we want to pass a string value to the
container in the event payload, we define
string here. If we want to pass an
integer, we define number here. If we want
to pass multiple values, we can specify an
object here. In this example, we define a
notify event with a string payload. When
the user clicks on the stars, the
StarComponent receives that click event.
We use event binding in the StarComponent
template to call the StarComponent's
onClick method. In the onClick method, we
use the notify event property and call its
emit method to raise the notify event to
the container. If we want to pass data in
the event payload, we pass that data into
the emit method. In this example, the
onClick method raises the notify event and
sets the event payload to a string
message. The container component receives
that event with the specified payload. In
the container component's template, we use
event binding to bind to this notify event
and call a method. We access the event
payload using $event. The only time we can
specify a nested component's property as
an event‑binding target on the left side
of an equals is when that property is
decorated with the Output decorator.
Lastly, the container component provides
the method to execute when the notify
event occurs. Since the event payload is a
string, this function takes in a string.
Here we can perform any desired action.
Hmm, lots of moving parts here. Let's jump
into the code and try it out. We are back
in the sample application looking at the
StarComponent. What is our goal? When the
user clicks on one of the rating stars, we
want to display that rating in the header.
This feature may not be incredibly useful,
but it will demonstrate how to pass events
from our nested child component to the
parent container component. So our first
task is to respond to the user's click
event on the star rating. We do that using
event binding in the StarComponent's
template. We'll bind the div element's
click event to an onClick method in the
StarComponent class. Next, let's implement
this onClick method in the component. Hmm,
somehow in this method, we need to send
out a notification of this click to the
container. For now, let's just log out
that the rating was clicked. In this
example, we use the ES2015 backticks to
define a template string. This allows us
to embed the rating directly into this
string. Let's try it out in the browser.
Open the developer tools and click on the
rating stars. We see it log to the console
here. Going back to the code, we need to
send out a notification to the container
when the user clicks on the star rating of
the nested component. Recall from the
slides how the nested component
communicates with its container. It uses
an event with the Output decorator. Let's
define an event property in the nested
component. We'll call it ratingClicked.
Since this must be an event, we define the
type of this property to be EventEmitter.
We'll use the provided quick fix toe add
EventEmitter to the import statement. We
want to pass a string to the container as
part of this event, so we specify string
as the generic argument. We then set the
ratingClicked property to a new instance
of EventEmitter. This sets up our event.
Next, we decorate our event property with
the Output decorator so that the container
can respond to this event. The Output
decorator is a function, so we add
parentheses. In this example, we are
decorating only one property of the nested
component with the Output decorator, but
we are not limited to one. We can expose
multiple output properties as needed as
long as they're events. Here in our
onClick method, we want to raise this
event to the container and pass along our
message. We use the event property and
call its emit method, passing in the
desired string. The emit method raises the
event. Now that we are raising this
ratingClicked event to our container, how
does the container listen for and respond
to this event? It uses event binding. In
this example, our container is the
ProductListComponent. In the
ProductListComponent template, we bind to
the event raised from the StarComponent
using event binding. For event binding, we
use parentheses and specify the name of
the event to listen for. We want to listen
for the ratingClicked event raised by the
StarComponent. Now what do we want to do
when the event is raised? We'll need to
define a method in the
ProductListComponent class to process the
event. Let's call that method
onRatingClicked. Recall that we are
passing a string when raising this event,
so let's pass that string into our
onRatingClicked method. We do that using
$event. $event passes along any
information associated with the generated
event. Next, we need to write the code for
this method in the ProductListComponent
class. Our template is expecting that we
have a method called onRatingClicked, and
it's passing a string message with the
event. Our method returns no value, so we
define the return type as void. Now that
we have the message from the event, what
do we want to do with it? Our goal was to
display it on the page title, so we'll
modify the page title to display product
list and the message from the nested
StarComponent. Okay yeah, that is not a
very real‑world example, but I wanted to
keep this as straightforward as possible.
We'd have a better example if the nested
component contained an input box and we
could pass the user's input in the event
payload. But you get the general idea
here. Let's see how this works in the
browser. Click on the star rating, and we
see the page title change to display the
message received from the nested
component. Success! We just saw how the
container passes data to the nested
component by binding to a nested component
property that is decorated with the Input
decorator and how the nested component
uses an event property decorated with the
Output decorator to raise events. We can
think of the properties decorated with the
Input or Output decorators as the public
API of the nestable component. Everything
else in the component is encapsulated and
only accessible to the component's
template and class. Let's finish up this
module with some checklists we can use as we build nestable components.