We build a nested component using the same
techniques we use to build any other
Angular component. We won't review that
again here. Let's instead lay out a
checklist for inputs and outputs. Decorate
a nested component property with the input
decorator anytime it needs input data from
its container. Any type of component
property can be decorated with the input
decorator. Don't forget the @ prefix, and
since the input decorator is a function,
follow it with open and closing
parentheses. Decorate a nested component
property with the output decorator anytime
it needs to raise events and optionally
pass information back to its container.
Only properties of type EventEmitter
should be marked with the output
decorator. Use the EventEmitter's generic
argument to specify the type of the event
payload, and use the new keyword to create
an instance of the EventEmitter. Don't
forget the @ prefix, and since the output
decorator is a function, suffix it with
open and closing parentheses. In a
container component's template, use the
nested component as a directive. For the
name of the directive, see the nested
component's selector property. Use
property binding to pass data to the
nested component. Any property of the
nested component that is decorated with
the input decorator can be used as a
binding target. Use event binding to
respond to events from the nested
component. Any event that is decorated
with the output decorator can be used as
the binding target, and use $event to
access the event payload passed from the
nested component. To learn more about
nested or child components, check out the
Angular Component Communication course
here in the Pluralsight library. This
module was all about nested components. We
began by building a component that could
be nested within other components. We then
walked through how to use the nested
component within a container. We saw how
to pass data into the nested component by
binding to a property marked with the
input decorator, and we discovered how to
pass data out of the nested component by
raising an event marked with the output
decorator. In this module, we built the
star component and nested it within the
ProductListComponent. We can reuse this
component in any other component of the
application such as the
ProductDetailComponent. Next up, let's
check out how to build an Angular service
so we won't need hard‑coded product data in our component.