Now that we know the basics of routing,
we're ready for more. Welcome back to
Angular: Getting Started from Pluralsight.
My name is Deborah Kurata, and in this
module, we look at several additional
routing techniques. With what we learned
in the prior module, a user can now
navigate to any defined route in our
application. But that only covered the
very basic routing scenarios. What if we
need to pass parameters to a route or
activate a route with code instead of with
a clickable element? Or what if we need to
protect a route and only allow access to
it in special cases or by certain users or
ask a user to save changes before leaving
a route? In this second module on routing,
we examine how to pass parameters to a
route, how to activate a route with code,
and how to protect our routes with guards.
When we're finished with this module,
we'll know how to handle additional
routing scenarios, including routing to a
component that requires parameters, such
as our product detail component. Let's get started.