We sometimes need to pass parameters to a
route. For example, to navigate to the
product detail view. we need to define
which products details to display. The
first step to passing parameters to a
route is to configure the route with
parameters. We've already done this step
to route to our product detail component.
Here we define a slash, a colon, and a
placeholder for the parameter. If multiple
parameters are needed, we'd repeat this
with another slash, colon, and
placeholder. With the route definition in
place, we can decide where we want the
user to activate this route. Will we add a
menu option or a data link? It is there we
set the router link and pass in the
required parameter. In the product list
component template, we display a table of
products. Each table row contains the
product name so we add a router link to
this anchor tag and assign it to the link
parameters array. The first element of the
array is the string path of the route. The
second element of the array is the value
for the route parameter. When the router
composes the URL, it uses this array
element to construct the defined
parameter. To display the appropriate
product, the product detail component
reads this parameter from the URL. It then
uses the parameter to retrieve the
appropriate product and display it in the
view. To get the parameter from the URL,
we use the activated route service
provided by the router. We want an
instance of the service so we define it as
a dependency in our constructor. We've
seen this syntax before. This line of code
defines a private variable called route
and assigns it to the instance of the
activated route provided by the Angular
service injector. Then we use the instance
of the activated route service to get the
desired parameter. There are two different
ways to get the parameter. We could use a
snapshot or we could use an observable.
Use the snapshot approach if you only need
to get the initial value of the parameter.
The code is then a one‑liner, as shown
here. In our example, the user is always
returned to the list page before
navigating to another product so the
snapshot approach would be sufficient. If
you expect the parameter to change without
leaving the page, use an observable. For
example, if we had a Next button on the
product detail page to display the next
product, the URL will change to the next
product's id. So you'd want to use an
observable instead. We use the activated
routes snapshot method here and access the
appropriate parameter from its parameter
array. The string specified here must
match the name of the parameter from the path. Let's give this a try.