In this demo, we pass a parameter as part
of the ProductDetailRoute and read that
parameter in the ProductDetailComponent.
We already have the
ProductDetailComponent's route configured
with a parameter. Looking at that route,
here in the path, we provide any
parameters prefixed with a colon and
separated by slashes. For the
ProductDetailComponent, we pass a product
id so the view knows which product's
detail to display. Next, we need to decide
where to tie this route to a user action.
We can't add the product detail to the
menu because we don't have an easy way for
the user to specify the ID of the desired
product. Let's instead modify the list of
products in the product list view such
that each product name is a link, then the
user can click on the product to display
its details. In the product‑list template,
we'll add an anchor tag so the productName
becomes a link. We add the routerLink
directive to the anchor tag and set up the
link parameter's array. In the array, we
define the path of the route to activate
in the first element and pass the
parameter value in the second element. In
this example, we want to pass the
product's ID. When we view the result in
the browser, we see that the product names
are now links. And if we click a link, we
see the ID in the URL, and we navigate to
the ProductDetailComponent. But that
component does not yet get the parameter
from the URL. Let's do that next. We add
code in the ProductDetailComponent to get
the parameter passed in on the URL. We use
the activated route service provided by
the router to help us. First, we import
the service. We don't have to register
this service. Because it is registered as
part of the router module, we add it to
the imports array in the last course
module. We then set ActivatedRoute as a
dependency by defining it as a parameter
to the constructor function. The
ActivatedRoute instance is then injected
into this component class. Now let's get
the ID from the route and store it in a
local variable. We'll use the snapshot
approach here because we don't expect the
URL to change. Where do we put the code to
read the parameter? We don't want it in
the constructor. We'll instead use the
OnInIt lifecycle hook. We start by reading
the parameter into a variable. We use let
here, which is new in ES2015 and defines a
block scoped variable. We then use
this.route.snapshot to get the parameter.
We pass in the name of the parameter we
want to read. The parameter name we
defined in the route configuration is id,
so that's the parameter name we specify
here. And because the parameter is
provided as a string, we'll add a + here
at the beginning. The + is a JavaScript
shortcut to convert the parameter string
to a numeric ID. At this point, we could
add code here to retrieve the desired
product using this ID. But since we are
focused in this module on routing and not
on HTTP, we'll hard code the product here.
To make it easy to see the ID we got from
the URL, let's display it as part of the
pageTitle. Here, we use the ES2015
backticks to define a template string and
display the ID. Let's see the result in
the browser. Click the menu option to
display the Product List, then click a
product. The URL changes to include the
parameter and the product detail page is
displayed. If everything worked, the title
displays the same parameter as shown in
the URL. Yeah! To get back to the Product
List, we could use the menu option here,
but it would be nicer to have a back
button. Let's add a back button and see how to activate a route with code.