We want to add a Back button to our
product detail page that navigates back to
the product list page. We could activate
this route using the routerLink directive
in the component template, just like we
did with the menu options. But it's also
possible to route with code, so let's try
that out instead. When would you want to
navigate with code instead of the
routerLink directive and a template? One
example is a save button where you need to
execute some code to save the data and
then route. To route with code we use the
Router service. We import the Router
service from angular/router. We define a
dependency on the router service using a
constructor parameter. The router instance
is then injected into this component
class. Every time we inject a service
dependency into a class, we should ask
ourselves, hmm, did we register this
service with the Angular injector? In the
case of Router, it is registered in
RouterModule, which we added to our
application's Angular module imports
array. We use this router instance to
activate a route. Here we define a method
that we can call from the template based
on a user action. The code uses the
navigate method of the Router service and
passes in the same link parameter array we
use when binding the router link. In this
example, we route to the products route
and don't pass any arguments. Let's give
this a try. Here we are looking at the
ProductDetailComponent. We want the
ProductDetailComponent to navigate back to
the ProductListComponent. We define the
router as a dependency by adding another
constructor parameter. When this component
class is constructed we'll get an instance
of both the ActivatedRoute service and the
Router service. Now we can build a method
that navigates with code. Since the
purpose of this method is to navigate
back, we'll call it onBack. It doesn't
return anything, so we'll set its return
type to void. In this method, we use the
this.router instance and call the navigate
method. We pass it a link parameters
array. In this example, we want to
navigate back to the ProductListComponent,
and we don't need any parameters. We just
define the route path, which is products.
In the product detail template, we'll add
a button. We again use the Twitter
Bootstrap style classes to give the button
some style. We use event binding to bind
the click event of the button to the
onBack method we defined in the class. Now
let's check it out in the browser. Click
on the menu option to display the product
list then click on a product. The product
detail page is displayed. We click our
Back button and we are back on the product
list page. Let's try another one. We see
the detail page. Now we're back on the
product list page. Our code‑based
navigation is working. So routing with
code involves importing the router and
using its navigate method to activate the
route. Now that we have several routes in
place, let's look at how to protect them with guards.