There may be times that we want to limit
access to a route. We want routes only
accessible to specific users such as an
administrator, for example, or we want the
user to confirm a navigation operation
such as asking whether to save before
navigating away from an edit page. For
that, we use guards. The Angular router
provides several guards, including
CanActivate to guard navigation to a
route, CanDeactivate to guard navigation
away from the current route, Resolve to
prefetch data before activating a route,
and CanLoad to prevent asynchronous
routing. In this clip, we work through how
to implement the CanActivate guard. You
can use the same techniques we're covering
here to implement any other type of route
guard. We'll build a guard that prevents
navigation to the ProductDetail route
unless a specific condition is true.
Building a guard clause follows the common
pattern used throughout Angular, create a
class, add a decorator, and import what we
need. Here we define a guard class. Since
we are implementing this guard as a
service, we use the Injectable decorator.
This class implements CanActivate. To
create one of the other kinds of guards,
change this to implement one of the other
guard types. We then implement the
CanActivate method. For simple cases, this
method can return a boolean value, true to
activate the route and false to cancel the
route activation. For more complex cases,
we could return an observable or a promise
from this method. Using a guard is simple.
We built the guard to protect the
ProductDetail route, so we add the guard
to the ProductDetail route. We add
CanActivate and set it to an array
containing the guards to execute before
this route is activated. In our case, there is only one. Let's give this a try.