In this demo, we protect our ProductDetail
route with a guard. We want to build a
guard that prevents navigation to the
ProductDetailComponent if the provided URL
parameter is not valid. Recall that the
route definition for the
ProductDetailComponent includes an id, but
there is nothing here that defines this id
to be numeric or greater than 0, so our
guard should prevent navigation to the
ProductDetail route if the id is 0 or not
a number. Our first step is to build our
guard. We could build it manually, but why
not use the Angular CLI? We open the
integrated terminal and type ng, for the
Angular CLI, g, for generate, g, for
guard, and the name of our guard. Since
this guard is for the ProductDetail route,
we add it to the products folder. So,
products/product‑detail. That's all that
is required. Press Enter, and the Angular
CLI prompts us to select the type of guard
we want to generate. We can select one or
more guards. For our example, we only want
the CanActivate guard, so press space to
select it. Press Enter, and we see that
the CLI created the guard and the start of
a unit test for that guard. Let's open the
resulting guard. The CLI added all of the
basic boilerplate here for us. Yay! Let's
talk through it. Since a guard is a
service, it needs to be registered with an
Angular injector. The CLI registers this
guard with the root application injector
using the providedIn property. It
implements the CanActivate interface and
builds the start of the CanActivate
method. We can change this as needed if we
want to implement a different type of
guard. The CanActivate method has two
parameters, the ActivatedRouteSnapshot to
provide current route information, and the
RouterStateSnapshot to provide router
state information. The method can return
an observable, a promise, or a simple
Boolean value. All that's left is to write
the logic for the guard. What do we want
this method to do? We need to check the
route URL and ensure that the id passed in
is valid. If it is not valid, we want to
navigate back to the Product List page.
Navigation requires the router, so the
first thing we need is a constructor. Then
we inject in the router, letting VS Code
import the appropriate package. Next, in
the CanActivate, we need to read the
parameter from the route. Luckily for us,
CanActivate has a parameter that gives us
the ActivatedRouteSnapshot. The
ActivatedRouteSnapshot contains the
information about a route at any
particular moment in time. Now I'll paste
the code for the method body and we can
talk through it. The ProductDetail route
URL is comprised of two segments, product
and the requested id. We only care about
the id, so we pull the path from the
second element, which is index of 1. The
plus here at the beginning converts the
URL path string to a number. If the
resulting value is not a number, or less
than 1, we display an alert, direct the
user to the Product List page, and return
false to abort the current operation.
Notice that this code is the same code we
used to activate our route with code that
we saw in the last clip. And here we
return true to continue activating the
route. Now, we don't normally want to
display an alert from our application. In
a real application, we'd route to an error
page that would notify the user of the
problem and optionally provide a button
for navigating back to the Product List
page. But this is good enough for our
purposes. Next, we need to hook up this
guard to the appropriate route. We add the
CanActivate property to the route
definition for the ProductDetailComponent
and set it to an array. In the array, we
specify each guard we want to execute when
activating the ProductDetail route. In
this case, we have only one. That should
do it. Let's give it a try. If we view the
Product List page and select a product,
our URL is valid and we navigate to the
page. If we instead type in a URL that is
not a number, we see our message. The
ProductDetail route navigation is
cancelled and we are redirected to the
Product List page. It works! Use route
guards any time you want to prevent access
to a route, confirm navigation away from a
route, or preload data for a route. So
let's finish up this module with some checklists.