We can pass any number of parameters to a
route, separated by slashes. Add the
parameter to the route configuration path
by specifying a slash, a colon, and the
parameter name. Pass the parameter value
by adding it to an element of the link
parameters array bound to the routerLink
directive. Read the parameter value in the
navigated component using the
ActivatedRoute service. Notice here that
the parameter name, id in this example, is
exactly the same as in the route
definition. To activate a route with code,
use the router service. Be sure to import
the service and define it as a dependency
on the constructor. Create a method that
calls the navigate method of the router
service instance and pass in the link
parameters array. Add a user interface
element and use event binding to call the
created method. We can use guards to
prevent access to a route, confirm
navigation away from a route, or to
preload data for a route. To create a
router guard, we build a guard service,
implement the guard type, in our case
CanActivate, and create the associated
method. We then register the guard service
provider. Lastly, we add the guard to the
desired route. In this module, we covered
some additional routing techniques,
including passing parameters to a route,
activating a route with code, and
protecting routes with guards. But we've
only just touched on the basics. If you
are interested in learning more about
routing, check out my Angular Routing
course, here on Pluralsight. You'll learn
how to pass required, optional, and query
parameters on a route, how to fetch data
with route resolvers, how to define child
and secondary, or named, router outlets,
and more on router guards. Plus, you'll
see how to improve your application
performance with lazy loading. We now have
routing to our ProductDetailComponent.
Yay! However, the Product DetailComponent
and its associated template are not
finished. We only wired up the bare
minimum to demonstrate routing. As a
homework assignment, try building the
remainder of the product detail template
and code. To check your answer, you can
find the completed application on my
GitHub, as described in the First Things
First module. There, you will also find a
version of the product data service that
retrieves one product by id. You'll need
that to get the data for the
ProductDetailComponent. At this point, our
AppModule is looking a little cluttered
and hard to manage. Up next, let's spend
some more time with Angular modules and
look at how to refactor our application into more manageable pieces.