A single view does not an application
make. Welcome back to Angular: Getting
Started from Pluralsight. My name is
Deborah Kurata, and in these next two
modules, we define routes to navigate
between multiple views in our application.
Users like to have all of the information
they need at their fingertips, so our
applications often provide multiple sets
of data in multiple layouts across
multiple views. Routing provides a way for
the user to navigate between those many
views of the application. Whether there
are five, ten, or hundreds. In this
module, we start with an overview of how
routing works in Angular. We examine how
to configure routes and tie routes to
actions, and we define where to place the
routed components view. Currently, our APP
component embeds our product list
component as a nested component. We
instead want to define a set of routes so
the user can navigate to the welcome view,
product list view, or product detail view.
We've already built the
ProductListComponent, and I've provided
the WelcomeComponent with the starter
files in the GitHub repository for this
course. As part of the demos in this
module, we'll build the shell for the
product detail component. When we're
finished with this module, we'll have a
simple application that routes to multiple views.