Before we jump into routing, we need more
components so we have something to route
to. I provided the WelcomeComponent as
part of the starter files. Let's build the
ProductDetailComponent. The
ProductDetailComponent should ultimately
look like this, but we want to focus on
routing, not building another component.
So let's just create a shell for the
ProductDetailComponent so we can route to
it. We could use the Explorer and create
new component class and template files
manually, or we could use the Angular CLI
to automatically create those files. We
are going to spend more time on the CLI
later in this course, but if you want to
try it out now, start by opening a
terminal window. I'll use the integrated
terminal built into VS Code. If you don't
already have the CLI installed globally,
install it now using npm install ‑g, for
global, @angular/cli. Note that we will
then have the Angular CLI installed twice.
We installed it local to our project when
we installed the packages from our
package.json file at the beginning of this
course. This local install ensures that
our project is served and compiled using a
consistent version of the CLI. We access
this local version with our npm scripts,
such as npm start. This command installs
the Angular CLI globally and adds ng to
our system path. That allows us to type ng
commands directly from any folder. I
already have the Angular CLI installed
globally, so I won't install it again.
Next, we type ng for the Angular CLI, g,
for generate, c, for component, and the
name of our component. Since we want to
create this component under the products
folder, we add the path to the desired
component name, products/product‑detail,
following our naming convention. That's
all that is required. By default, however,
Angular will create a new folder for this
component. For the sample application, we
want the contents of our product folder to
be flat. We'll use the ‑‑flat option to
achieve this. We'll learn much more about
the Angular CLI later in this course. For
now, press Enter and the Angular CLI
creates the component files for us, and it
updated are Angular module. Yay! We can
see here in the Explorer that it created
the style sheet in a CSS file, the
template in an HTML file, and the class in
a TypeScript file. It even created the
start of a unit test for us. Let's check
out the generated template. Not much here.
We'll replace the generated HTML with some
placeholder text and use interpolation to
bind to a page title. Here, we include the
product's name in that title. If we
retrieve the product to display using
HTTP, which we most likely will, we could
have a problem with this code. Any idea
what could go wrong here? Recall from the
last module that HTTP is asynchronous.
This means that our page could attempt to
display the product's name before the
product is retrieved. At that point, the
product property is undefined, so we would
get a runtime error telling us it can't
read the property product name of
undefined. How do we ensure this error
doesn't happen to us? There are several
common ways to prevent undefined property
errors. We could use the safe navigation
operator defined with a question mark. The
safe navigation operator guards against
null and undefined values when navigating
an object's properties. If the product
object is null or undefined, the safe
navigation operator simply returns null
and does not attempt to access the
productName property. Hence, we don't see
an undefined property error. The safe
navigation operator is great, but it is
not always the best option. For example,
it does not work when used with the
ngModel two‑way binding. It can also be
quite tedious when we display many
properties, like in our detail template.
So there is another option. We can use
ngIf and check for the existence of the
product object. We add the ngIf to an HTML
element that encloses all references to
the product object. Then we don't need to
use the safe navigation operator. Next,
let's look at the TypeScript file. The
generated component class has all of the
basic syntax in place. All it needs is the
page title and product properties that we
are referencing in the template. Notice
that the CLI generated the selector
property here. The selector property is
only required if the component will be
nested within another component. We won't
need to nest this component, we'll instead
display the component's view as part of
the routing. So let's delete the selector.
Now let's check out the Angular module.
Notice that the CLI added the appropriate
import and declared our new component.
Very nice! Every time we add a component
to the application, we need to declare the
component in an Angular module. We
currently have only one Angular module,
AppModule, so the ProductDetailComponent
and the WelcomeComponent must be added to
the declarations array for the AppModule.
If we use the Angular CLI, as we did in
this example, it automatically adds the
appropriate declarations. Cool! If we
don't use the CLI, like for our
WelcomeComponent, we need to add the
component to the declarations array
ourselves. Let's do that now. We add the
WelcomeComponent to the declarations away,
then add the associated import statement.
Now that we have the basic components in
place, we are ready to add routing to our application.