An Angular application is a single‑page
application. That means all of our views
are displayed within one page, normally
defined in the index.html file. So each of
the 5, 10, or hundreds of views take turns
appearing on that one page. How do we
manage which few to display when? That's
the purpose of routing. We configure a
route for each component that wants to
display its view on the page. As part of
our application design, we provide a menu,
a toolbar, buttons, images, or data links
that allow the user to select the view to
display. We tie a route to each option or
action. When the user selects the option
or performs the action, the associated
route is activated. Activating a
component's route displays that
component's view. So, for example, the
user selects a menu option to display the
product list. The product list route is
activated and it displays its view. Hmm,
let's look at that process again with an
illustration. Here is the menu that we'll
add to our sample application. We tie a
route to teach menu option using a
built‑in router directive called
routerLink. When the user clicks on the
Product List option, for example, the
Angular router navigates to the product's
route. The browser's location URL changes
to match this path segment, and we see
/products appear in the address bar. By
default, Angular uses HTML5 style URLs,
which don't require the hash symbol to
indicate local navigation. By using the
HTML5 style URLs, you need to configure
your web server to perform URL rewriting.
How this is done depends on your web
server. See the documentation for your web
server on how to configure URL rewriting.
Angular also supports hash style routing,
which does not require URL rewriting.
We'll look at how to use hash style
routing later in this module. When the
browser's URL changes, the Angular router
looks for a route definition, matching the
path segment, products, in this example.
The route definition includes the
component to load when this route is
activated. In this case, the
ProductListComponent. The Angular router
then loads the component's template. Where
does it display this template? Where we
specified, with the built‑in routing
directive called router‑outlet, and the
Product List appears. So that's how
routing works. We'll examine these steps
in further detail and try them out in
demos as we journey through this course module.