Routing is component based, so we identify
the set of components that we want to
provide as routing targets and to find a
route for each one. Let's see how this is
done. An Angular application has one
router that is managed by Angular's router
service, and we know that before we can
use a service, we need to register the
service provider in an Angular module.
Similar to the HTTP module, Angular
provides a RouterModule in the
angular/router package that registers the
router service provider. To include the
features of this external module in our
application, we need to add it to the
Imports array of our application's Angular
module. In addition to registering the
service provider, the RouterModule also
declares the router directives. In the
last clip, we mentioned two router
directives, RouterLink and RouterOutlet.
By importing the RouterModule our
component templates can use these or any
other router directives. RouterModule also
exposes the routes we configure. Before we
can navigate to a route, we need to ensure
that the routes are available to the
application. We do this by passing the
routes to RouterModule like this. We call
the RouterModule's forRoot method and pass
our array of routes to that method. This
establishes the routes for the root of our
application. If we want to use hash‑style
routes instead of HTML5‑style routes, we
change this code to set useHash as shown
here. With that, we are ready to configure
some routes. The router must be configured
with a list of route definitions. Each
definition specifies a route object. Each
route requires a path. The path property
defines the URL pass segment for the
route. When this route is activated, this
URL pass segment is appended to the URL of
our application. The user can type in or
bookmark the resulting URL to return
directly to the associated component's
view. In most cases, we also specify a
component, which is the component
associated with the route. It is this
component's template that is displayed
when the route is activated. These are all
examples of route definitions. The first
route simply maps a specific URL pass
segment to a specific component. So this
URL displays the template from the
ProductListComponent. The :id in the
second route represents a route parameter.
The product detail page displays the
detail for one product, so it needs to
know which product to display. The
ProductDetailComponent reads the ID from
this pass segment and displays the defined
product. We can define any number of
parameters here separated with slashes.
What does this route do? Yep, this URL
displays the template from the welcome
component. This one defines the default
route. The redirect here translates the
empty route to the desired default pass
segment, in this example, the welcome
route. A redirect route requires a
pathMatch property to tell the router how
to match the URL pass segment to the path
of a route. We only want this default
route when the entire client‑side portion
of the path is empty, so we set the
pathMatch to full. The asterisks in the
last route denote a wildcard path. The
router matches this route if the requested
URL doesn't match any prior paths to find
in the configuration. This is useful for
displaying a 404 not found page or
redirecting to another route. A few things
to note here. There are no leading slashes
in our pass segments, and the order of the
routes in this array matters. The router
uses a first match wins strategy when
matching the routes. This means that more
specific routes should always be before
less specific routes such as the wildcard route. Ready to try this out?