In this demo, we configure the basic
routes for our application. We are back in
the sample application with the index.html
file open. The first step to set up
routing is to define a base element in the
head tag of the index.html file. Notice
that the Angular CLI already did that for
us here. This element tells the router how
to compose the navigation URLs. Since the
app folder is the application route, we'll
set the href for the base tag to /. Now we
are ready to configure the route
definitions. For that, we go to our
Angular module. Add the appropriate import
statement, then add RouterModule to the
imports array. This registers the router
service provider, declares the router
directives, and exposes the configured
routes. How does the RouterModule know
about are configured routes? We passed
them into the RouterModule by calling the
forRoot method. We then configure the
routes here by passing them in using an
array. Let's start with the product
routes. For each route, we specify the
path and a reference to the component. The
template defined in the specified
component will display when the router
navigates to this path. Next, we add the
route to display our welcome page. We'll
set the path to welcome and specify the
welcome component. When the application
loads, we want to default to the template
from the welcome component. So we'll
specify a default route that redirects to
our welcome component. And let's define a
wildcard path in case the requested URL
doesn't match any prior paths defined in
the configuration. This is often used for
displaying a 404 Not Found page. But in
our simple example, we'll use it to
redirect back to the welcome page. There's
a lot of stuff here now in our root
application module. In a later course
module, we'll look at how to refactor this
module into multiple Angular modules for a separation of concerns.