With routing, the user can navigate
through the application in several ways.
The user can click a menu option, link,
image, or button that activates or
navigates to a route. The user can type
the associated URL segment in the address
bar after the application URL, or use a
bookmark to that URL, or the user can
click the browsers' forward or back
buttons. The route configuration handles
the URLs so the last techniques will just
work. We need to handle the first
technique by tying routes to the user
actions. We need to decide how we will
show the routing options to the user. We
could display a navigation pane with
links, we can provide a toolbar or images,
or we can build a navigation menu like
this one. In a more full‑featured
application, the menu could have many more
options and sub options, but this will do
for our purposes. We define that menu as
part of this component's template. We then
need to tie a route to each menu option.
We do that using the routerLink directive.
The routerLink is an attribute directive,
so we add it to an element such as the
anchor tag here, and we enclose it in
square brackets. We bind it to a template
expression that returns a link parameters
array. The first element of this array is
the string path of a route. Additional
elements can be added to this array to
specify optional route parameters. The
router uses this array toe. Locate the
associated route and build up the
appropriate Earl based on any provided
parameters. When the user selects the
option, the Associated Road is activated.
Activating a component route displays that
component's view. Now let's add a menu and
use the router link directive so the user
can navigate to the views and our sample
application. First, we need to decide how
to show the routing options to the user.
For our sample application, we'll build a
menu. We want to add that menu at the root
of our application, so we'll add it to the
AppComponent. In the AppComponent template
currently, we're nesting the product list
component. Now that we are implementing
routing, we'll route to the product list
component instead. That means that it no
longer needs a selector. In the product
list component, let's remove that
selector. Going back to the AppComponent,
we'll replace the nesting with a
navigation menu. This menu uses the nav
element and the navbar classes from the
Twitter Bootstrap styling framework. Let's
see how this looks in the browser. Here is
our new menu, but clicking on the menu
options don't do anything yet, and our
product list no longer appears. We need to
tie routes to these menu options. We'll
use the router link directive to tie a
route to each of these menu options. For
the home menu option, we'll add the router
link to the anchor element, but we could
use any clickable element. We want to tie
the welcome route to the home menu option
so we specify Welcome here. Pay close
attention to this syntax. We assign the
router link directive to an array defined
within quotes. The first element of the
array is a string, so it is also enclosed
in quotes. We'll use similar syntax to tie
the products route to the product list
menu option. Now we just need to tell
Angular where to place our views and display the routed components template.