When a route is activated, the associated
components view is displayed, but
displayed where? How do we specify where
we want the routed component to display
its view? We use the router outlet
directive. We place that directive in the
host components template. The routed
components view then appears in this
location. Let's add the router outlet to
our sample application. We are back
looking at the app component, because it
is the host for our router. We add the
router outlet in the template where we
want to display the routed components
view. We'll put it here. Whenever a route
is activated, the associated components
view displays here. Let's see how that
looks in the browser. Oh my! Where did
that page come from? That's the welcome
page provided in the starter files. When
the application launches, the default
route is activated and the welcome view
displays. If we click on the product list
menu, the router link directive now
activates the product list route, and the
product list view appears. Sweet! Our
application component can now route to
multiple views. Notice the URL. The URL
segment we defined for the route is
displayed here. If we type in something
like Welcome, the welcome component's view
is displayed. Now that we have our routing
in place, let's review how these routing
features work together. When the user
navigates to a feature tied to a route
with a router link directive, the router
link uses the link parameters array to
compose the URL segment. The browsers
location URL is changed to the application
URL, plus the composed URL segment. The
router searches through the list of valid
route definitions and picks the first
match. The router locates or creates an
instance of the component associated with
that route. The components view is
injected in the location defined by the
router outlet directive, and the page is
displayed. We now have basic routing in
our sample application. Yay!. As we've
seen in this course module, routing is
rather intricate, requiring code in
multiple files and strings, such as
parameter names and route paths that must
match across those files. So let's finish
up this module with some checklists that
can help ensure all of the bits of routing are in the right places.