To route or to nest, that is the question.
When creating components, we need to think
about how they will be displayed. For
components designed to be nested within
other components, we need to define a
selector as part of the component
decorator. The selector provides the name
of the directive, and then we nest the
component within another component, using
the directive to define where the
component template appears. The component
does not then need a route. For components
designed to be displayed as a view within
our single application page, the component
needs no selector, but we do need to
configure routes. We then tie those routes
to actions. An action activates a route to
display the view. If we want to do routing
in our application, we need to configure
the route definitions, tie routes to
actions, and place the view. Let's do
checklists for each of these tasks. The
first step for doing routing in an
application is to configure the routes.
Begin by defining the base element in the
index.html file. Add RouterModule to an
Angular module's imports array, then at
each route to the array passed to the
RouterModule's forRoot method, and
remember that order matters. The router
will pick the first route that matches.
Each route definition requires a path,
which defines the URL path segment for the
route. Be sure the path has no leading
slash. Use an empty path for a default
route and two asterisks for a wildcard
route, which is matched if no prior path
matches. Most route definitions also
include a component. The component is a
reference to the component itself. It is
not a string name and is not enclosed in
quotes. Once we have the routes
configured, we need to tie those routes to
actions. First, we identify which actions
to tie to which routes. Then we add the
RouterLink directive as an attribute to
any clickable element in a component's
template. We can use them in menu options,
toolbars, buttons, links, images, and so
on. Be sure to enclose the RouterLink in
square brackets. Bind the router linked to
a link parameters array. The first element
of the link parameters array is the
route's path. All other elements in the
array are values for the route parameters.
Use the RouterOutlet to identify where to
display the routed component's view. This
is most often specified in the host
component template. When a route is
activated, the route component's view is
displayed at the location of the router
outlet. This module was all about
navigation and routing. We began with a
look at how routing works. We then walked
through how to configure routes, tie
routes to actions, and define where the
routed component's view should appear. Our
App Component had embedded our Product
List Component as a nested component. In
this module we were finally able to remove
that nesting. We set up routing so we can
now navigate to our Welcome and Product
List Components. We've covered the basics
of routing in this module, but there is so
much more. In the next module we'll look
at some additional routing techniques and
add navigation to the product detail component.