Whether you are new to Angular or
migrating from AngularJS, you want to come
up to speed quickly with Angular's
components, templates, and services.
Welcome to Angular: Getting Started, from
Pluralsight. My name is Deborah Kurata,
and this course provides the basics you
need to get started building an Angular
application. As we journey through this
course, we'll discover Angular's many
features and uncover the answers to key
questions. For example, what is a
component? Where do we put the HTML for
our user interface? When should we use
data binding? Why do we need a service?
And how? How do we build an Angular
application? The who, of course, is you.
This course guides you down the right
path, making your own journey with Angular
more pleasant and productive. As we start
this journey, let's get the lay of the
land and take a high‑level look at
Angular. Simply stated, Angular is a
JavaScript framework for building
client‑side applications using HTML, CSS,
and TypeScript, which is a typed superset
of JavaScript. Why Angular and not some
other JavaScript framework? And there are
lots of JavaScript frameworks out there.
Angular makes our HTML more expressive. It
powers up our HTML with features such as
if conditions, for loops, and local
variables. Angular has powerful data
binding. We can easily display fields from
our data model, track changes, and process
updates from the user. Angular promotes
modularity by design. Our applications
become a set of building blocks, making it
easier to create and reuse content. And
Angular has built‑in support for
communication with a back‑end service.
This makes it easy for our web
applications to integrate with a back‑end
service to get and post data or execute
server‑side business logic. No wonder
Angular is so very popular with millions
of web developers. With so many developers
already using AngularJS, why did we need a
new Angular? Angular is built for speed.
It has faster initial loads, faster change
detection, and improved rendering times.
Angular is modern. It takes advantage of
features provided in the latest JavaScript
standards and beyond, such as classes,
modules, and decorators, yet it supports
both greenfield and legacy browsers.
Angular has a simplified API. It has fewer
built‑in directives to learn, simpler
bindings, and a lower overall concept
count. And Angular enhances our
productivity to improve our day‑to‑day
workflow. You'll see these productivity
improvements as we go through this course,
and we'll discern a consistency of
patterns for building the blocks that form
an Angular application. In this first
module, we lay out the anatomy of an
Angular application. We consider several
suggestions for getting the most from this
course. We explore the sample application
that we'll build throughout this course,
and we'll look at the topics we'll cover
in the remainder of this course. Now let's
check out the anatomy of an Angular application.