In Angular, an application is comprised of
a set of components and services that
provide functionality across those
components. So what is an Angular
component? Each component is comprised of
a template, which is the HTML for the user
interface fragment defining a view for the
application. Add to that a class for the
code associated with the view. The class
contains the properties or data elements
available for use in the view and methods,
which perform actions for the view, such
as responding to a button click. A
component also has metadata, which
provides additional information about the
component to Angular. It is this metadata
that identifies the class as an Angular
component. So a component is a view
defined with a template. It's associated
code defined with a class and additional
information defined with metadata. We'll
look at this in more detail in the
upcoming modules. As we build these
components, how do we pull them together
into an application? We define Angular
modules. Angular modules help us organize
our application into cohesive blocks of
functionality. Every Angular application
has at least one Angular module called the
applications root Angular module. An
application can have any number of
additional Angular modules, including
feature modules that consolidate the
components for a specific application
feature. We'll see much more about Angular
modules along our journey. For now, let's
look at some tips for getting the most from this course.