First are the prerequisites. This is a
beginner‑level course, but this course
assumes you have some basic knowledge of
JavaScript for code, HTML for building the
user interface, and Cascading Style
Sheets, or CSS, for styling. You don't
have to have much experience, but a
working knowledge of each will help you
get the most from this course. Though not
required, it is helpful if you have had
some exposure to object‑oriented
programming concepts, maybe through coding
with C++, C#, Java, or PHP. But if you
don't have any exposure to OOP, that's
okay. You do not need any prior knowledge
of Angular or TypeScript. We'll cover what
you need in this course. Another way to
get the most from this course is to join
the discussion. Thoughts, comments, or
questions as you watch this course? Feel
free to use the Discussion tab. You can
find the link to the discussion on the
Pluralsight page for this course. Or
follow me on Twitter. It would be great to
hear about your experiences with Angular.
There is also a blog post specifically for
this course at the URL shown here. This
post lists common issues along with their
solutions. If you are having problems with
the code for the course, check here first.
There may already be a solution posted.
Keep this URL handy as you work through
the course. When building web
applications, regardless of the
technologies we use, there are often lots
of steps and places where things can go
wrong. That's where a good checklist can
come in. I'll present checklists at the
end of each module, and we'll use them as
a brief review of what was covered in that
module. Feel free to jump ahead to the
checklist if you have any problems when
coding along with the demos in the module.
And consider referencing these checklists
as you start building your own Angular
applications. Coding along on this journey
is another great way to get the most from
this course. Though not required, it is
often helpful to try out the presented
code as you navigate through the course.
To get you started, I've set up a public
GitHub repository specifically for this
course. It is called
Angular‑GettingStarted, and you can find
it at this URL. The starter files for the
sample application are here. You can use
these files as a starting point if you
want to code along with the demos. If
you'd prefer to follow along with the
completed code, you can find that here. If
you're new to GitHub, simply click this
button to download all of this code as a
ZIP file. So what is this sample application? Let's take a look.