To demonstrate the basic features of
Angular, we'll build a sample application
step by step as we journey through this
course. Let's see the finished sample
application in action. Welcome to Acme
Product Management. As its name implies,
this application manages our current list
of products. Here at the top is our menu
for access to the key features of the
application. In a full‑featured
application, there would, of course, be
more options here, but we want to limit
this sample application to the features we
can build within this course. Clicking on
the Product List option displays the
Product List page. We see the page title
and a table containing the list of
products. If the user clicks the Show
Image button, the product images appear,
and the button changes to Hide Image.
Click the button again to hide the images
and compress the display. Notice the nice
formatting of our price. And instead of a
number for the rating, we display the
rating in stars. Here at the top is an
input box where the user can enter a
filter string. When the input box contains
a value, a Filtered by message appears,
and the product list is filtered to only
those with a product name that contained
the entered string. Click on a product
name to navigate to the product details.
On the Product Detail page, we see the
page title with the name of the product
and all of the product details, including
a product description, the nicely
formatted price, and the star rating.
Click the Back button to navigate back to
the Product List page. So not a huge app,
but big enough to demonstrate the basics
of Angular. As with any Angular
application, this application is comprised
of a set of components, including a nested
component for the rating stars. It has a
service to get the data, and it
incorporates routing to navigate between
the pages. Now that we've seen the sample
application, how do we build it? As stated
earlier, an Angular application is
comprised of a set of components and
services that provide data and logic
across those components. With that in
mind, let's break the sample application
into components and services. For the
Welcome page, we'll build a welcome
component. For the Product. List page,
we'll build a product list component.
Recall that we had a nice visual display
of stars for our ratings. We want to reuse
that feature, so we'll build a separate
nestable star component. Clicking on a
product in the Product List page displayed
the product detail. We'll build a
component for that as well and reuse the
star component. Then we need a app
component that ties our application pieces
together. And our application gets data,
so we'll want a product data service.
Lastly, we need an index.html file. This
is the file that is downloaded by the
browser when a user accesses our
application. We'll build the basics of
each of these pieces and learn how to
organize the components into Angular
modules as we journey through this course.
Now let's finish up this introductory
module with a look at the outline for the remainder of this course.