We start with first things first. We'll
discuss the tools we'll use, then walk
through how to set up and run an Angular
application. Next, we'll dive into
components. We'll build the app component
using a simple template and minimal
component code and metadata. We'll see how
to build the user interface for our
application using templates,
interpolation, and directives. We'll power
up that user interface with data binding
and nicely format our data with pipes.
Next, we'll tackle some additional
component techniques. We'll define
interfaces, encapsulate styles, and
leverage lifecycle hooks to build better
components. We'll see how to build a
component designed to be nested within
other components and how to communicate
between the nested component and its
container. We often have logic or data
that is needed across components. We'll
learn how to build services specifically
for this purpose and use dependency
injection to inject those services into
the components that need them. Most web
applications need to communicate with a
back‑end server to get or post data and to
execute back‑end business logic. In this
module, we'll leverage HTTP to retrieve
the data for our application. Our sample
application displays multiple views. We'll
see how to set up routing to navigate
between those views. Next is Angular
modules. We learn about and use the root
Angular module throughout this course. But
as the application grows, we want to
separate its concerns. This course module
reviews the basics of Angular modules and
refactors our application into logical
blocks using multiple Angular modules.
Through the majority of this course, we
create our components and other code
manually, but, spoiler alert, there is an
easier way. We'll learn how to use the
Angular CLI to build, test, and deploy our
application. We're covering a lot of
territory, and by the end of our journey,
we'll have a simple, but fully operational
Angular application. You can use that
application as a reference for your own
development. Let's start our journey through Angular.