The data for our application is on a
server somewhere in the cloud, at the
office, under our desk. How do we get that
data into our view? Welcome back to
Angular: Getting Started, from
Pluralsight. My name is Deborah Kurata,
and in this module we'll learn how to use
HTTP with observables to retrieve data.
Most Angular applications obtain data
using HTTP. The application issues an HTTP
GET request to a web service. That web
service retrieves the data, often using a
database, and returns it to the
application in an HTTP response. The
application then processes that data. In
this module, we begin with an introduction
to Observables and the Reactive
Extensions. We then examine how to send an
HTTP request and map the result to an
array. We add some exception handling and
we look at how to subscribe to observables
to get the data for our view. We finished
the first cut of a product data service in
the last module, but it still has hard
coded data. Now, we'll replace that hard
coded data with HTTP calls. Let's get started.