Data sequences can take many forms, such
as a response from a back end web service,
a set of system notifications, or a stream
of events such as user input. In this
diagram, our stream contains three
elements. The first marble comes in, then
the second, and sometime later the third.
Reactive extensions represent a data
sequence as an observable sequence,
commonly just called an observable.
Observables help us manage asynchronous
data, such as data coming from a back end
service. Observables treat events as a
collection. We can think of an observable
as an array whose items arrive
asynchronously over time. A method in our
code can subscribe to an observable to
receive asynchronous notifications as new
data arrives. The method can then react as
data is pushed to it. The method is
notified when there is no more data or
when an error occurs. Observables are used
within Angular itself, including Angular's
event system and it's HTTP client service,
which is why we are covering them here.
Observables allow us to manipulate sets of
events with operators. Operators are
methods on observables that compose new
observables. Each operator transforms the
source observable in some way. Operators
do not wait for all of the values and
process them at once. Rather, operators on
observables process each value as it is
emitted. Some examples of operators
include map, filter, take, and merge. The
map operator allows us to transform the
incoming data. The argument to the map
operator is an arrow function that says to
take each data item and transform it to 10
times its value. So when we receive 1, it
is mapped to 10. When we received 2, it is
mapped to 20, and so on. This depiction is
called a marble diagram, and it's helpful
for visualizing observable sequences. This
is a screenshot from rxmarbles at this
URL. We compose observable operators with
the observable pipe method, hence the
reason that observable operators are
sometimes referred to as pipeable
operators. Let's look at an example. Here
we see how to use the pipe method to
compose multiple observable operators.
Rxjs has two primary packages we use to
import functionality. Observable and the
observable creation methods, such as
range, can be found in the rxjs package.
We import the operators from
rxjs/operators. We use the range creation
method to create an observable stream of
numbers from 0 to 9. Not a common
scenario, I know, but our goal here is to
show how to compose operators with the
pipe. By convention, we add a dollar
suffix to the variables that hold an
observable. This makes it easier to
quickly distinguish the observables in our
code, and we declare its type as an
observable stream of numbers, using the
generic argument. We use the pipe method
to pipe this observable stream through
several operators, map and filter. We only
include two operators here, but we can
define any number of operators separated
by commas. This map operator takes each
number emitted into the observable stream,
0 through 9, and multiplies it by 3, which
results in an observable with 0, 3, 6, 9
and so on. As each number is emitted by
the map operator, this filter operator
filters the result to only the even
numbers in the sequence. That is those
that when divided by 2 have a remainder of
0. Here we subscribe to the resulting
observable to start receiving emitted
values. The observable source does not
emit any values until it has a subscriber.
So subscribing is key. What do you think
will be logged to the console? Let's see
how we got that result. The source emits
0, the 0 is multiplied by 3, resulting in
0. The 0 is divided by 2 with a remainder
of 0, so it is included in the final
result. The source then emits 1. The 1 is
multiplied by 3, resulting in 3. The 3 is
divided by 2 with a remainder of 1, so it
is not included in the final result, and
so on. Notice that each item in the
sequence is processed through the pipeable
operators as it is emitted. You may have
worked with asynchronous data in
JavaScript previously, using promises.
Observables are different from promises in
several ways. A promise returns a single
future value. An observable emits multiple
asynchronous values over time. A promise
is not lazy. By the time you have a
promise, it's on its way to being
resolved. An observable is lazy by
default. Observables will not emit values
until they are subscribed to. A promise is
not cancellable, it is resolved or
rejected, and only once. An observable can
be cancelled by unsubscribing, plus an
observable supports map, filter, reduce,
and similar operators. In this module, we'll do HTTP using observables.