We often encapsulate the data access for
our application into a data service that
can be used by any component or other
service that needs it. In the last module,
we did just that, but our product data
service still contains a hardcoded list of
products. We, instead, want to send an
HTTP request to get the products from a
backend web server. Angular provides an
HTTP service that allows us to communicate
with a backend web server using the
familiar HTTP request and response
protocol. For example, we call a get
method of the HTTP service, which in turn
sends a Get request to the web server. The
web server response is returned from the
HTTP service to our product data service
as an observable. What does this look like
in code? This is the ProductService we
built in the last module modified to
retrieve the products using Angular's HTTP
service. Let's walk through this code.
First, we specify a URL to the products on
the web server. This defines where we send
our HTTP requests. Note that this URL is
shown for illustration purposes only and
is not a real URL. Next, we add a
constructor. Recall from the last course
module that we use a constructor to inject
dependencies. In this case, we need
Angular's HTTP service so we inject it
here. Recognize the syntax? It creates a
private HTTP variable and assigns the
injected service instance to that
variable. And since we are strongly typing
this variable to HttpClient, we import
HttpClient from the angular/common/http
package here. Recall also from the last
course module that before we can inject a
service in as a dependency, we need to
register that services provider with
Angular's injector. The Http Service
Provider Registration is done for us in
the HttpClientModule included in the
angular/common/http package. To include
the features of this external package in
our application, we add it to the imports
array of our application's Angular module,
app.module. Recall that the declarations
array is for declaring components,
directives, and pipes that belong to this
module. The imports array is for pulling
in external modules. Now our Angular
module illustration looks like this. We
declare our components, we declare the
directives and pipes that those components
require, and we import the external
modules that we need. Going back to the
ProductService and getProducts, we use the
injected HTTP service instance and call
the get method passing in the desired URL.
The HTTP service then sends a Get request
using the specified URL. Often, the data
returned from the backend server is in
Json format. Lucky for us, the HttpClient
get method makes it easy to receive that
Json data. We specify the expected type of
response by setting the get method's
generic parameter. Since we are expecting
an array of product objects, we set the
generic parameter to IProduct array. The
get method then automatically maps the
response object returned from the backend
server to that defined type so we don't
have to. Does this generic syntax look
familiar? We used it earlier in this
course to define the event payload when
passing event information from a nested
component to its container, we aren't
quite finished. What does our method now
return? Since we are using strong typing,
we should have a function return value
here. We define the get method generic
parameter as IProduct array, so will that
be what we get back? Not quite. The
getProducts method returns an Observable
of IProduct array. That's because the HTTP
calls are asynchronous operations, and
it's important to note that HTTP calls are
single asynchronous operations, meaning
that the observable sequence returned from
the get method contains only one element.
This element is the HTTP response object
mapped to the type specified in the
generic parameter. Notice that the
observable also takes advantage of
generics to define the type of data it is
observing in the observable sequence. In
our case, it's the array of products. Now, let's add HTTP to our ProductService.