In this demo, we'll send an HTTP request
to get the products for our Product List
page. We are looking at our application's
Angular module we called app.module.
Recall from the slides that Angular
registers its HTTP service provider in an
Angular module called HttpClientModule. In
our application's Angular module, we
import that HttpClientModule. We then pull
that module into our application by adding
HttpClientModule to the imports array
here. Now we can inject the Angular HTTP
service into any class that needs it. Here
is the product data service we created in
the last module with all of the hard coded
data. We want to modify our product
service to get the product data using
HTTP. Let's start at the top with the
import statements. We want Angular to
provide us an instance of the HttpClient
service, so we identify it as a dependency
in the constructor. We don't have a
constructor yet, so let's add that first.
Then we specify the parameter. Angular
will then inject the HttpClient service
instance into this variable. Now we need
to identify the location of our web
server. Hmm, this doesn't look like a
valid URL to a web server. To keep things
simple, the demonstration reads the data
from a local JSON file that was provided
with the starter files. That way we don't
need to set up an actual web server.
However, we do need to define the location
of this JSON file so that the Angular CLI
can find it when it serves up the
application. I've already done this in the
provided starter files. Here in the
angular.json file, we can see the path
here in the assets array. To change this
code to work against a web server, simply
change this URL to point to an appropriate
web server. And, of course, you need to
write the server‑side code to return the
list of products. Ah, it's finally time to
delete our hard coded data, so let's
delete the hard coded products from the
getProducts method. Gone. We'll call the
HTTP GET method here instead, passing in
the defined URL. Since we expect the
response to be a JSON structure containing
an array of products, we set the GET
method generic parameter to IProduct
array. When we get a response back, this
method will then automatically map the
returned response to an array of products.
We'll need to change the return type as
well. Now this method returns an
observable of IProduct array. We can't try
this out at this point because we are not
yet subscribing to the observable returned
from the service. Plus, looking at the
console, we have a syntax error where we
are calling this method since we changed
the return type. Let's add some exception
handling first, then modify the
ProductListComponent to subscribe to the observable list of products.