As you can imagine, there are many things
that can go wrong when communicating with
a back‑end service. Everything from an
invalid request to a lost connection. So
let's add some exception handling. There
are two key observable operators that
we'll need. Tap taps into the observable
stream and allows us to look at the
emitted values in the stream without
transforming the stream. So tap is great
to use for debugging or logging.
CatchError catches any error. We import
them both from rxjs/operators. As we
discussed earlier in this course, to use
these operators, we access the pipe method
of the observable. We then pass in the
operators, separated by commas. Here, the
tap operator logs the retrieved data to
the console. That way we can verify it's
been retrieved correctly. And the
catchError operator takes in a error
handling method. The error handling method
gets one parameter, the ErrorResponse
object. In the error handling method, we
can handle the error as appropriate. We
can send the error information to a remote
logging infrastructure or throw an error
to the calling code. Now let's add
exception handling to our product.service.
We are back in the editor with the
product.service just as we left it. This
code is not really complete without the
exception handling, so we'll add the
appropriate imports for both the
catchError and tap operators. We then call
the pipe method and pass in both of the
operators, just like we saw on the slide.
I'll paste in the handleError method, and
we need the import for HttpErrorResponse
and throwError. In this method, we handle
logging our errors anyway we want. For our
sample application, we'll just log to the
console and throw an error to the calling
code. So our getProducts method is
complete. We can add other methods here to
POST or PUT data as well, but we still
have that syntax error here, and we can't
see the result of our hard work because we
are not yet subscribing to the observable. Let's do that next.