Observables are lazy. Just like a
newspaper or a newsletter, an observable
doesn't emit values until we subscribe. So
when we are ready to start receiving
values in our component, we call
subscribe. The subscribe method takes an
optional argument, which is an Observer
object. As its name suggests, the Observer
object observes the stream and responds to
three types of notifications, next, error,
and complete. We use the Observer object
to define handler functions that execute
on these notifications. The first handler
function is often called a next function
because it processes the next emitted
value. Since observables can handle
multiple values over time, the next
function is called for each value the
observable emits. The second is an error
handler function. And yep, you guessed it,
it executes if there is an error. In some
cases, we want to know when the observable
completes, so observables provide a third
handler that is executed on completion.
The subscribe function returns a
subscription. We use that subscription to
call unsubscribe and cancel the
subscription, if needed. Now that our
product data service is returning an
observable, any class that needs product
data, such as our product‑list.component,
can call our service and subscribe to the
returned observable. This line of code
calls the product data service getProducts
method, and because we subscribed, it
kicks off the HTTP GET request. It then
asynchronously receives data and
notifications from the observable. We pass
an observer object to the subscribe. This
syntax defines a key and value pair where
the key is the function name and the value
is the function, specified here using
arrow function syntax. The first observer
function specifies the action to take
whenever the observable emits an item. The
method parameter is that emitted item.
Since HTTP calls are single async
operations, only one item is emitted,
which is the HTTP response object that was
mapped to our product array in the
service. So the parameter is our array of
products. This code then sets the local
products property to the returned array of
products. The second function is executed
if the observable fails. In this example,
it sets a local errorMessage variable to
the returned error. A third function, not
used here, specifies the action to take
when the observable ends with a completed
notification. The third function is rarely
used when working with HTTP requests since
they automatically complete after emitting
the single response. Alternatively, we can
define the observer methods like this,
taking advantage of a shortcut that was
introduced in ES2015 for defining methods
on object literals. Instead of defining a
separate key and value function, the
shorthand syntax only requires the
function and uses that function's name as
the key. Note that you cannot use an arrow
function when using this syntax because it
needs the function name for the key. But
because we can't use an arrow function
here, we can't use this alternate syntax
if we need to reference class‑level
properties. When using an arrow function,
the this keyword is scoped to the class,
so the code here is referencing our
class‑level products property, which is
what we want. When using a normal
function, the this keyword is scoped to
that function, so the code here defines a
second products variable that is local to
the next function and does not modify our
class‑level products property. That means
the code here won't execute as expected.
Only use this alternate syntax if you
don't need to reference class‑level
properties. Now let's subscribe to our observable.