In this demo, we modify our component to
subscribe to the observable provided by
the product service. Here in the
ProductListComponent, we see a syntax
error. Now that we've changed the product
service to return an observable, we cannot
assign the result to our product property
directly. Rather, we subscribe to the
returned observable. When the observable
emits the data, we set our product
property to the returned array of
products. But things don't always go as
expected. To handle any errors, let's add
an errorMessage property. If our request
for products fails, our errorMessage
property is set to the error. Are we ready
to try it out? Oh, we have no data. Why is
that? Let's look again at our code. Recall
that we said that HTTP is an asynchronous
operation. What does that mean exactly for
this code? Let's take it by the numbers.
Angular first initializes the component
and executes the ngOnInit method. We call
the getProducts method of the
productService. The productService returns
an observable of IProduct array. We
subscribe to that observable and the HTTP
GET request is submitted. This is the
asynchronous operation. This code is then
complete, and we execute the next line,
which is setting our filteredProducts. But
at this point, our products property is
not yet set, so the filteredProducts is
empty and we see no data. At some future
point in time, the service receives the
HTTP response from our request. The
response data is mapped to an array of
products. The response is piped through
any operators, and the observable emits
that mapped data to any subscribers. Our
subscriber receives the emitted data and
assigns our product property to the
emitted array of products. But since we
are binding to the filteredProducts
property, we are not notified that we now
have the retrieved list of products. There
are several ways we can handle this. One
option is that we can move this line into
the subscribe function. That way we won't
assign the filtered products until the
retrieved set of products are emitted from
the service. Right now it is a single line
function. To pass in a multiple line
function, we need to add curly braces,
like this. And let's not forget the
semicolon. Now that it's a multi‑line
function, we need to end each statement
with a semicolon. Then we can move this
line into the function. Now this line is
executed after the products property is
set to our list of products. Let's check
it out. There are all of our products.
Success! We have more here now because
we're retrieving the products from the
provided product.json file. If we open the
F12 Developer Tools, we see that data in
the console, here. The recommended way to
use HTTP is to encapsulate it in a
service, like our product service, then
expose an observable for use by any
component that needs product data. The
component simply subscribes to the
observable, and at some later point in
time gets the data or a notification.
Let's finish up this module with some
checklists we can use as we work with HTTP.