Before we can use Angular's HttpClient
service, some setup is required. We need
to ensure that the service provider is
registered with the Angular injector. This
registration is done for us in the
HttpClientModule, so all we need to do is
pull the HttpClientModule into our
application. We do this by adding
HttpClientModule to the imports array of
one of our application's Angular modules.
Build a data access service to wrap HTTP
requests. In that data service, specify
the needed imports to find a dependency
for the Angular HttpClient service using a
constructor parameter. Create a method for
each HTTP request. In the method, call the
desired HTTP method such as GET and pass
in the URL to the desired server. Use
generics to specify the response return
type. This will transform the raw HTTP
response to the specified type, and do
error handling as desired. In any class
that needs data from a data service, call
the subscribe method to subscribe to the
observable. Provide a function to execute
when the observable emits an item. This
often assigns a property to the returned
JSON object. And if that property is bound
to a template, the retrieved data appears
in the view, and add an error function to
handle any returned errors. Here are some
related courses in the Pluralsight
library. To perform, create, read, update,
and delete, or CRUD operations, using
HTTP, see the Angular Reactive Forms
course. It demonstrates how to display,
edit, and save data in Angular. For more
information on RxJS and observables, see
the RxJS and Angular Reactive Development
course. It provides a detailed look at
observables, including how to combine data
from multiple sources, build action
streams to react to user actions, and work
with streams without subscribing. See the
Angular HTTP Communication course for
intermediate HTTP techniques such as error
handling, building interceptors, and
testing HTTP requests. This module was all
about HTTP and observables. We began with
an overview of observables and reactive
extensions. We examined how to build a
data access service that sends requests
for data over HTTP. We walked through how
to set up some basic exception handling
and we saw how to subscribe to the
returned observable and ultimately display
the resulting data in the view. We've now
removed the hard‑coded data from the
product data service, yeah, and instead
retrieve the data using HTTP. In our
sample application, we are using HTTP to
retrieve the data from a local JSON file,
but the techniques are the same for
retrieving data from a back‑end service.
Next up, we'll see how to display multiple pages with navigation and routing.