Hello, my name is Deborah Kurata, and I'd
like to welcome you to my course, Angular:
Getting Started, from Pluralsight. This
beginner‑level course takes you on a
journey through the basic features of
Angular. It guides you down the right
path, making your own journey with Angular
more pleasant and productive. Along the
way, we build a sample application so you
can code along or use it as a reference
for your own development. You'll see how
Angular provides a consistent set of
patterns for building components,
templates, modules, and services, helping
you come up to speed quickly. This course
covers how to build components, how to
create the user interface for your
application in a template, and power it up
with data binding and directives. You'll
discover how to build services for logic
needed across components and inject those
services where they are needed. You'll
learn how to send requests to a web server
using HTTP and observables. And you'll see
how to set up routing to navigate between
the views of your application. In
addition, you'll see how to use the
Angular command‑line interface, or CLI, to
generate, execute, test, and deploy your
Angular application. By the end of this
course, you will know the basics you need
to get started building your own Angular
applications. I hope you'll join me on
this journey through Angular: Getting Started, from Pluralsight.