To build the user interface for our
application in Angular, we create a
template with HTML. To really power up
that user interface, we need Angular's
data binding and directives. Welcome back
to Angular: Getting Started, from
Pluralsight. My name is Deborah Kurata,
and in these next two modules, we create
the user interface using templates,
directives, and data binding. Web
applications are all about the user
interface, and Angular makes it easier to
build rich and powerful user interfaces.
Angular gives us data binding so we can
easily display information and respond to
user actions. With Angular directives, we
add logic to our HTML such as if
statements and for loops. And with Angular
components, we build nested user interface
fragments such as an image rotator or
rating stars. We've seen that an Angular
component is a view defined with a
template, its associated code defined with
a class, and additional information
defined with metadata and set using a
component decorator. In these next two
modules, we'll focus on techniques for
building the template. In this module, we
evaluate the different ways we can build a
template for our component and demonstrate
how to create a linked template for our
view. Then we'll build a component
associated with that template and use it
as a directive. We'll detail how to set up
data binding using interpolation and
display the value of our component class
properties in the view. We need some basic
logic in the template, so we'll leverage
Angular's built‑ in directives. In the
next module, we'll look at additional data
binding techniques. Looking at our
application architecture, we currently
have the index.html file and our root
AppComponent in place. So we have a
working sample application, but it doesn't
look like much. What we really want is a
list of products. In this module, we'll
begin work on the product list component
to display that list of products. Let's get started.