In the prior module, we built an inline
template for our app component. We used
the template property to define the
template directly in the component's
metadata. But this is not the only way we
can build a template for our components.
We can use the template property and
define an inline template using a simple
quoted string with single or double
quotes. Or we can define an inline
template with a multi‑line string by
enclosing the HTML in ES 2015 back ticks.
The back ticks allow composing a string
over several lines, making the HTML more
readable. We used this technique to build
our template in the last module. There are
some advantages to defining an inline
template using one of these two
techniques. The template is directly
defined within the component, keeping the
view and the code for that view in one
file. It is then easy to match up our data
bindings with the class properties, such
as the page title, in this example.
However, there are disadvantages as well.
When defining the HTML in a string, most
development tools don't provide
IntelliSense, automatic formatting, and
syntax checking. Especially as we define
more HTML in the template, these issues
become challenges. In many cases, the
better option is to define a linked
template with the HTML in its own file. We
can then use the templateUrl property in
the component metadata to define the URL
of our HTML file. Let's use this technique
and build a linked template for our
product list view. Here is our ultimate
goal for the product list view. The view
has a nice heading, a filter by box at the
top allows the user to enter a string. The
user entered string is displayed here, and
the list of products is filtered to only
those with a product name containing that
string. The products are listed in a neat
table with a nicely formatted header. The
Show Image button shows an image for each
product. The product name is a link that
displays the product detail view, which
we'll build later in this course. To make
this page look nice with very little
effort, we use the Twitter bootstrap
styling framework. If you want to find out
more about bootstrap, check out this link.
And for the stars, we use the font awesome
icon set and toolkit. To find out more
about font awesome, check out this link.
We'll install both of these in the
upcoming demo. Now let's jump into a demo
and start building the template for our
product list view. First, let's install
bootstrap and font awesome so we can use
them in our templates. Open the Integrated
Terminal or command window. I still have
the application running in this window, so
I'll click plus to open another command
window, then type npm install bootstrap
font‑awesome. This installs both packages.
You may see some warnings here. These
warnings tell us that bootstrap requires
jQuery and Popper, but we only plan to use
the styling parts of bootstrap, not the
interactive features, so we don't need
these dependencies. Installing the
packages does not provide access to their
style sheets. For that, we import the
styles for these packages into our global
application style sheet, which is the
style.css file here. We'll import the
minimized version of the styles from the
bootstrap/dist/css folder, and the
font‑awesome/css folder. The style sheets
are then available to any template in our
application. Now we are ready to add an
external template file for the product
list component. By convention, each
feature of the application has its own
folder under the app folder. So let's add
a new folder here and name it products. In
that folder, we'll create the template for
our product list component. By convention,
the name of the template is the same name
as the component with an HTML extension.
We'll call our product list component
product‑list.component.html. Let's widen
that up a little bit. Now we are ready to
create the HTML for our template. Let's
start with the heading. We're using
Twitter bootstrap style classes here. In
the heading we display Product List. If
you don't want to type in all of this
code, you can copy it from the APM final
folder, provided in my GitHub repository,
as detailed in the First Things First
module, earlier in this course. Next is
the filter by. We define an input box for
entry of the filter string, and we add
text that displays the user entered
filter. We again used Twitter bootstrap
style classes to lay out the input box and
text into rows. Now let's build the table.
We use Twitter bootstrap's table style
classes. We have a table header. The first
column header is a button to show the
product image, and here is the table body.
Hmm, we definitely don't want to hard code
in the products here. So let's leave the
table body empty for now. So we have the
start of a template defined for our
component. Now what? If you said we need
to build a component, you are exactly right.