Remember the steps for building a
component that we covered in the last
module? We define a class, we add a
component decorator to define the metadata
and specify the template, and we import
what we need. The only thing that's really
different from the component we created in
the last module is the template property.
Here we are using templateUrl to define
the location of our linked template
instead of defining an HTML string. Notice
the syntax of the path here. If we follow
the convention of defining the template
HTML file in the same folder as the
associated component, we can use a
relative path by specifying dot slash.
Let's jump right back to the demo and give
this a try. We are back with the sample
application exactly where we left it, and
we are ready to build a new component. We
start by creating a new file in the
products folder. We'll name it using the
component naming convention, dot
component, because it is an Angular
component, and dot ts for the extension.
Then we create the class, export class
ProductListComponent. We're exporting this
class so it is available to other parts of
the application. Next we decorate the
class with a component decorator. It is
the component decorator that makes this
class a component, and we know what that
underlying means, we need the import
statement. Let's pass an object into the
component decorator with the appropriate
properties. For the selector, we'll set pm
products. We'll use the same prefix is in
the app component to distinguish the
selector as part of the product management
application. Then we define the
templateUrl. Here we provide the path to
our HTML file. Since we define the HTML
file in the same folder as the component,
we can use the dot slash relative past
syntax here. So now we have our template
defining our view, our class, which
defines our associated code, and the
component decorator that defines the
metadata. Our component is complete and we're ready to use it. But how?