Here is our newly created
product‑list.component. And here is the
app.component we created earlier. Note
that I've excluded some of the code here
on this slide, such as the import
statements and class details for a better
fit. We'll see the complete code when we
get back to the demo. When a component has
a selector defined, as we have here, we
can use the component as a directive. This
means that we can insert this component's
template into any other component's
template by using the selector as an HTML
tag like this. The
product‑list.component's template is then
inserted into this location in the
app.component's template. So this is the
first step when using a component as a
directive. Use the name defined in this
selector as an HTML tag in another
component's template. When this template
is displayed, Angular looks for a
component that has a selector with this
name. We could have hundreds of components
in our application. How does our
application know where to look for this
selector? The application looks to the
Angular module that owns this component to
find all of the directives that are
visible to this component. Every Angular
application must have at least one Angular
module, the root application module,
commonly called AppModule. Currently our
AppModule declares our root application
component, AppComponent. A component must
belong to one and only one Angular module.
Because the AppModule declares the
AppComponent, the AppComponent belongs to
the AppModule. The AppModule bootstraps
the application with this component, so it
is the first component that is loaded for
our application. Our AppModule also
imports the system browser module to pull
in the features it needs to run this
application in a browser. So this is what
our AppModule currently looks like. An
Angular module defines the boundary or
context within which the component
resolves its directives and dependencies.
So when a component contains a directive,
Angular looks to the component's module to
determine which directives are visible to
that component. What does that mean for
us? Well, for Angular to find the
pm‑products directive used in the
app.component, the product‑list.component
must also be declared in this Angular
module. This is the second step when using
a component as a directive. We need to
ensure that the directive is visible to
any component that uses it. There are two
ways to expose a directive in an Angular
module. We can declare the component in
the Angular module as we show here, or if
the component is already declared in
another Angular module, we can import that
module similar to how we import
BrowserModule here. Now let's jump back to
the demo and give this a try. We are back
in our sample app. We defined a selector
for our product‑list.component here so we
can use it as a directive in any other
component. Let's use it in the
app.component. Open the app.component
file. So instead of displaying My First
Component, we'll display our new product
list template here. Replace the div tags
with pm‑products. Are we ready to see our
result in the browser? What you'll see in
the browser depends on when you last
started the compiler with npm start. You
may see the app.component page title but
not our product‑list.component. In this
case, the browser displayed the last
successful compiled files, so you don't
see our new component. Using the F12
tools, no error is shown. Or you may see
the message, Cannot GET. Opening the
developer tools, you see the error is
Failed to load resource: the server
responded with a status of 404 (Not
Found). You may see this error whenever
the application can't compile and,
therefore, can't serve the files to the
browser. Or you may get lucky and see the
actual error, pm‑products is not a known
element. Whenever you see unexpected
results or errors in the browser, check
the VS Code terminal window for compile
issues. Here we see the error pm‑products
is not a known element. And with this
error, Angular gives us a solution. If
pm‑products is an Angular component, and
in our case it is, then verify that it is
part of this module. Ah, yes. We didn't do
step two and declare it in our
application's Angular module. Let's go
back to the code. We'll open the
app.module and add ProductListComponent to
the declarations array. Well, we're
getting a squiggly line here. That means
we have an error. Any guess as to what's
wrong? If you said we're missing the
import, you are correct. Everything we
declare must be imported. With VS Code,
this is easy. Notice the lightbulb icon on
the left. It is indicating that it has a
quick fix for this underlined issue. Click
the lightbulb and select the desired fix,
and VS Code adds the appropriate import
line for us. Cool! Now that our syntax
error is gone, let's try it again. There's
our page. It's not complete, and it's not
interactive yet, but we have the basics in
place. Note that after a compile error,
you may need to refresh the browser page
or restart the compiler in order to see
the changes in the browser. To restart,
use the VS Code terminal window and type
Ctrl+C or Cmd+C to stop the compiler and
npm start to restart the compiler. So we
successfully used our
product‑list.component as a directive. We
added the selector as the directive in the
containing component's template. We
declared the component to the
application's Angular module, and we added
the appropriate import statement. Now we
are ready to power up our user interface
with data binding and some built‑in Angular directives.