In Angular, binding coordinates
communication between the component's
class and its template and often involves
passing data. We can provide values from
the class to the template for display, and
the template raises events to pass user
actions or user‑entered values back to the
class. The binding syntax is always
defined in the template. Angular provides
several types of binding, and we'll look
at each of them. In this module we cover
interpolation. The remaining data binding
techniques are covered in the next module.
The double curly braces that signify
interpolation are readily recognizable.
The pageTitle in this example is bound to
a property in the component's class.
Interpolation is a one‑way binding from
the class property to the template, so the
value here shows up here. Interpolation
supports much more than simple properties.
We can perform operations such as
concatenation or simple calculations. We
can even call a class method, such as
getTitle shown here. We use interpolation
to insert the interpolated strings into
the text between HTML elements, as shown
here. Or we can use interpolation with
element property assignments, as in this
example. Here we assign the innerText
property of the h1 element to a bound
value. Both of these examples display the
same result. The syntax between the
interpolation curly braces is called a
template expression. Angular evaluates
that expression using the component as the
context. So Angular looks to the component
to obtain property values or to call
methods. Angular then converts the result
of the template expression to a string and
assigns that string, to an element or
directive property. So any time we want to
display read‑only data, we define a
property for that data in our class and
use interpolation to display that data in
the template. And if we need to perform
simple calculations or get a result from a
method, we can do that with interpretation
as well. Let's give this a try. Looking at
the product list template from our sample
application, we hardcoded in the page
title here. In the heading. Binding the
heading to a property in the class instead
of hardcoding it in the HTML makes it
easier to see and change when working on
the code, and we could later retrieve this
text from a file or database. Let's start
by adding a property in the class for the
page title. We'll open the component to
the right and close down the explorer.
Here in the class, we specify the property
name. We'll call it pageTitle, and because
we are using TypeScript, we define the
type for this property. Lastly, we assign
a default value, Product List. With the
pageTitle property in place, we can now
bind to the pageTitle property in the
template. We replace the hardcoded product
list here with interpolation and specify
the name of the property. Now when this
template is displayed, Angular assigns the
string value of the pageTitle property to
the innerText property of this div
element, and Product List will be
displayed. Let's see the result in the
browser. With our binding, the page title
appears as before. So we can confirm that
it works, I've rearranged the windows so
that we can see both the code and the
browser. Now let's make a change to our
pageTitle here, and we immediately see it
in the browser. So our interpolation
works. So any time we want to display the
value of a component property, we simply
use interpolation. Now we're ready to add some logic to our template