We can think of a directive as a custom
HTML element or attribute we used to power
up and extend our HTML. We can build our
own custom directives or use Angular's
built‑in directives. Previously in this
module, we've seen how to build a
component and use it as a custom
directive. We use the pm‑products
directive to display our product‑list
template. In addition to building our own
custom directives, we can use Angular's
built‑in directives. The built‑in Angular
directives we'll look at are structural
directives. A structural directive
modifies the structure or layout of a view
by adding, removing, or manipulating
elements and their children. They help us
to power up our HTML with If logic and For
loops. Notice the asterisk in front of the
directive name. That marks the directive
as a structural directive. Let's look at
ngIf first. NgIf is a structural directive
that removes or recreates a portion of the
DOM tree based on an expression. If the
expression assigned to the ngIf evaluates
to a false value, the element and its
children are removed from the DOM. If the
expression evaluates to a true value, a
copy of the element and its children are
reinserted into the DOM. For example, say
we only wanted to show the HTML table if
there are some products in a list of
products. We use ngIf on the table element
and set it to products and
products.length. If the products variable
has a value and the products list has
length, the table appears in the DOM. If
not, the table element and all of its
children are removed from the DOM. But
didn't we just say that an Angular module
defines the boundary or context within
which the component resolves its
directives and dependencies? How will our
application find this ngIf directive?
Looking back at the illustration of our
AppModule, we see that it imports
BrowserModule. Luckily for us,
BrowserModule exposes the ngIf and ngFor
directives. So any component declared by
the AppModule can use the ngIf or ngFor
directives. With that settled, let's try
out the ngIf directive. We are back in the
sample application, looking at the
ProductListComponent and its template. We
only want to display this table of
products if there are some products to
display, so the first thing we need is a
property to hold the list of products.
Where do we define that products property?
In the component's class, of course. We'll
add a products property here. Hmm. But
what is the type of this property? Well,
we want an array of product instances, but
we don't currently have anything that
defines what a product is. We'll have a
better solution in a later module, but for
now we'll just define products as an array
of any. In TypeScript, we use any as the
data type any time we don't know or don't
care what the specific data type is. We
need to populate our array, but where do
we get the data? In many cases, we would
communicate with a back‑end server to get
this data. We'll look at how to do that
later in this course. For now, we'll just
hard code in a set of products. If you are
coding along, consider copying a few of
the products from the products.json file
provided with the starter files under the
api products folder. With the products
property in place, we're ready to use it
in the HTML. We want to put it on the
table element because that is the element
we want to add or remove from the DOM.
Type *ngIf= and then our expression
enclosed in quotes. We only want to show
the table if there is a list of products,
and that list of products contain some
elements. Let's see what this looks like
in the browser. We see the table header,
so we know our table is displayed. Let's
try this: Let's comment out the product
data, bring up the browser again, and we
see that the table disappeared. Now, if we
uncomment out the product data and look
again at the browser, our table reappears.
With ngIf, the associated element and its
children are literally added or removed
from the DOM. But notice that we still
aren't populating the table with our products. Let's do that next.