Another structural directive is ngFor.
NgFor repeats a portion of the DOM tree
once for each item in an iterable list. So
we define a block of HTML that defines how
we want to display a single item and tell
Angular to use that block for displaying
each item in the list. For example, say we
want to display each product in a row of a
table. We define one table row and its
child table data elements. That table row
element and its children are then repeated
for each product in the list of products.
The let keyword here creates a template
input variable called product. We can
reference this variable anywhere on this
element, on any sibling element, or on any
child element. And notice the of instead
of in here. We'll talk more about that in
a moment. For now, let's jump back to our
demo. We are once again looking at the
ProductListComponent and its template.
Here in the table body, we want to repeat
a table row for each product in the list
of products. In the table body, we'll add
a tr element for the table row. And in the
tr element, we'll specify the ngFor,
*ngFor='let product of products'. Next,
we'll add the child elements. We'll insert
a td or a table data element for each
property of the product that we want to
display in the table. We'll need to match
them up with the table header elements.
The first column displays the product
image. Let's skip the image for now. We'll
add that in the next module, but we'll
still add the td element as a placeholder.
The next table header says Product. So in
this column, we want the product name.
We'll use interpolation to bind to the
product's name by using the local variable
product and a dot to drill down to the
product properties. We want productName
here. How did we know that property name?
Looking here at the ProductListComponent,
we see the product property names here. So
these are the names we use in the
interpolation template expressions. Next,
I'll add td elements for some of the other
product properties. So for each product in
our list of products, we will get a tr
element for a table row and td elements
for table data. Want to see how this looks
in the browser? Wow, we have our products.
Doesn't that look nice? Well, our price is
not very well‑formatted, and it doesn't
have a currency symbol. We'll fix that
with pipes in the next module. Looking
back at the component, we defined an array
for our list of products. In the template,
we laid out the HTML to display one
product. The product is displayed in a
table row with product properties in the
appropriate columns. Using an ngFor
structural directive, we repeat this table
row and its columns for each product in
the list of products. So why is this ngFor
syntax product of products and not product
in products? The reasoning for this has to
do with ES2015 for loops. Yes, 2015 has
both a for...of loop and a for...in loop.
The for...of loop is similar to a for each
style loop. It iterates over an iterable
object, such as an array. For example, say
we have an array of persons nicknames. If
we use for...of to iterate over this list,
we'll see each nickname logged to the
console. The for...in loop iterates over
the properties of an object. When working
with an array, such as this example, the
array indexes are enumerable properties
with integer names and are otherwise
identical to general object properties. So
we see each array index logged to the
console. To help remember the difference,
think of in as iterating the index. Since
the ngFor directive iterates over iterable
objects, not their properties, Angular
selected to use the of keyword in the
ngFor expression. Now let's finish up this
module with some checklists we can use as
we work with templates, interpolation, and directives.