Checklists are a great way to recheck our
understanding and our work. Let's start
with a template. Use an inline template
when building shorter templates, then
specify the template property in the
Component decorator. Use double or single
quotes to define the template string, or
use the ES2015 back ticks to lay out the
HTML on multiple lines. When using inline
templates, there is often no design‑time
syntax checking, so pay close attention to
the syntax. Use linked templates for
longer templates. Specify the template URL
property in the Component decorator, and
define the path to the external template
file. This one is a more visual checklist.
After building the template, we build its
component and learn how to use that
component as a directive. Remember our
steps? First, we use the directive as an
element in the template for any other
component. We use the directive component
selector as the directive name. We then
declare the component so it is available
to any template associated with this
Angular module. We add the component to
the declarations array passed into the
NgModule decorator of the Angular module.
Angular's data binding was introduced in
this module with a look at interpolation.
Interpolation is one‑way binding from a
component class property to an element
property. Interpolation is defined with
curly braces and a template expression.
That expression can be a simple property,
a concatenation, a calculation, or a
method call. Note that no quotes are
needed when using interpolation. And we
saw how to use two of Angular's structural
directives, ngIf and ngFor. When using
these structural directives, be sure to
prefix them with an asterisk and assign
them to a quoted string expression. Use
ngIf to add or remove an element and its
children from the DOM based on an
expression. If the assigned expression is
evaluated to be a true value, the element
is added to the DOM. If false, the element
is removed from the DOM. Use ngFor to
repeat an element and its children in the
DOM for each element in an iterable list.
Define the local variable with let and use
of, not in when defining the ngFor
expression. In this module, we evaluated
the differences between an inline template
and a linked template, and we created a
linked template. We then built a component
for that template and learned how to use
that component as a directive. We took a
first look at Angular data binding through
interpolation and powered up our template
by using built‑in Angular directives.
Here, once again, is our application
architecture. In this module, we started
the product list component. Next up, let's
discover more of Angular's data binding
features and add interactivity to the product list template.