We've mentioned the Angular CLI a few
times in this course but haven't really
discussed what it is or what it can do.
What seemed like wizardry is instead a
full‑featured tool for building, testing,
and deploying our Angular applications.
Welcome back to Angular: Getting Started,
from Pluralsight. My name is Deborah
Kurata, and in this module we look closer
at the Angular CLI. Let's peek behind the
curtain and learn more about this amazing
tool. In this module, we start with an
overview and discover the purpose and
basic features of the Angular CLI. We then
build an application from scratch using
the CLI and examine the many configuration
and startup files it creates. We dig into
how it serves up our application, learn
more about its cogeneration features, take
a brief look at running tests, and prepare
the resulting application for deployment. Let's get started.