The Angular CLI is a command line
interface for Angular. Its primary purpose
is to assist Angular developers with
building an Angular application,
generating Angular files, and executing,
testing, and deploying Angular
applications. Before you can use the CLI,
you need to install it. Just open a
terminal window or command prompt and type
npm install ‑g @angular/cli. This installs
the CLI globally so you can use it from
any folder. If you have not yet installed
the CLI, do it now. Once you have it
installed, we'll jump into a demo and try
it out. I've already installed the CLI.
Now, how can we find out what the CLI can
do? One option is to use the ng help
feature. We can see that it is listing
every command. Let's try out the version
command. Type ng for the angular CLI and
the command. We'll use the v alias. And we
see a nice text output, including our
angular CLI version. When you watch this
course, you may have a newer version. Use
the help command any time you need
assistance with the CLI commands or their
flags. Now let's build a new application from scratch using the CLI.