Using the Angular CLI, we create a new
Angular application using the new command.
Let's try it out. Here in the terminal
window, we'll type ng new and our new
application name. Let's use a classic,
hello‑world. The CLI has the ability to
provide prompts to ask for more
information. The CLI may add or change
prompts, so your experience may vary from
what you see here. In this specific
example, it's asking whether we want to
add Angular routing to the application. To
keep things simple for our demo, let's
answer No. Next, it asks which style sheet
format we want. Use the arrow keys to
select the desired format. We'll select
CSS and press Enter to select. After we
answer the last question, the CLI
generates our application. Look at all the
files that the CLI created. Now the CLI is
automatically installing the packages
defined in that package.json file. This
takes a bit of time, so I'll jump ahead.
When the CLI new command is finished, we
see a success message. Yay! The CLI
creates a folder with the same name as the
application name. Let's navigate down to
the created hello‑world folder. I'll then
use the shortcut code . to open this
folder in VS Code. Starting at the top,
here is an e2e folder. This folder
contains the start of an end‑to‑end test
for the application. The node_modules
folder contains all of the libraries that
were just installed by the CLI as defined
in the package.json file. The src folder
contains the source code for our
application. Below it is the app folder
where we'll add all of the modules,
components, services, and other files for
our application. The assets folder is for
any images or assets we want to include
with the application. In our APM project,
our welcome page logo is in this folder.
The environments folder sets up our build
environments. By default, it generates
two, one for development and one for
production. The CLI picks the appropriate
environment file based on the flags we
use. The CLI comes with a default favicon.
Nice! Feel free to replace it with
whatever is appropriate for your
application. The index.html file is the
first file downloaded when a user accesses
our application. There isn't much here.
You'd think that there would be at least a
few script tags, but no. We'll see why a
little later. In most cases, you won't
need to ever modify this file. Main.ts is
the file that bootstraps our application.
This is another file you should never need
to modify. The polyfills file aids in
supporting both evergreen and classic
browsers. Pollyfills add code to allow
functionality written for modern browsers
to work in older browsers. By default. It
is set up to support evergreen browsers,
as stated here. If you need to target
older browsers, there are comments in this
file defining which additional libraries
you need. Simply remove the comment marks
from the desired libraries to include
them. Here is a style sheet for
application‑wide styles. As its name
suggests, the test file sets up for
testing. That's it for the src folder. The
browserlistrc file defines the list of
browsers and browser versions that your
application will support. It's used by the
build system to build bundles appropriate
for your supported browsers. The
editorconfig file provides some standard
settings for your editor. The gitignore
tells Git which files to ignore for
checking in to Git. Notice that our large
node_modules folder is included in this
list. Let's skip the CLI configuration
file for a moment and quickly cover the
remaining files here. The karma.config
file sets up Karma, which is a JavaScript
test runner. We'll use that for our unit
tests. We walked through the package.json
file in the First Things First module
earlier in this course. Here's a basic
README. The tsconfig files are for
TypeScript configuration. Lastly, there is
a tslint configuration file. Tslint is a
TypeScript linter which checks our code
against a set of code style rules and
notifies us if any of the rules aren't
followed. This file defines those rules.
Feel free to change these settings based
on your team's selected code style
preferences. Now let's go back to the CLI
configuration file. This file is used to
configure how the CLI generates code and
works with our files. I'm not going to go
through every option here, but want to
point out a few key settings. The assets
array allows us to provide a list of
folders or files that are included with
our application. This defines our
application's selector prefix. Recall that
in the APM application we defined a prefix
of pm. By default, the CLI creates a
prefix of app. If you want to assign a
unique prefix for your application, it is
best to do that as part of the new
command. Use ng new hello‑world ‑‑prefix
hw for hello world or whatever prefix you
prefer. Lastly, any global style sheets
are defined in this styles array. You can
list any number of style sheets as needed,
but only include the global style sheets
here. So that's an overview of the basic
files created by the CLI new command.
Before moving on, let's look at a few key
new command flags. Since we have VS Code
open, we can now use its integrated
terminal. And I'll make it a little
larger. Type ng new ‑‑help. Scrolling back
to the top, we can see that it has many
flags. The ‑‑skip‑install is nice if you
want to generate some code without waiting
for it to install the Node packages. You
can install packages later using npm
install. We've already discussed the
‑‑prefix flag. Feel free to create
additional applications using the new
command with any of these flags. Just note
that you cannot generate a new Angular
application within the folder of an
existing Angular application. And so be
sure to navigate out of the hello‑world
folder before using the new command. The
next thing we want to do is run our
application, so let's check out the serve command.