Once we have a generated application, the
first thing we may want to do is run it.
We do that with the ng serve command.
Let's give that a try. Here in the
TERMINAL window, we'll type ng serve. The
application is then built, and we can see
that it compiled successfully. The CLI
launches a development server and listens
on port 4200. The compiler is now in watch
mode, so it watches for any changes and
automatically recompiles for us. So, where
is it? Where is our application? We can
navigate to the defined port 4200. And
here is the application. It has a slick
welcome page with links to the Tour of
Heroes tutorial, the CLI documentation,
and the Angular team's blog. Feel free to
check out those links. Previously in this
course, we used npm start to run our
application, not ng serve. If we open the
package.json file, we see that the npm
start script is associated with the ng
serve command. So using npm start
basically executes ng serve. We can use
Ctrl+C then y to stop execution. Then type
npm start. The process is the same. We can
see that it executes ng serve. But we
still have to manually bring up a browser
and navigate to the appropriate port. We
haven't had to do that for the other demos
in this course. What's up with that? Let's
look back at the APM application. In the
package.json file that I included with the
starter files for this application, I
added ‑o to the start script. The ‑o is an
alias for the ‑‑open flag, which opens the
default browser. Mystery solved. Going
back to the hello‑world application, let's
stop execution and restart with the ‑o
flag. We type ng serve ‑o, which
automatically opens our default browser
and navigates to our application. But we
can go into our package.json and update it
here if we'd like. Before we move on,
let's take a moment and look more closely
at the output of the ng serve process.
When we use the ng serve command, the CLI
builds the application and outputs it as a
set of bundled JavaScript and map files.
Here we see the list of bundles. These
files are generated in memory and are not
available to find on disk. We'll generate
actual files we can look at when we use
the ng build command shortly. Here is the
application in the browser. We'll open the
developer tools and view the Sources tab.
We see those same bundles here on the
left. And notice our index.html file. The
CLI injected the needed script tags for us
to pull down all of these bundles. Another
mystery solved. Peeking inside the main
bundle, we see something that looks a bit
like our code. Here is our AppModule
transpiled to JavaScript. Unless we
specify otherwise, all of our application
code will be compiled into this bundle.
Since the CLI also generated the
associated map files, we can see that we
have our actual TypeScript code. This
makes it much easier to debug our code, as
we saw earlier in this course. Now I'll
close the browser and use Ctrl+C to stop
the development server. Now let's look at
some of the key flags available with the
serve command. Type ng serve ‑‑help. There
are lots of flags here. Many of these
we'll use with the build command later.
There are two I used regularly. The ‑‑port
flag lets you specify an alternate port so
you don't have to use 4200. And we've seen
the effect of the ‑‑open flag. Now that we
have an application and can run it, we'll
want to add to it. Let's check out the generate command next.