Our new little application is cool and
all, but it doesn't do much. We need to
add components, and templates, and
services, and modules. We do that with a
generate command. We've already seen this
command in action, but it can do so much
more. If we type ng g ‑‑help, this lists
all of the different types of files we can
generate with this command. We can create
simple classes. We can create components
with external template and style sheet
files as we did with the product detail
component earlier in this course. We can
generate our own custom directives, enum
values, and route guards as we did with
our product detail guard. We can create
interfaces and modules. We can create
pipes and services all with only typing a
few characters. Neat! Let's generate a
component. Type ng g c and our component
name, and let's say welcome. The output
indicates that it created a style sheet
file, template HTML file, unit testing
file, and TypeScript file for our
component. By default, it created a
welcome folder and added these files to it.