Testing our Angular code is always
important, but often neglected due to the
additional time and effort required to set
up and execute the tests. The CLI makes it
a bit easier by generating the testing
spec and configuration files for us. We
can run these tests using ng test and ng
e2e. To run our unit tests, in the
terminal window type ng test. This builds
the application, launches the browser, and
executes the Karma test runner. From here,
we can see the results of our unit tests.
Angular generated four tests for us, and
they've all passed, so we are all green.
The test runner runs in watch mode so we
can modify our files and the tests will
immediately rerun. I'll close the browser,
and notice that it tried to bring it up
again. I first need to terminate the test
runner with Ctrl+C, then I'll clear the
screen with cls. We can use the e2e
command to run our end‑to‑end tests using
Protractor. Let's try that out. Ng e2e.
Notice that it pops up the browser,
executes our application, and closes the
browser again. We can see here that it
successfully executed one spec. Testing is
a big topic that is beyond the scope of
this course. See the Pluralsight library
for more information about testing. Now
that we have our application built and tested, we are ready to deploy.