An application is not very useful unless
you can deploy it to your users. The build
command helps you prepare your application
for deployment. Let's take a look. Here in
the terminal window we'll type ng build.
The output is similar to the ng serve
command. When the ng build process is
complete, we have a dist folder here in
our project. If we open the folder, we see
our actual bundles. We can look again at
the main bundle .js file and find our
code. And here is the resulting index.html
file with the script tags to pull in each
bundle. We can then deploy these files to
a server somewhere. But wait, there's
more. When we deploy it to production,
there are a few more things that we want
to achieve. We want our bundles to be as
small as possible. This means that we want
to minify or uglify the code and perform
something called tree shaking. Tree
shaking shakes up our code to drop out any
dead branches, which basically means that
it removes any unused pieces. The CLI will
do all of these things for us if we simply
add the ‑‑prod flag. Let's try that out.
Type ng build ‑‑prod. Now if we look at
the files in the dist folder, we notice
that they have a hash as part of the file
name. This is a cache‑busting technique.
Every time we update something in our
code, it needs to be redeployed to the
server. We expect the new version of the
files to be downloaded by the browser when
a user accesses our application. But for
performance reasons, the browser may have
cached those files. By changing the file
names using a hash, the browser will
download the latest version because the
file names won't match its cached
versions. Notice also that there are no
map files here. By default, the ‑‑prod
flag does not generate map files, but
there is a flag for that if you need them.
Peeking into the main bundle, all the code
is on one line. And look at those variable
names. It's been minified. Glad we don't
have to debug using that code. Let's look
at some of the key flags available with
the build command. Type ng build ‑‑help.
We'll scroll up a bit. There are quite a
few flags here to help you tune exactly
what you want the built command to do. One
of the other key flags here is the
‑‑base‑href. Recall that we set the base
element in our index.html file to specify
the root path for our Angular routing. But
when we deploy it to production, we may
not want to deploy to the root path of our
server. We can use the ‑‑base‑href flag to
set the appropriate based URL for the
deployed application. Wow, the CLI is
powerful. Now let's finish up this module
with some checklists we can use as we leverage the Angular CLI.