Here are the key CLI commands for
reference. Use ng help or ng, a command
name ‑‑help to view the CLI documentation.
The remaining commands here help you
create, execute, build, test, and deploy
your Angular application. You may find
yourself using ng generate a lot. Refer to
this checklist as you generate the code
files for your application. In this
module, we discovered the purpose and
basic features of the CLI. We built an
application from scratch and examined it's
many configuration and startup files. We
dug into how it serves up our application,
learned about its code generation
features, looked at running tests, and
prepared the resulting application for
deployment. Now that we've peeked behind
the curtain, you know the secrets of the
CLI. There is no wizardry here. There are
more commands and many more flags than
what we discussed in this module. To learn
more about the Angular CLI, check out John
Papa's course happily entitled, Angular
CLI in the Pluralsight library, it covers
many more of its amazing features. Only one module left.