There's more to data binding than just
displaying component properties. Welcome
back to Angular: Getting Started from
Pluralsight. My name is Deborah Kurata,
and in this module, we explore more data
binding features and transform bound data
with pipes. To provide a great interactive
user experience, we want to bind DOM
elements to component properties, so the
component can change the look and feel as
needed. We can use bindings to change
element colors or styles based on data
values, update font size based on user
preferences or a sudden image source from
a database field. And we want notification
of user actions and other events from the
DOM, so the component can respond
accordingly. For example, we respond to a
click on a button to hide or show images.
And sometimes we want the best of both
worlds using two‑way binding to set an
element property and receive event
notifications of user changes to that
property. In this module, we'll use
Angular's property binding to set HTML
element properties in the DOM. We walk
through how to handle user events, such as
a button click, with event binding and how
to handle user input with two‑way binding.
Lastly, we'll discover how to transform
bound data with pipes. And here, once
again, is our application architecture. We
have the first cut of our
ProductListComponent, but it doesn't have
any interactivity. In this module, we'll
use data binding features to add
interactivity to the ProductListComponent. Let's get started.