Property binding allows us to set a
property of an element to the value of a
template expression. Here we bind the src
property of the img element to the
imageUrl property of the product,
effectively defining the source of the
image from information in our component
class. Our binding target is always
enclosed in square brackets to the left of
the equals and identifies a property of
the element. The binding source is always
enclosed in quotes to the right of the
equals and specifies the template
expression. For comparison, here is a
similar binding using interpolation. Note
that in this case the element property is
not enclosed in square brackets, and the
template expression is enclosed in curly
braces with no quotes. If you need to
include the template expression as part of
a larger expression, such as this example,
you may need to use interpolation. Like
interpolation, property binding is one way
from the source class property to the
target element property. It effectively
allows us to control our template's DOM
from our component class. Now let's add
some property binding to our sample
application. Here we are back in the
editor looking at the ProductListComponent
and its associated template. Let's use
property binding to bind the source of our
product image. We use an img element to
display our product image, and we'll use
property binding to bind the image's
source, or src, property. So we enclose
the src in square brackets. On the right
side of the equals, we define the template
expression in quotes. We want to bind to
the product's imageUrl property from the
ProductListComponent class. Let's also use
property binding to bind the title
property of the image to the product's
name. Let's check out the result in the
browser. Whoa, they're big, but we do see
images. If we hover over an image, we see
the image title. But this image is rather
large for display in our table. Let's use
property binding to set some style
properties. Let's add properties for the
image width an image margin to our
component class. The imageWidth is a
number, so we specify its type with a
colon and then number. Let's set it to 50.
The imageMargin is also a number, and
we'll set it to 2. Back in the template,
we use property binding to bind the image
styles. We want to bind the style property
width in pixels. We'll bind that to the
imageWidth property from the component
class. Notice that we don't prefix this
property with product because image with
is a property of the component class, not
the product object. And we do the same
with the style.margin in pixels and set
that to the imageMargin class property. So
now we've seen how to use property binding
to bind several properties of the image
element to properties of the component's
class. Before we look at the result, let's
talk about TypeScript's type inference. To
learn about TypeScript's strong typing,
we've been adding data types to our
properties. However, if we set a
property's default value, we often don't
need to specify its type. TypeScript will
infer the type from its value. For
example, since the pageTitle property is
assigned to a string, we don't need to
specify its type. TypeScript will infer it
as a string. Same for the numeric values.
If you use a linting tool, it may flag any
properties with an unnecessary data type.
Feel free to remove these unnecessary
types. I'll leave them here for reference.
Now, looking back at the browser, our
image sizes look much better, but our
images are always displayed. The Show
Image button doesn't work yet. To hook up
the button, we need to respond to user events. Let's do that next.