So far, all of our data binding has been
one way, from the component class property
to the element property. But there are
times we need to send information the
other way to respond to user events. For
example, to perform an operation when the
user clicks a button. A component listens
for user actions using event binding, as
shown here. Notice how similar this syntax
is to property binding. In this example,
the component listens for the click event
on a button. The name of the bound event
is enclosed in parentheses, identifying it
as the target event. To the right of the
equals is the template statement. This is
often the name of a component class
method, followed by open and closing
parentheses and enclosed in quotes. If the
defined event occurs, the template
statement is executed, calling the
specified method in the component.
Wondering where you might find a list of
valid DOM events? Check out this link. The
Mozilla Developer Network provides a
thorough list of standard events, along
with some documentation. Now let's give
event binding a try. In this demo, we want
to implement our Show Image button. First,
we define a class property that keeps
track of whether the images are currently
displayed. We'll call that property
showImage. Since this property is true or
false, we define its type as boolean. And
let's set its default value to false so
the images are not displayed when the page
is first loaded. Next, we build the method
that the event binding will call. By
convention, methods are normally created
after all of the properties are defined,
so we'll put it down here. Let's name the
method toggleImage. Notice that TypeScript
does not require any keywords, such as
function. Following the method name with
open and closing parentheses identifies it
as a method. Our method won't have a
return type, so we specify the return type
as void. The body of the method simply
toggles the state of the showImage
property. The bang, or exclamation point,
used here is a logical not operator. It
returns false if its operand, showImage in
this case, is true and true if showImage
is false, basically toggling the value
from true to false or false to true. Back
in the template, we are ready to set up
the event binding. On the button element,
we define the click as the target event by
enclosing it in parentheses. We assign it
to our method enclosed in quotes. When the
user clicks the button, the binding calls
our method. So the only thing left is to
actually hide or show the image. Recall
how we add logic to add or remove HTML
elements from the DOM? If you said the
ngIf directive, you are right. We'll add
ngIf to the image element. We only want
this image element if the showImage flag
is true. So we type *ngIf= 'showImage'.
The image element will then only be added
to the DOM if showImage is true. Let's see
if this works. Are we ready to give it a
try? Click the button, and the image
appears. Click the button again, and the
image disappears. Oh, very cool. The only
odd thing is the button text. When the
image is displayed, the button text should
change to Hide Image. So up here where we
have the button text, let's use
interpolation. When showImage is true, we
want the button text to say Hide Image,
and when showImage is false, we want the
button text to say Show Image. We
accomplish this using a JavaScript
conditional operator. We specify the
condition, which is showImage and a
question mark. Then we specify the true
expression. So when showImage is true, we
want to display Hide Image. Then we add a
colon and the false expression. So when
showImage is false, we want it to say Show
Image. Basically, we can read this syntax
as if showImage is true, display Hide;
otherwise, display Show. Let's check this
out in the browser. So our button text now
says Show Image. If we click it, it says
Hide Image. Ah, that seems a little more
user friendly. Cool. Before we move on,
let's talk a moment about Angular's change
detection. By default, Angular is
constantly watching for changes to any
bound properties and listening for events.
In our sample application, we have a
button that shows or hides images. In the
HTML for the button, we bound it's click
event to a method in our component, and we
used interpolation to change the text of
the button based on the value of a
property in our component. In the product
list, we used the ngIf structural
directive to add or remove the image
element from the DOM. The showImage
property is initially false, so the button
text displays Show Image, and the ngIf
removed the image from the display. When
the user clicks the button, Angular
executes the method bound to the click
event. The code and the method toggles the
showImage property from false, its default
value, to true. Angular's change detection
detects that change and automatically
reevaluates all the bindings. The
interpolation changes the button text from
Show to Hide, and the ngIf ads the image
element to the DOM, displaying the image.
This is the Angular way to modify DOM
elements. Now that we have our images
working, let's tackle the Filtered by box, and for that, we need two‑way binding.