When working with user entry HTML
elements, such as an input element, we
often want to display a component class
property in the template and update that
property when the user makes a change.
This process requires two‑way binding. To
specify two‑way binding in Angular, we use
the ngModel directive. We enclose ngModel
in square brackets to indicate property
binding from the class property to the
input element, and parentheses to indicate
event binding to send a notification of
the user‑entered data back to the class
property. We assign this directive to a
template expression. To help us remember
which order to put the two sets of
brackets, visualize a banana in a box.
Square brackets for the box on the outside
and parentheses for the banana on the
inside. So now we have another Angular
directive that we can use. Every time we
want to use an Angular directive in a
template, we need to consider how to make
that directive visible to the component
associated with that template. Recall that
an Angular module defines the boundary or
context within which the component
resolves its directives and dependencies.
The illustration of our AppModule
currently looks like this. We want to use
the ngModel directive in our
ProductListComponent, which is owned by
AppModule. So in the AppModule, we need to
import the appropriate system module that
exposes the ngModel directive. Since the
ngModel directive is most often used when
building data entry forms, ngModel is part
of FormsModule, so we import that here.
Now, the ngModel directive and any of the
other Angular forms directives are visible
to any component declared by AppModule,
including our ProductListComponent. Now
let's give this a try. We are back in the
editor and looking at the
ProductListComponent and its associated
template. Recall that we defined a Filter
by input box here and display the entered
filter here. We'll later use the filter to
filter our list of products. Let's start
by adding a component class property for
the listFilter. This property is a string,
and we'll set a default initial value for
filtering the list of products. We hard
code the filter string here, but you can
imagine that we store the user's last
entered filter and use that as the default
instead. With that, we can set up the
two‑way binding. On the input element, we
draw a banana in a box, then specify the
ngModel directive. We bind to the
component class listFilter property. We
want to display the list filter here, so
we use interpolation. Recall that
interpolation has no quotes. Are we done?
Not quite. Let's open the terminal window.
We see an error, Can't bind to ngModel
since it isn't a known property of input.
This is telling us that Angular can't find
the ngModel directive. Recall from the
slides that the ngModel directive is part
of the Angular module for forms called
FormsModule. To expose this directive to
our ProductListComponent, we need to
import the FormsModule in the module that
owns the ProductListComponent, which is
our AppModule. We start by importing
FormsModule from @angular/forms. We then
add FormsModule to the imports array for
the NgModule decorator. Why the imports
array and not the declarations? Our
directives, components, and pipes are
declared here in the declarations array.
Directives, components, and pipes we use
from other sources, such as Angular itself
or third parties, are defined in external
Angular modules we add to the imports
array here. Now that we've told Angular
where to find the ngModel, let's see the
result. When the page displays, we see
cart as the default value. It is displayed
here and here. If we modify the entry,
notice that the displayed filter text is
also updated. That's because we are using
two‑way binding. Notice that the list of
products is not yet filtered. We'll do
that in the next module. There is one more
thing we do want to address now, and that
is the data formatting. That price should
really look like a price and show the appropriate currency symbol.