With Angular's data binding, displaying
data is easy, just bind an element
property to a class property and we're
done. Well, not always. Sometimes the data
is not in a format appropriate for a
display. That's where pipes come in handy.
Pipes transform bound properties before
they are displayed so we can alter the
property values to make them more user
friendly or more locale appropriate.
Angular provides some built‑in pipes for
formatting values such as date, number,
decimal, percent, currency, uppercase,
lowercase, and so on. Angular also
provides a few pipes for working with
objects, such as the Json Pipe to display
the content of an object as a Json string,
which is helpful when debugging, and a
slice pipe, which selects a specific
subset of elements from a list. We can
also build our own custom pipes as we'll
see in the next module. Let's start with a
simple example. Say we want to display the
product code in lowercase. We can add the
pipe character after the property in the
template expression and then specify the
lowercase pipe. The product code is then
transformed into lowercase before it is
displayed. We can also use pipes and
property bindings, add the pipe after the
property in the template expression and
specify the desired pipe. In this example,
we specified the uppercase pipe so the
image title will appear in all caps. If
needed, we can chain pipes. In this
example, the price is transformed into a
currency. By default, the currency pipe
adds the all caps three‑letter
abbreviation of the local currency to the
amount. If we want to display that
abbreviation in lowercase, we can
transform it again by simply adding
another pipe. Some pipes support
parameters. Parameters are defined by
specifying a colon and the parameter
value. For example, the currency pipe has
three parameters, the desired currency
code, a string defining how to show the
currency symbol, and digit info. The digit
info consists of the minimum number of
integer digits, the minimum number of
fractional digits, and the maximum number
of fractional digits. The value here of
1.2‑2 means at least 1 digit to the left
of the decimal and at least 2 digits to
the right of the decimal and no more than
2 digits to the right of the decimal
effectively defining 2 decimal places.
With that, let's jump back to the demo. We
specify the pipes in the template, so we
are looking at the product list component
template. Let's add a lowercase pipe for
the product code and a currency pipe for
the price. For the product code, we simply
insert the pipe character after the
property in the template expression and
type lowercase. That's it. For the price,
we insert a pipe character and currency.
That's all that is required, but let's try
out a few of the parameters. We'll specify
USD symbol to display the dollar sign
instead of the currency abbreviation, and
1.2‑2 to specify that we want at least 1
number to the left of the decimal place
and 2 and only 2 numbers to the right of
the decimal place. Let's see how we did.
Ah, looking at the result, we now see the
product code in lowercase and the price
displayed nicely as the currency. So we
can easily perform simple data
transformations using the built‑in pipes
in the template expressions for our
bindings. Feel free to try out some of the
other pipes from the slides. Let's finish
up this module with some diagrams and a
checklist we can use as we work with bindings and pipes.