Data binding makes it easy to display
class properties from our component and
set DOM element properties to our class
property values to better control the
view. And the component can listen for
events from the DOM to respond as needed
for an interactive user experience. There
are four basic types of binding in
Angular. Here is a diagram as a memory
aid. Interpolation inserts interpolated
strings into the text between HTML
elements or assigns element properties. Be
sure to wrap the template expression in
curly braces and no quotes. Property
binding sets an element's property to the
value of a template expression. The
binding target specifies a property of the
element and must be enclosed in square
brackets. The binding source specifies the
template expression and must be enclosed
in quotes. Event binding listens for
events and executes a template statement
when the event occurs. The target event
specifies an event name and must be
enclosed in parentheses. The template
statement often defines the name of the
method to call when the event occurs and
must be enclosed in quotes. Two‑way
binding displays a component class
property and updates the property when the
user makes a change. Use the banana in a
box syntax with the NgModel directive. The
binding source specifies the template
expression and must be enclosed in quotes.
Here are some things to remember when
using NgModel. Define NgModel within the
banana in a box for two‑way binding. Be
sure to add FormsModule from the Angular
forms package to the imports array of an
appropriate Angular module, in this case,
AppModule. This ensures that the ngModel
directive is available to any template
defined in a component associated with
that module. We'll talk more about Angular
modules later in this course. The data we
have in our component may not be in the
format we want for display. We can use a
pipe in a template to transform that data
to a more user‑friendly format. To use a
pipe, specify the pipe character, the name
of the pipe, and any pipe parameters,
separated with colons. Here is an example
of the currency pipe with three
parameters. This module covered data
binding and pipes. We looked at property
binding, event binding, and two‑way
binding. Lastly, we discovered how to
transform bound data to a more
user‑friendly format using built‑in pipes.
And here once again is our application
architecture. In this module, we finished
more of the Product List Component, but it
could be better. Next up, we'll see
several techniques for improving our component.