In the last module, we set up the
infrastructure for our Angular
application. Now we are ready to build our
first component. Welcome back to Angular:
Getting Started, from Pluralsight. My name
is Deborah Kurata, and in this module, we
walk through building a very basic
component with a focus on clearly defining
the component's parts, their meaning, and
their purpose. We can think of our Angular
application as a set of components. We
create each component, then arrange them
to form our application. If all goes well,
those components work together in harmony
to provide the user with a great
experience. In this module, we take a
closer look at what an Angular component
is and examine the code we need to build
one. We walk through how to create the
component's class and how and why we need
to define metadata. We look at how to
import what we need from external modules,
and we discover how to bootstrap the app
component to bring our application to
life. We'll continue to add to this
application throughout this course.
Lastly, we discuss the Angular compiler
and where to find syntax and compiler
error messages in case something goes
wrong along the way. Looking again at our
application architecture that we defined
in the first module, I had used the
Angular CLI to create the initial content
for my starter files, including the
index.html file and the app component,
which I then updated for our sample
application. In this module, we'll rebuild this app component. Let's get started.