An Angular component includes a template,
which lays out the user interface
fragment, defining a view for the
application. It is created with HTML and
defines what is rendered on the page. We
use Angular binding and directives in the
HTML to power up the view. We'll cover
binding and directives in a later module.
Add to that a class for the code
associated with the view, the classes
created with TypeScript. The class
contains the properties or data elements
available for use in the view. For
example, if we want to display a title in
the view, we define a class property for
that title. The class also contains
methods, which are the functions for the
logic needed by the view. For example, if
we want to show and hide an image, we'd
write the logic in a class method. A
component also has metadata, which
provides additional information about the
component to Angular. It is this metadata
that defines this class as an Angular
component. The metadata is defined with a
decorator. A decorator is a function that
adds metadata to a class, its members, or
its method arguments. So a component is a
view defined in a template, it's
associated code defined with the class,
and metadata defined with a decorator.
Want to see what a component looks like in
TypeScript? Here is a simple component. It
might look complex at first, so let's
break this component into chunks, starting
at the bottom. Here is our class. It
defines the properties and methods needed
by our view. Here is the component
decorator that defines the metadata. The
metadata includes the template that lays
out the view managed by this component,
and here we import the members that we
need. Let's examine each of these chunks
in more detail, starting at the bottom with the class.