If you have done any object‑oriented
programming in languages such a C#,
VB.NET, Java, or C++, this code should
look familiar. A class is a construct that
allows us to create a type with properties
that define the data elements and methods
that provide functionality. We define a
class using the class keyword followed by
the class name. A common Angular
convention is to name each component class
with the feature name, then append the
word component as the suffix. Also, by
convention, the root component for an
application is called AppComponent, as
shown here. This class name is used as the
component name when the component is
referenced in code. The export keyword
here at the front exports this class,
thereby making it available for use by
other components of the application. And
as we learned in the last course module,
since this file exports something, this
file is now an ES module. Within the body
of the class are the properties and
methods. In this example, we only have one
property and no methods. A property
defines a data element associated with the
class. We start with the property name,
which by convention is a noun describing
the data element, and it is in camelCase,
whereby the first letter of the name is
lowercase. In this example, it is the
title of the page. Using TypeScript's
strong typing, we follow the property name
with a colon and its data type. In this
example, the pageTitle property is a
string. We can optionally assign a default
value to the property as shown in this
example. Methods are normally defined
within the class body after all of the
properties. Method names are often verbs
that describe the action the method
performs. Method names are also in
camelCase, whereby the first letter of the
name is lowercase. So that's it for the
class. But a class alone is not enough to
define a component. We need to define the
template associated with this component
class. How do we provide this extra
information to Angular? With metadata. Let's look at that next.