A class becomes an Angular component when
we give it component metadata. Angular
needs that metadata to understand how to
instantiate the component, construct the
view, and interact with the component. We
define a component's metadata with the
Angular component function. In TypeScript,
we attach that function to the class as a
decorator. A decorator is a function that
adds metadata to a class, its members, or
its method arguments. A decorator is a
JavaScript language feature that is
implemented in TypeScript. The scope of
the decorator is limited to the feature
that it decorates. A decorator is always
prefixed with an @ sign. Angular has
several built‑in decorators we used to
provide additional information to Angular.
We can also build our own decorators, but
that is out of the scope of this course.
We apply a decorator by positioning it
immediately in front of the feature we are
decorating. When decorating a class, as in
this example, we define the decorator
immediately above the class signature.
Notice that there is no semicolon here.
This syntax is similar to attributes used
in other programming languages. We used
the @Component decorator to identify the
class as a component. Since the decorator
is a function, we always add parentheses.
We pass an object to the component
function as indicated with the curly
braces. The object we pass in, has many
properties. We are only using two of them
here. If we plan to reference the
component in any HTML, we specify a
selector. The selector defines the
component's directive name. A directive is
simply a custom HTML tag. Whenever this
directive is used in the HTML, Angular
renders this component's template. We'll
see how this works in the upcoming demo. A
component should always have a template.
Here we define the layout for the user
interface fragment or view managed by this
component. The double curly braces
indicate data binding. We bind the h1
element value to the pageTitle property of
the class. So when this HTML is rendered,
the h1 element displays Acme Product
Management. We'll see that in the upcoming
demo as well, and we'll cover more about
binding in a later module. There is one
more key task before our component is complete, importing.