Before we can use an external function or
class, we need to define where to find it.
We do that with an import statement. The
import statement is part of ES2015 and
implemented in TypeScript. It is
conceptually similar to the import
statement in Java or the C# using
statement. The import statement allows us
to use exported members from external
modules. Remember how we just exported our
class using the export keyword? That means
that other modules in our application can
import our exported class if needed. We'll
use the import statement throughout our
code to import any third‑party library,
any of our own modules, or from Angular
itself. We can import from Angular because
Angular is modular. It is a collection of
library modules. Each library is itself a
module made up of several related feature
modules. When we need something from
Angular, we import it from an Angular
library module, just like we import from
any other external module. Use this link
if you want to view the list of available
Angular library packages and their current
versions. In our component code, we use
the @Component decorator function from
Angular to define our class as a
component. We need to tell Angular where
to find this function, so we add an import
statement and import  from
'@angular/core'; like this. We start with
the import keyword. We identify the name
of the member we need within curly braces.
In this case, we need the @Component
decorator function, and we define the path
to the module containing that member. In
this case, the @angular/core library
module. If we need multiple members from
the same module, we can list them all in
the imports list, separated by commas.
We'll see examples of that later in this
course. So this is a component. Now we're
ready to build the first component for our sample application. Let's jump in.