In this demo, we build our app component,
which is the root component for our
application. Here we are in the editor
with the APM folder open. This is the
folder we set up in the last module from
the starter files I provided. Let's open
the src folder, and under that, the app
folder. Since I used the Angular CLI to
create the starter files, it created the
root app component. It named the file
app.component.ts. The file naming
convention that we'll follow throughout
this course is to start with the feature
name. This is our root application
component, so by convention, it's called
app, then a dot, then the type of ES
module defined in this file, in this case,
component, to identify this ES module as a
component. Another dot and the extension.
Since we are using TypeScript, we'll use
ts as the extension. Let's open that file.
In VS Code, I can click the Explorer icon
to close the Explorer and see more of the
code. I can reopen the Explorer by
clicking the icon again. Now I'll delete
the starter code for this file so we can
build the app component from scratch. I
like to start coding by building the
class, but the order of these steps really
don't matter. When we build a class, we
first type in the export keyword to ensure
that other parts of the application can
use this class. Next, we type in the class
keyword, then the name of the class. Since
this is our application component class,
we'll follow conventions and name it
AppComponent. Inside this class, we'll
define one property, the pageTitle. We
type the property name followed by a colon
and the property data type, which for the
pageTitle is a string. Notice how
IntelliSense helps us here. For this
property, we want to define a default
value for the pageTitle. Next, we define
the Component decorator above the class.
The Component decorator always begins with
an at sign, then the name of the
decorator, and we're using the Component
decorator. The Component decorator is a
function, so we type parentheses. And
we're going to pass in an object, so we
type in curly braces. Notice how
TypeScript has underlined the Component
decorator and flagged it as an error. The
error is, Can't find name 'Component'. Any
guesses on what the problem is? If you
said that we are missing the import
statement, you are right. We need to
import the Component decorator from
Angular/core. Now the error underline goes
away, and we can complete the metadata. In
the Component metadata, we specify a
selector for the name of this component
when used as a directive in the HTML. Now
that we've imported the appropriate
module, we get IntelliSense for these
properties. We set the selector two
pm‑root. The current convention is to
prefix each selector with something to
identify it as part of our application, so
we selected pm for product management. We
end with a name that represents this
component, so we used root since this is
our root app component. We'll see how to
identify our desired selector prefix to
the Angular CLI in the building, testing,
and deploying with the CLI module later in
this course. Next, we define the template.
To specify another property here, we enter
a comma and then the name of the other
property. We want to define template. Any
valid HTML can be specified in the
template. We'll dive deeper into templates
in a later module. So for this example,
I'll just paste in the HTML, and we're
done. We have now created the first
component for our application. Yay! But
how do we use it? How do we display its template?