You may have heard the saying, pulling
yourself up by your bootstraps, originally
meaning to improve your situation by your
own efforts. In tech, it has come to mean
a self‑starting process that loads and
goes. We need to tell Angular to load our
root component through a process that is
called bootstrapping. We first set up the
index.html file to host our application.
Then we define our root Angular module to
bootstrap our root component. Let's look
at both of these steps. Client‑side web
applications often work like this: A user
accesses a specific URL. The server
associated with that URL is located and
sent a request. The server responds by
returning its default web page,
index.html. The browser receives and
processes that index.html file. For an
Angular application, the index.html file
contains script tags referencing the
application files that were transpired and
bundled into several JavaScript files.
These application files are then
downloaded to and processed by the
browser, and the application's main page
appears. The index.html file contains that
main page for the application. This
index.html file is often the one true web
page of the application. Hence, an
application is often called a single‑page
application, or SPA. But don't worry. It
will look to the user like we have lots of
pages, as we saw in the demo at the
beginning of this course. What we do is
insert bits of HTML into the one HTML page
defined in index.html. Let's see how that
works. Here again is our AppComponent just
shifted to the right. Recall that the
selector is the name of the component when
we use it as a directive in HTML. And the
template defines the HTML that we want to
display. So in the index.html file we
simply add the selector where we want our
template displayed. Here in the template
we call this a directive. A directive is
basically a custom element. As soon as the
loading is complete, the HTML defined in
the component template is inserted between
the selector element tags and appears on
the page. But how does the Angular
compiler know about this custom HTML
element? It looks in an Angular module.
Angular modules help us organize our
application into cohesive blocks of
functionality and provide boundaries
within our application. They also provide
a template resolution environment. What
does that mean? When the Angular compiler
sees a directive and a template, it looks
to the Angular module for the definition.
So we declare the AppComponent in an
Angular module so the compiler can find
it. We also use the module to bootstrap
our startup component, which is our
AppComponent. And we want our application
to work correctly in the browser, so we
add Angular's BrowserModule to our Angular
module's imports. Okay, pictures are nice,
but what does that look like in code? Here
is our application's root Angular module.
As with most everything in Angular, we
define an Angular module using a class. We
identify the class as an Angular module by
attaching the NgModule decorator and
passing in metadata defining the details
of this Angular module. For the NgModule
decorator, the properties are arrays. In
the declarations array, we define which of
our components belong to this module. By
convention, our root application
component, AppComponent, belongs to the
application's root Angular module,
AppModule, so we declare it here. We can
add other components here as well. We'll
cover best practices for organizing our
application into Angular modules later in
this course. For now, all of our
components will be declared here. In the
imports array, we define the external
modules that we want to have available to
all of the components that belong to this
Angular module. External modules could be
modules provided by Angular, a third
party, or our own Angular modules. Here we
import BrowserModule, which every browser
application must import. BrowserModule
registers important application service
providers such as error handling. The
bootstrap array defines the startup
component of the application, which is our
AppComponent. The startup component should
contain the selector we use in the
index.html file, which in this case it
does. Now let's check it out in the sample application.