In this demo, we'll set up index.html to
host our application and examine the root
Angular module that bootstraps our app
component. Here we are back with our
sample application exactly how we left it.
Since I used the Angular CLI to create
these starter files, the index.html file
is already hosting our app component, and
the app.module.ts file already bootstraps
our app component. Let's take a look
starting with the index.html file. To host
our application, we use the component
selector as a directive here within the
body element. We can think of a directive
as simply a custom HTML tag. Since I used
the Angular CLI to create the starter
files, the directive is already included
here. Now let's open the app.module.ts
file. Here is the class, and here is the
@NgModule decorator defining this class as
an Angular module. The declaration's array
declares the AppComponent so that Angular
can locate its selector. The imports array
includes BrowserModule so the application
runs correctly in the browser, and the
bootstrap array lists our AppComponent as
the starting component for our
application. Looks like we are ready to
run. We saw in the last module how to
start the application by typing npm start
in a terminal or command window. When the
root AppComponent is loaded, the HTML from
our component appears, and the binding in
that HTML is replaced with the value of
our page title property. We now have a
working, albeit very small, application.
Before closing the browser, let's take a
moment and look at the browser developer
tools. In Chrome, I'll press F12. The
exact tools you see here depend on the
browser you are using. I'm using Chrome.
Most modern browsers provide a Console tab
as part of the development tools. This is
always the first place to look if the page
does not appear as expected or doesn't
appear at all. Errors, warnings, and other
information is displayed here. Use the
Elements tab or DOM explorer to view the
HTML displayed in the page. This is a
depiction of the DOM, or document object
model. The document object model is a
document model loaded into the browser and
represents our HTML as a node tree where
each node is a part of our HTML. Notice
these scripts listed here. These aren't in
our source index.html file. We'll talk
about these bundles, what they are, and
how they got here in the Building,
Testing, and Deploying with the CLI module
later in this course. Here is our selector
tag. Open the selector tag, and we see the
HTML that we defined in our Components
template. This view is a great way to see
the HTML for the rendered page. There is
also a debugger option available here on
the Sources tab to view in debugger code.
Since the Angular CLI uses webpack, our
TypeScript files are listed under the
webpack node here. And because the Angular
CLI serve feature generates the map files,
we can debug our TypeScript code directly.
We can set a break point, refresh the
browser, and it hits that break point. We
can step through and check the value of
any of our properties. Click here to
resume. Use these debugging features
anytime you need them. Before we move on,
let's talk a moment about the Angular compiler.