Because browsers don't understand the
components and templates we build, Angular
applications require a compile process to
convert our templates and TypeScript code
into JavaScript. Angular has two
compilers, a Just In Time, or JIT,
compiler, which was used during
development. It compiles our application
in the browser at runtime, making it quick
and forgiving. And an Ahead Of Time, or
AOT, compiler, which was used for
deployment. It compiles the application
ahead of time before serving it to the
browser, so we don't need to include the
Angular compiler and the compiled bundles,
which means smaller bundles, less for the
users to download, and faster rendering.
Having two compilers was sometimes a
problem in that our code would work fine
when compiled with the JIT compiler during
development, but would fail when compiled
with the AOT compiler for production.
Starting with Angular version 9, the
performance of the AOT compiler was
improved enough to use it for development
as well. It now compiles before serving
the application to the browser. Using one
compiler for both development and
deployment mitigates any issues early and
not during that final build for
production. However, the AOT compiler
comes with some changes in how we see our
syntax and compile errors. When we start
our application with npm start, Angular
compiles then serves the application to
the browser. If the application has
compilation errors, we may see this in the
browser, cannot GET. That's not very
helpful. Using the F12 developer tools, we
see Failed to load resource: the server
responded with a status of 404 (Not
Found). In this case, this message is
telling us that Angular could not serve
our application to the browser because it
could not successfully compile it. If the
application was already running
successfully, and then we make a change
that causes a compile error, we may see
the last successful compile files in the
browser, or we may see a black overlay
with an error message. In any of these
cases, the best course of action is to
open the VS Code terminal window. It will
display any and all compile errors.
Consider the terminal window to be the
source of truth for compile‑related
errors. You may, however, find from time
to time that as you modify the code, the
terminal window shows errors that were
already corrected. When that happens, stop
the compiler with Ctrl+C or Cmd+C and
restart it with npm start. Now let's
finish up this module with some checklists we can use as we build our own components.