Angular is all about components, so our
first set of checklists are for building a
component. We create a class for the
component with code to support the view.
We use a decorator to define the component
metadata, which includes the HTML for the
component's template. And we import what
we need from any third‑party library, from
our modules, or from Angular itself. When
creating the component class, we give it a
clear name. This is not only the name of
the class but the name of the component as
well. Be sure to watch the casing since
JavaScript is case sensitive. By
convention use PascalCasing, whereby every
word of the name is capitalized. It is
common to append component to the end of
the class name to make it clear that it is
a component class. Be sure to include the
export keyword on the class signature.
Recall what the export keyword does? It
makes the class accessible to be imported
by other parts of the application. If the
component view displays data, such as a
title, the data element is defined as a
property of the class. To leverage
TypeScript's strong typing, be sure to set
the appropriate data type for each
property, and set a default value where
appropriate. Use camelCase for property
names with the first letter lowercase. If
the component view has functionality, such
as hiding and showing an image, the logic
is defined as methods in the class. Use
camelCase for method names with the first
letter lowercase. How do we define the
metadata for our component? If you said a
component decorator, you are right. A
class is not a component unless it has a
component decorator. Be sure to prefix the
decorator with an @. Since a decorator is
a function, add parentheses, and pass in
the appropriate object properties. Use the
selector property to define the name of
the component when used as a directive in
HTML. Be sure to prefix the selector for
clarity. Note that the selector property
is not needed if the component is not used
in any HTML, as we'll see later in this
course. Use the template property in the
component metadata to define the view's
HTML. Since we define the HTML in a string
literal, we often get no IntelliSense or
syntax checking. So take care to define
correct HTML syntax. We'll see alternate
ways to create the template for a
component in the next module. So why do we
need to use import? The import statement
tells Angular where to find the members
that this component needs from any
external modules. The import statement
requires the import keyword followed by
the member name and module path. Take care
when defining the member name as it is
case sensitive. The path to the module
file must be enclosed in quotes and is
also case sensitive. And remember that we
don't need to specify the file extension.
So what do you do if you followed the
steps, but the sample application doesn't
work for you? You follow the Something's
Wrong! checklist. First, press the F12 key
in the browser to view the developer tools
and check the console. If that wasn't
helpful, check the VS Code terminal
window. That will display any syntax or
compile errors. The compile messages are
often quite clear if you scroll up and
read the first one generated after the
last compile. It may also be useful to
stop the compiler with Ctrl+C or Cmd+C and
restart it with npm start for a fresh
compile. That will display any current
compilation errors. When resolving an
error, or if you aren't getting expected
results in the browser, recheck your code.
For any HTML, be sure the tags are all
correctly closed and that all of the
Angular directives are correctly spelled
and cased. Angular directives are case
sensitive. For the TypeScript code, be
sure the braces are all properly closed.
And just like JavaScript, TypeScript is
case sensitive, so ensure everything has
the appropriate case. If there doesn't
appear to be anything wrong with the code,
check my blog post as described in the
first course module. Here's the link. I'll
add common sample application problems and
their solutions to this post. Note that I
don't get notified if you post comments on
my blog, so consider posting comments
elsewhere, as described next. If there's
nothing on my blog that solves your issue,
post a comment on the Discussion page for
the course. Here's the link. I normally
get notified of every post to the
Discussion page, plus other Pluralsight
subscribers will see your post and can
respond. Following these steps should get
you back on the path to success with
Angular. In this module, we detailed what
a component was and how to build one by
creating a component class, defining the
metadata, and importing what we need. And
we discovered how to bootstrap the
component we built to bring our
application to life. Lastly, we discussed
the Angular compiler and where to find
syntax and compiler error messages in case
something goes wrong. Here, again, is our
application architecture. In this module,
we rebuilt the app component and have the
very basics of our application working.
Next up, let's take a closer look at
templates and how Angular can power them
up with binding and directives as we start
building the product list component.