The goal of this course was to guide you
down the right path, making your own
adventures with Angular more pleasant and
productive. Let's recap our journey and
review the answers to the key questions we
identified at the beginning of this
course. What is a component? We discovered
that a component is a view defined with a
template, logic defined with the class,
and meta data defined with a decorator.
Where do we put the HTML for our user
interface? Either in the metadata using
the template property or in a separate
HTML file using the template URL property
in the metadata. When should we use
binding? Any time we want to display a
component class property value in the
view, when we want to control the DOM by
setting a DOM element property in code,
when we want to respond to user actions,
and when we want to display a component
class property and update the property
when the user makes a change. Why do we
need a service? We uncovered several
reasons for building a service: to
implement functionality that is
independent from any particular component,
to share data and logic across components,
and to encapsulate external interactions,
such as with data access. And how? How do
we build an Angular application? With code
that looks like this. Export a class,
attach a decorator. and import what we
need. Then put each component directive
and pipe in its appropriate Angular
module. Leverage the Angular CLI for
creating building, testing, and deploying
your Angular application. Along the way,
each module provided a set of checklists
containing steps and tips. Feel free to
revisit and reference these checklists as
you start building your own Angular applications.