This course covered the basics, but there
is so much more. On Pluralsight, the
Angular: First Look course provides a
comparison of AngularJS to the newer
versions of Angular and presents a more
full‑featured sample application. The
Angular CLI course covers much more about
the Angular CLI. Angular Reactive Forms
covers building and validating data entry
forms with Angular and details basic CRUD,
or create, read, update, and delete,
operations using HTTP. In the Angular
Routing course, you'll learn how to define
more complex routes, pass data to routes,
guard your routes, preload data for your
views, lazy load routes for better
performance, and much more. Angular
Component Communication provides effective
solutions for tracking and sharing state
and sending notifications between
components. This course teaches you
numerous communication techniques and,
more importantly, which to use when.
Angular Fundamentals expands on the basics
and covers more intermediate information
on every key aspect of Angular. And Unit
Testing in Angular teaches you everything
you need to know to unit test your Angular
projects, including testing services,
component templates, and dealing with
asynchronous code. In addition to courses,
the Angular documentation is very
comprehensive and is a great reference to
everything Angular. And I've set up a
GitHub repository for this course so you
can use it as a starting point or learning
aid. It provides starter files if you want
to try building an application yourself,
or you can review the completed course files here.