At the beginning of this course, we
defined Angular as a JavaScript framework
for building client‑side applications
using HTML, CSS, and a language such as
JavaScript. But this is a somewhat narrow
view of Angular, focusing on using it just
for client‑side web applications. But
Angular is actually so much more. A better
definition is that Angular is a platform.
It supports multiple languages, multiple
templating syntaxes, and multiple
rendering targets. It has features to
support mobile web, such as material
design, a set of widgets that work across
devices, Angular Universal to prerender
views on the server, and web workers for
background processing. And Angular
supports native mobile development using
products such as Ionic and NativeScript.
Keep an eye on Pluralsight and Angular.io
for more information on these exciting technologies.