As we've seen throughout this course,
Angular modules are a key part of any
Angular application. Welcome back to
Angular: Getting Started, from
Pluralsight. My name is Deborah Kurata,
and in this course module, we focus on
Angular modules and how to use them to
better organize our code. Ooh, it's so
beautiful! No, it's not a van Gogh, not
even a Picasso, and yeah, it sort of looks
like a metro map. This is a picture of
what our application could look like if we
leverage the power of Angular modules.
Instead of one large app module like we
have now, there are multiple modules, and
each piece of our application has a
logical place within one of those modules.
This keeps each module smaller and more
manageable. In this course module, we take
another look at the definition and purpose
of an Angular module. We then focus in on
the Angular module metadata to better
understand how to use it. We leverage that
knowledge to create a feature module for
our application and take it one step
further, defining a shared module to
reduce duplication. Lastly, we re‑examine
our application's root Angular module. Let's get started.