What is an Angular module? As we've seen
earlier in this course, an Angular module
is a class with an NgModule decorator. Its
purpose? To organize the pieces of our
application, arrange them into cohesive
blocks of functionality, and extend our
application with capabilities from
external libraries. Angular modules
provide the environment for resolving the
directives and pipes in our component's
templates. We'll talk more about this in a
few moments. And modules are a great way
to selectively aggregate classes from
other modules and re‑export them in a
consolidated convenience module.
BrowserModule, HTTPModule, and
RouterModule are all examples of this, and
we'll create our own convenience module
when we build a shared module a little
later. An Angular module can be loaded
eagerly when the application starts, or it
can be lazy loaded asynchronously by the
router. Lazy loading is out of the scope
of this course but is discussed in detail
in my Angular Routing course here on
Pluralsight. How does an Angular module
organize our application? An Angular
module declares each component, directive,
and pipe that it manages. Every component,
directive, and pipe we create belongs to
an Angular module. An Angular module
bootstraps our root application component,
defining the component needed to display
our first template. An Angular module can
export components, directives, pipes, and
even other Angular modules, making them
available for other modules to import and
use. An Angular module imports other
Angular modules. This brings in the
exported functionality from those imported
modules. An Angular module can register
service providers with the Angular
injector, making the services available to
any class in the application. We can think
of an Angular module as a box. Inside that
box, we declare each of our components. If
those components need any functionality,
that functionality also needs to be
defined within this box. The AppComponent
sets up the routing for our main menu
using routerLink and includes the
router‑outlet directive, so it needs the
routing directives Router service and
Routes, which are defined in RouterModule.
The ProductListComponent uses NgModel, so
it needs the FormsModule. The
ProductListComponent also uses ngFor and
ngIf, so it needs the BrowserModule. The
ProductListComponent uses the pipe, so it
needs that too. The ProductListComponent
also uses the starRating component's
directive, so it needs that as well. And
so on until the box contains everything
that each of our components needs. Saying
this another way, for each component that
belongs to an Angular module, that Angular
module provides the environment for
template resolution. The module defines
which set of components, directives, and
pipes are available to the component's
template. Each declared component's
template is resolved using only the
capabilities provided within that module.
Let's look at our ProductListComponent as
an example. The ProductListComponent's
template uses NgModel, so NgModel must be
available within this module. We achieve
that by importing the Angular FormsModule.
The ProductListComponent's template also
uses a directive we created, the
StarComponent, so the StarComponent must
be available within this module. Since the
StarComponent is one we created, we can
either declare the StarComponent within
the module directly, or we can import
another module that exports the
StarComponent. Importing an Angular module
brings in the functionality exported by
that module. And we'd need to do one or
the other, never both. We didn't need to
think about template resolution much in
our sample application up until now,
because all of the pieces of our
application are in one Angular module. But
we will need to keep this in mind as we
split our application into multiple
Angular modules. Let's take a quick look
at our current AppModule. Here is the
Angular module we've defined throughout
this course. It is the application's root
Angular module, and by convention is
called at AppModule. The AppModule imports
the system Angular modules we need,
including the RouterModule, which is where
we configured our routes. It declares each
component and pipe that we created in this
course, and it bootstraps the application
with the root application component,
AppComponent. We have a lot of information
in here, and we're mixing up basic
application pieces such as our
WelcomeComponent with pieces specific to
our product feature. Let's journey through
the NgModule metadata to better understand
how Angular modules work, so we can then
refactor our AppNodule into multiple modules for better code organization,