As we have seen, every Angular application
has at least one Angular module called the
root application module or AppModule. And
an Angular application has at least one
component called the root application
component or AppComponent. The AppModule
bootstraps the AppComponent to provide the
directive used in the index.html file. We
covered the bootstrapping process in the
Introduction to Components module earlier
in this course. The bootstrap array of the
NgModule decorator defines the component
that is the starting point of the
application. This is the component that is
loaded when the application is launched.
Here are some things to keep in mind when
using the bootstrap array. Every
application must bootstrap at least one
component, the root application component.
We do this by simply adding the root
application component to the bootstrap
array of the root application module. The
bootstrap array should only be used in the
root application module, AppModule. As we
build other Angular modules, we won't use the bootstrap array.