Every component directive and pipe we
create is declared by an Angular module.
We use the declarations array of the
NgModule decorator to define the
components, directives, and pipes that
belong to this Angular module. Here are
some things to keep in mind when using the
declarations array. Every component
directive and pipe we create has to belong
to one and only one Angular module. In our
sample application, all of our components
are defined in one Angular module,
AppModule. It would be better to divide
the components into multiple modules with
basic application pieces in the AppModule
and feature pieces inappropriate feature
modules. We'll do that a little later in
this course module. As we separate out our
pieces, it is important to remember that
each component directive and pipe belongs
to one and only one Angular module. Only
declare components, directives, and pipes.
Don't add other classes, services, or
modules to the declarations array. Never
re‑declare components, directives, or
pipes that belong to another module. This
is a corollary to truth number 1. If we
re‑declare, then the component directive
or pipe no longer belongs to one and only
one Angular module. For example, the
StarComponent directive belongs to Module
B, so we should never re‑declare
StarComponent in Module A. We should only
declare components, directives, and pipes
that belong to this module. All declared
components, directives, and pipes are
private by default. They are only
accessible to other components,
directives, and pipes declared in the same
module. So if we declare the StarComponent
in Module B, by default that component is
not available to components in other
Angular modules. We share components,
directives, and pipes by exporting them.
We'll talk more about exporting in a few
moments. The Angular module provides the
template resolution environment for its
component's templates. When we include a
component in the declarations array of an
Angular module, the component belongs to
that Angular module. That component's
template, directives, and pipes are then
resolved within that module. When we use a
directive in a components template,
Angular looks to the module for the
definition of that directive. If the
component defining that directive is not
declared within the same Angular module or
exported from an imported module, Angular
won't find the directive and will generate
an error. For this example, the
StarComponent must be declared in the same
module as the ProductListComponent, or the
StarComponent must be exported from an imported module. Never both.