The exports array of the NG module
decorator allows us to share an Angular
module's components, directives, and pipes
with other modules. We can export any of
this module's components, directives, and
pipes so they can be pulled in when
another module imports this module. We can
also re‑export system Angular modules such
as forms module and HTTP module. We can
re‑export third‑party modules such as
material design. Material design is a set
of high‑quality user interface components,
including buttons and dialogues, and we
can re‑export our own modules. Here are
some things to keep in mind when using the
exports array. Export any component,
directive, or pipe if another component
needs it. A module can export any of its
declared components directives or pipes.
Re‑export modules to re‑export their
components, directives, and pipes. This is
useful when consolidating features for
multiple modules to build a convenience or
shared module. We can re‑export something
without importing it first. An Angular
module only needs to import the
components, directives, and pipes that are
required by the components declared in the
module, but the Angular module can still
provide capabilities to other modules that
import it by re‑exporting. In this
example, a shared module exports the forms
module, even though it did not import it.
So any module that imports the shared
module will have access to the NG model
and other forms directives. We'll see this
in an upcoming demo. Never export a
service. Services added to the provider's
array of an Angular module are registered
with the root application injector, making
them available for injection into any
class in the application, so there is no
point in exporting them. They are already shared throughout the application.