An Angular module can be extended by
importing capabilities from other Angular
modules. The imports array of the NgModule
decorator allows us to import supporting
modules that export components,
directives, or pipes. We then use those
exported components, directives, and pipes
within the templates of components that
are declared in this module. Many Angular
system libraries are Angular modules such,
as the FormsModule and HttpModule we've
used in this course. We can import Angular
modules to use their capabilities. Many
third party libraries are also Angular
modules such, as Material Design. We can
import third party Angular modules to use
their capabilities. We can import our own
modules to extend our application with
additional features or share capabilities
across several modules. We'll see that in
an upcoming demo. And we could separate
out our route configurations into its own
module or a set of modules and import
that. Here are some things to keep in mind
when using the imports array. Importing a
module makes available any exported
components, directives, and pipes from
that module. Recall that we're using
NgModel in our ProductList component for
two‑way binding. The NgModel directive is
exported in the FormsModule. By importing
the FormsModule into our AppModule, we can
use NgModel in any component declared in
our AppModule. Only import what this
module needs. Only import modules whose
exported components, directives, or pipes
are needed by this module's component
templates. Don't import anything this
module does not need. Importing a module
does not provide access to its imported
modules. Hmm, let's look at that with a
picture. Here we have AppModule, which
declares the ProductList‑Component and a
SharedModule that declares and exports the
StarComponent. AppModule imports the
SharedModule, so the SharedModule's
exports are available to the AppModule's
component templates. This means that the
ProductList‑Component can use the
StarComponent directive. If the
SharedModule imports FormsModule, then the
FormsModules exports are available to the
SharedModule, and the StarComponent could
use the NgModel directive. But the
FormsModule exports are not available to
the AppModule. So the
ProductList‑Component could not use the
NgModel directive. I've heard this rule
also stated another way. Imports are not
inherited. Note, however, that if the
SharedModule re‑exported the FormsModule,
then the FormsModule exports are available
to the AppModule. And the
ProductList‑Component could use the
NgModel directive. So when thinking about
the relationship between modules, think of
a module more as a box than as a tree structure.