Angular modules can also register service
providers for our application. However,
this is no longer recommended practice.
Starting with Angular Version 6, the
recommended way to register service
providers for our application is to use
the providedIn property of the service
itself, not the providers array of the
Angular module. Because you may see older
code use the providers array to register
services, I'll still cover it. Here are
some things to keep in mind when using the
ng module providers array. Any service
provider added to the providers array is
registered at the root of the application,
so the service is available to be injected
into any class in the application. Say,
for example, we have a future module
called ProductModule. We add the
ProductService to the providers array of
this module. At first glance, we may think
we have encapsulated the product service
into the product module, but that is not
the case. Any service provider added to
the providers array is registered at the
root of the application and is available
to any class, even classes and other
feature modules. So if we want to ensure
our particular service is encapsulated and
only accessible within a specific
component or a set of components, add the
service provider to the providers array of
an appropriate component, instead of an
Angular module. Note that this is not the
case for lazy loaded services. See the
Angular documentation for more information
on lazy loading. Don't add services to the
providers array of a shared module. As
discussed in the services and dependency
injection course module, there should only
be one instance of a service that is an
application wide singleton, so a service
should not be included in the providers
array for any module that is meant to be
shared. Instead, consider building a
CoreModule for services and importing it
once in the AppModule. This will help
ensure that the services are only
registered one time. We could even add
code to the code module's constructor to
ensure that it is never imported a second
time. See the Angular documentation for
details. Now that we've covered the basics
of the ng module decorator, let's refactor
our application into multiple Angular modules.