So far in this course, we created the root
application module, AppModule. It declares
all of our components and our pipe. It
imports the system Angular modules that
our components need, but this is getting a
little unwieldy. We have no separation of
responsibilities. Here we are mixing our
basic application features, such as the
WelcomeComponent, with our product
features, such as the product components,
with our shared features, such as the
StarComponent. As we add more feature sets
to this application, such as customer
management, invoicing, and so on, this is
only going to get harder to manage. So
let's reorganize and refactor to break
this into multiple Angular modules. The
first thing we want to do is extract some
of these pieces into feature sets. We can
then create a feature module for each
feature set. Using feature modules helps
us partition our application into logical
groupings with separate concerns. Our
first step is to define a new feature
module. Creating a feature module involves
defining a new module file, ProductModule
in this example, and reorganizing the
pieces of the application so that all of
the associated feature pieces and
everything they need are here in this
module. In the declarations array of the
feature module, we add the appropriate
components that provide the features for
the application. In this example, we add
the ProductList component and
ProductDetail component. Then, as we did
with the box example at the beginning of
this course module, we start to look at
what each component needs. In this
example, the ProductList component uses
the pipe, so we need that. And both the
ProductList and ProductDetail components
use the StarComponent, so we'll need that
here as well. But that's not enough. The
ProductLisT ‑ Component uses NgModel and
NgFor, and both components use NgIf and
routing. How do we get that? We import
these needed capabilities from other
Angular modules. Our product components
use routing, so we import the SystemRouter
module. The ProductList component uses
NgModel, so we import the SystemForms
module. And we need NgFor and NgIf. So do
we pull in the system BrowserModule? Nope.
The BrowserModule should only be imported
into the root application module,
AppModule. Instead, we import this system
CommonModule. The CommonModule exposes the
NgFor and NgIf directives. Not
surprisingly, the BrowserModule itself
actually imports and exports the
CommonModule, which is why we have access
to NgFor and NgIf when we import
BrowserModule in our AppModule. Our
FeatureModule is looking pretty good here.
But now that we've removed these features
from the root application module, how will
the application find all of these
features? What's that? Imports array, dDid
you say? That's correct. We need to import
the product module into the AppModule.
That extends the AppModule with the
ProductModule features. Want to try this out?