In this demo, we'll build a feature module
for our product features. We are back in
the sample application. Here is our
AppModule. Let's create a new feature
module for our product feature. Want to
try generating it with the Angular CLI? We
open the integrated terminal and type ng
for the Angular CLI, g for generate, m for
module, and the name of our module. Since
we are creating the ProductModule, we want
it in the products folder, so
products/product. That's all that's
required. But by default, Angular will
create a new folder for this module
because it rightly assumes that we'll
create the module when we define the
feature and the feature folder. But we
already have the products folder, so we'll
use the ‑‑flat option. And we want to
import this module into the AppModule to
pull in its functionality. So we use the
‑m flag, specifying the module name. Press
Enter, and we see that the CLI created the
module. It also updated our AppModule. We
can see that here. It added ProductModule
to our imports array. Yeah! Let's open the
new ProductModule. The CLI already created
the class with the @NgModule decorator and
the required import statements. Since this
module is for our product features, in the
declarations array, we add the
ProductListComponent,
ProductDetailComponent,
ConvertToSpacesPipe, and StarComponent.
Now we can remove these declarations from
the AppModule. Going back to our
ProductModule, we can see that the CLI
already included CommonModule here since
we need that in every feature module.
We'll add the FormsModule and
RouterModule. Now we can remove the
FormsModule from the AppModule and it's
associated import statement. When we added
the RouterModule to the imports array in
the AppModule, we called forRoot to pass
in the configured routes for our root
component. Now that we are adding the
RouterModule to the imports array of a
feature module, we don't call forRoot,
rather we call forChild, and there we pass
in the routes related to products. Let's
cut the product routes from the AppModule
and paste them here in our ProductModule,
and we need to import the
ProductDetailGuard. Recall that the
RouterModule registers the router service
provider, declares the router directives,
and exposes our configured routes. But as
we've discussed previously, we never want
to register a service more than once. So
when we use forRoot to pass in our
configured routes, the RouterModule knows
to register the router service provider.
When we use forChild, as we did here, the
RouterModule knows not to reregister the
router service. Note that we could also
consider moving the routes into their own
modules. We'll look at that a little
later. Do you think our application will
run? And our application works as
expected. So we now have our first working
feature module. But let's think about this
for a moment. As we build our application,
we'll build more features. Each logical
set of features will have their own
feature module. And each feature module
will most likely need the CommonModule for
common directives such as ngFor and ngIf,
the FormsModule for NgModel in two‑way
binding, and we may have other features
that want to reuse our StarComponent. Do
we really want to repeat all of this in
each feature module? There has to be a
better way. Yep, we can define a SharedModule.