The purpose of a SharedModule is to
organize a set of commonly used pieces
into one module and export those pieces so
they are available to any module that
imports the SharedModule. This allows us
to selectively aggregate our reusable
components and any external modules and
reexport them in a consolidated
convenience module. Creating a
SharedModule involves defining a new
module file, SharedModule in this example,
and reorganizing the pieces of the
application so that the shared pieces are
here in this module. First, we add the
components, directives, and pipes that we
want to share throughout our application
to the declarations array. In this
example, we only want to add the
StarComponent. Then we add to the Imports
array anything that the shared component
needs. In this example, we import the
CommonModule because our StarComponent may
need it. We don't import FormsModule
because we don't need it here. If our
StarComponent did use two‑way binding or
we added another component here that did,
we'd need to import FormsModule as well.
We then need to export everything that we
want to share. The exports array defines
what this Angular module shares with any
module that imports it. We export the
StarComponent. That way, it is available
to the components in any module that
imports the SharedModule. We reexport the
CommonModule and FormsModule so their
directives and other features are
available to any module that imports the
SharedModule. And notice here that we can
export something without importing it
first. To use the SharedModule, we import
it into every feature module that needs
the shared capabilities such as our
ProductModule. Let's give this a try. We
want to build a SharedModule and will
again use the CLI. Do you recall the
correct CLI command to generate a module?
We type ng for the Angular CLI, g for
generate, m for module, and the name of
our module since we are creating the
shared module we wanted in the shared
folder, so shared/shared. We already have
the shared folder in place, so we'll
specify the ‑‑flat option. That way, the
CLI won't create another folder. And we
want to import this module into the
ProductModule to pull in its
functionality. So we use the ‑m flag,
specifying the module path and name, press
Enter, and we see that the CLI creates the
SharedModule, and it updates our
ProductModule. We can see that here. It
added SharedModule to our imports array.
Let's open the new SharedModule. The CLI
already created the class with the
NgModule decorator and the required import
statements, and it included CommonModule
in the imports array here. Now, what did
we want to share? Well, we want to share
the StarComponent, so we add that to the
declarations array here. To share the
StarComponent, we need to export it. Let's
add an exports array and export the
StarComponent. There's a few more things
that we want to share. So we don't have to
import them into every feature module,
we'll add CommonModule and FormsModule to
the exports array. If there were other
modules we wanted to share such as
ReactiveFormsModule or Material Design, we
could add them here as well. We could also
share the ConvertToSpacesPipe. I'll leave
that up to you to add here if you wish.
Now we can remove the StarComponent,
CommonModule, and FormsModule from the
ProductModule along with their associated
import statements since these are now
already accessible from the imported
SharedModule. Are we good to go? Yep, our
application comes up as it did before.
Looking back at our code, notice now that
our feature module, ProductModule, only
contains product pieces and the
SharedModule, and the SharedModule is
clean only including the pieces we want to
share. We can reuse the SharedModule and
any future feature modules as we add functionality to our application.