We now know that every application has a
root application module that is, by
convention, called AppModule. The main
purpose of the AppModule is to orchestrate
the application as a whole. And now that
we've removed the feature and shared
pieces from this module, its purpose is
easier to see. Let's take another look.
We've reduced the code in AppModule such
that it now fits on one page. The
AppModule normally imports BrowserModule.
This is the module that every browser
application must import. BrowserModule
registers critical application service
providers. It also imports and exports
CommonModule, which declares and exports
directive such a NgIf and NgFor. These
directives are then available to any of
the AppModules component templates. We
also import HttpModule to register the
Angular HttpClientService provider. We
import RouterModule and call forRoot,
passing in the configured routes for the
root of the application. Here we configure
our default route and any wildcard routes.
Then we import each feature module. In
this example, we have only one feature
module, ProductModule. The declarations
array identifies the list of components
that belong to this module. In this
example, the root component, AppComponent,
and the application's WelcomeComponent are
declared here. The bootstrap array
identifies the root component,
AppComponent, as the bootstrap component.
When Angular launches the application, it
loads this component and displays its
template. We could take the refactoring a
step further and separate the routing into
its own module. We could create one
Angular module for our root application
routes and another Angular module for our
product feature routes. Let's go back to
the slides and see what that code would
look like. If we wanted to refactor our
root application routes into their own
module, this is what it might look like.
We export a class, at the NgModule
decorator, and import what we need. We add
the RouterModule to the imports array,
passing in our root application routes,
including our default route and our
wildcard route. Notice that we call
forRoot here to ensure that we register
the routing service provider. And we
export RouterModule so we can use it from
any module that imports this module. We
import the AppRoutingModule in the
AppModule here. Note that the
AppRoutingModule is listed after the
ProductModule in the imports array. This
is required because Angular registers the
routes based on the order of the modules
specified here. The ProductModule is
listed first, so it registers the product
routes first. Then the AppRoutingModule
registers the application routes,
including the wildcard route. If the
AppRoutingModule was before the
ProductModule, then the wildcard route
would be registered before the product
routes and the product routes would never
be accessible. So the AppRoutingModule
with the wildcard route should always be
last in this list. We can do the same to
refactor our product feature routes into
their own module. The key difference here
is when we import RouterModule in any
feature module, we pass the configured
routes to the forChild method instead of
the forRoot method. This ensures that we
don't register the routing service
provider a second time, and we import this
ProductRoutingModule into the
ProductModule as shown here. Now let's
finish up this course module with some checklists and a summary.