Your application architecture depends on
many factors, including the size and scope
of the application you are working on,
your team's size and experience, and your
project's goals. But here are some
suggestions based on what we covered in
this course module. Every application must
always have a root application module, by
convention called AppModule. This is
normally the module that bootstraps the
root application component, AppComponent.
For smaller applications, this could be
the only Angular module for the
application, as was the case with our
sample application prior to this course
module. As the application gets more
features, consider defining a separate
Angular module for each feature set. For
example, a product module, a customer
module in an invoice module. This keeps
the code organized, separates the
concerns, and prevents the AppModule from
getting excessively large and unwieldy. As
you add feature modules, you might find
components, pipes, and directives that you
want to share across feature modules.
Define one or more shared modules for
these shared pieces. Shared modules
primarily used the exports and
declarations arrays, with most of the
declared pieces exported as well. And as
we discussed in the last clip, we can also
refactor our routes into their own routing
modules. When creating an Angular module,
we build a class and decorate it with the
ng module decorator. The ng module
metadata includes the bootstrap array for
defining the list of startup components.
In many cases, there is only one, the root
component of the application. The
declarations array declares which
components, directives, and pipes belong
to this module. The exports array
identifies the list of components,
directives, and pipes that an importing
module can use The imports array lists
supporting modules. These modules provide
components, directives, and pipes needed
by the components in this module. The
providers array lists the service
providers. Angular registers each provider
with Angular's root application injector,
so these services are available to be
injected into any class in the
application. This course module was all
about Angular modules. We took a second
look at the definition and purpose of an
Angular module. We then focused in on the
Angular module metadata and covered the
truths to keep in mind when using that
metadata. We leveraged that knowledge to
create a feature module for our
application and took it one step further,
defining a shared module to reduce
duplication in our application. Lastly, we
reexamined our application root Angular
module and saw how it orchestrates the
application as a whole. If you are
building a small application, such as the
sample application we've created in this
course, you may only need the one root
application module, as shown here. But as
your application grows, you'll want to
refactor into feature modules and shared
modules like this. Here we organized our
application into multiple modules. We have
our feature module, ProductModule, that
encapsulates all of the product features.
There will be more feature modules as our
application grows. We have our
SharedModule that shares commonly used
components, directives, and pipes with any
module that imports it. Currently, we
import it into the ProductModule. As we
build more feature modules, we'll import
it into them as well. And we have our
AppModule that orchestrates the
application. Each feature module is added
to the AppModule's imports array to extend
the application with those features. Oh,
it's been quite a journey. Now let's
circle back to the beginning and spend a little more time with the Angular CLI.