Components are great and all, but what do
we do with data or logic that is not
associated with a specific view or that we
want to share across components? We build
services. Welcome back to Angular: Getting
Started, from Pluralsight. Deborah Kurata
here at your service, and in this module,
we create a service and use dependency
injection to inject that service into any
component that needs it. Applications
often require services such as a product
data service or a logging service. Our
components depend on these services to do
the heavy lifting. Wouldn't it be nice if
Angular could serve us up those services
on a platter? Well, yes, it can. But what
are services exactly? A service is a class
with a focused purpose. We often create a
service to implement functionality that is
independent from any particular component
to share data or logic across components
or encapsulate external interactions such
as data access. By shifting these
responsibilities from the component to a
service, the code is easier to test,
debug, and reuse. In this module, we start
with an overview of how services and
dependency injection work in Angular. Then
we'll build a service, we'll register that
service, and we'll examine how to use the
service in a component. We currently have
several pieces of our application in
place, but we hardcoded our data directly
in the Product List Component. In this
module, we'll shift the responsibility for
providing the product data to a product data service. Let's get started.