Before we jump into building a service,
let's take a look at how services and
dependency injection work in Angular. In
this diagram our service is here, and our
component that needs the service is here.
There are two ways our component can work
with this service. The component can
create an instance of the service class
and use it. That simple, and it works. But
the instance is local to the component, so
we can't share data or other resources,
and it will be more difficult to mock the
service for testing. Alternatively, we can
register the service with Angular. Angular
then creates a single instance of the
service class, called a singleton, and
holds onto it. Specifically, Angular
provides a built‑in injector. We register
our services with the Angular injector,
which maintains a container of created
service instances. The injector creates
and manages the single instance, or
singleton, of each registered service as
required. In this example, the Angular
injector is managing instances of three
different services: log, math, and my
service, which is abbreviated svc. If our
component needs a service, the component
class defines the service as a dependency.
The Angular injector then provides, or
injects, the service class instance when
the component class is instantiated. This
process is called dependency injection.
Since Angular manages the single instance,
any data or logic in that instance is
shared by all of the classes that use it.
This technique is the recommended way to
use services because it provides better
management of service instances, it allows
sharing of data and other resources, and
it's easier to mock the services for
testing purposes. Now let's look at a more
formal definition of dependency injection.
Dependency injection is a coding pattern
in which a class receives the instances of
objects it needs, called its dependencies,
from an external source rather than
creating them itself. In Angular, this
external source is the Angular injector.
Now that we've got a general idea of how
services and dependency injection work in Angular, let's build a service.