Are we ready to build a service? Here are
the steps. Create the service class to
find the metadata with the decorator, and
import what we need. Look familiar? These
are the same basic steps we follow to
build our components and our custom pipe.
Let's look at the code for a simple
service. Here is the class, we export it
so the service can be used from any other
parts of the application. This class
currently has one method, getProducts.
This method returns an array of products.
Next, we add a decorator for the service
metadata. When building services, we often
use the Injectable decorator. Lastly, we
import what we need, in this case
Injectable. Now let's build our service.
I've opened the folder for the sample
application in the editor once again.
Since our service will only provide
product data, we'll add it to the products
folder. We'll create a new file and call
it productservice.ts to follow our naming
conventions. We're then ready to create
the service class. I bet you can do it in
your sleep by now. Export class and the
class name. Since the service provides
products, we'll call it ProductService.
Next, we decorate the class with the
Injectable decorator, and we'll add the
import statement for that decorator. Now
that we have the structure in place, we
can add properties or methods to the class
as needed. Unless marked private or
protected, the properties and methods
defined in the class are accessible to any
class that uses this service. For our
ProductService, we want a getProducts
method that returns the list of products.
We strongly type this return value using
our IProduct interface, so we need to
import this interface. In the next module,
we'll see how to retrieve the products
using HTTP. For now, we'll hard code them
in here. If you're coding along, feel free
to copy some products from the
products.json file in the api products
folder. Notice that we have no properties
defined in this class, so we are not using
this particular service to share data. We
are using it to encapsulate the data
access features. By using the service to
provide the list of products, we take the
responsibility for managing the data away
from the individual component, that makes
it easier to modify or reuse this logic.
So we're done with our service for now.
How do we use it? Well, a service is just
really an ordinary class until we register
it with an Angular injector. Let's do that next.