As we illustrated in this diagram, we
register the service with the Angular
injector, and the injector provides the
service instance to any component that
injects it using the constructor. The
injector represented here is the root
application injector, but wait, there's
more. In addition to the root application
injector, Angular has an injector for each
component, mirroring the component tree. A
service registered with the root
application injector is available to any
component or other service in the
application. A service registered with a
specific component is only available to
that component and its child or nested
components. For example, if a service is
registered with the ProductList components
injector, the service is only available
for injection in the ProductList component
and its child, the StarComponent. So when
should you register your service with the
root injector versus a component injector?
Registering a service with the root
injector ensures that the service is
available throughout the application. In
most scenarios, you'll register the
service with the root injector. If you
register a service with a component
injector, the service is only available to
that component and it's child or nested
components. This isolates a service that
is used by only one component and its
children, and it provides multiple
instances of the service for multiple
instances of the component. For example,
we have multiple instances of the
StarComponent on the ProductList page, one
for each row. If we had a service that
tracks some settings for each
StarComponent instance, we would want
multiple instances of the service, one for
each instance of the component, but this
is not a common scenario. With that, the
next question is how, how do we register a
service? That depends on which injector we
use. We register the service with the root
application injector in the service. We
pass an object into the Injectable
decorator and set the providedIn property
to root. We can then access the service
from any component or other service in the
application. We want to use our
ProductService in several components, so
we'll register it with the root
application injector. Let's do that now.
Here in the service, we add the providedIn
property to the Injectable decorator, and
set it to root. An instance of the
ProductService is then available for
injection anywhere in the application, but
what if we only wanted to access the
service from one component instead? For
most scenarios, we'll register our service
in the service using the providedIn
property. The service is then available to
the entire application. To register our
service for a specific component, such as
the ProductList component, we register the
service in that component like this. The
service is then available to the component
and its child components. Note that the
providedIn feature is new in Angular
version 6. In older code, you'll see the
service registered in a module like this.
This syntax is still valid; however, the
recommended practice is to use the new
providedIn feature in the service instead.
This provides better tree shaking. Tree
shaking is a process whereby the Angular
compiler shakes out unused code for
smaller deployed bundles. We'll talk more
about tree shaking later in this course.
Now that we've registered the service,
let's see how to inject the service so we can use it.