Here again is our diagram. In the last
clip, we saw how to register the service
with the Angular injector. Now we just
need to define it as a dependency so the
injector will provide the instance in the
classes that need it. So how do we do
dependency injection in Angular? Well, the
better question is, how do we do
dependency injection in TypeScript? The
answer is in the constructor. Every class
has a constructor that is executed when an
instance of the class is created. If there
is no explicit constructor defined for the
class, an implicit constructor is used,
but if we want to inject dependencies such
as an instance of a service, we need an
explicit constructor. In TypeScript, a
constructor is defined with a constructor
function. What type of code normally goes
into the constructor function? As little
as possible. Since the constructor
function is executed when the component is
created, it is primarily used for
initialization and not for code that has
side effects or takes time to execute. We
identify our dependencies by specifying
them as parameters to the constructor
function like this. Here we define a
private variable to hold the injected
service instance. We create another
variable as the constructor parameter.
When this class is constructed, the
Angular injector sets this parameter to
the injected instance of the requested
service. We then assign the injected
service instance to our local variable. We
can then use this variable anywhere in our
class to access service properties or
methods. This is such a common pattern
that TypeScript defined a shorthand syntax
for all of this code. We simply add the
accessor keyword, such as private here, to
the constructor parameter. Then this is a
shortcut for declaring this variable,
defining a parameter, and setting the
variable to the parameter. Neat! You'll
see this technique used throughout the
Angular documentation and other code
examples. Ready to give it a try? We want
to use our service to get products in the
product list component. So we'll define
our product service as a dependency in the
product list component. We don't have to
add the providers array here, because the
product service is already registered. All
we need is a constructor, and we already
have one here. We'll use the shorthand
syntax to define the dependency; private
productService. Then because we are using
TypeScript, we type colon and the type,
which is ProductService. Note that the
excessor doesn't have to be private. This
shorthand syntax works with public and
protected as well. So now we have a syntax
error here. I bet you know why. Yes, we
need to import ProductService so we can
use it as the data type here. Now, when an
instance of the product list component is
created, the Angular injector injects in
the instance of the product service. We
are at the point now where we can actually
use the product service. First, let's
delete the hard‑coded products from here.
We'll instead get them from the service.
Now the question is, where should we put
the code to call the service? One thought
might be to put it in the constructor, but
ultimately our product service will go out
to a back‑end server to get the data. We
don't want all of that executed in the
constructor. Other thoughts? Remember our
discussion about lifecycle hooks? Earlier
in this course, we said that OnInit
lifecycle hook provides a place to perform
any component initialization, and it's a
great place to retrieve the data for the
template. Let's use the OnInit lifecycle
hook. We want to set the products property
to the products returned from our service.
To call the service, we use our private
variable containing the injected server
instance. We then type a dot and the name
of the method we want to call. Notice how
IntelliSense helps us with all of this.
There is a small problem with our code at
this point. Since the constructor is
executed before the ngOnInit, the list of
products will be empty here. We want to
set our filtered list of products to this
list of products, so we need to move this
line of code to the ngOnInit as well.
Let's make one more little change. Let's
remove the default list filter value so
we'll see all of the products in the list.
We should be all set to see our result in
the browser. And here are our products.
Yay! Notice that we have more products
displayed now, because I hard‑coded more
products into the service. Let's finish up
this module with some checklists we can use as we build our services.