We build a service using the same
techniques as when we build components and
custom pipes. We start by creating the
Service class. We specify a clear class
name appropriate for the services it
provides. Use PascalCasing where each word
of the name is capitalized, append service
to the name, and don't forget the export
keyword. We then decorate the Service
class with the Injectable decorator. Don't
forget the @ prefix, and since the
decorator is a function, follow it with
open and closing parentheses, and be sure
to define the appropriate imports. The
first step to registering a service is to
select the appropriate level in the
injector hierarchy that the service should
be registered. Use the root application
injector if the service is shared
throughout the application. If only one
component and its children needs the
service, register it with that component's
injector. Pick one or the other, not both.
Register a service with the root injector
using the Injectable decorator of the
service. Set the providedIn property to
root. Register a service for a specific
component and its children using its
Component decorator. Use the providers
property to register the service. In any
class that needs the service, specify the
service as a dependency. Use a constructor
parameter to define the dependency. The
Angular injector will inject an instance
of the service when the component is
instantiated. This module was all about
services. We began with an overview of how
services and dependency injection work in
Angular. Then we walked through how to
build a simple service. We defined how and
where to register the service with
Angular, and we examined how to define the
service as a dependency so the service
instance is injected into any class that
needs it. In this module, we built the
product data service, so our product list
component no longer has hard‑coded
products. Next up, we'll see how to modify the service to retrieve data using HTTP.