TypeScript is the language we use when
working with Angular. Because we'll use
TypeScript throughout this course, let's
take a moment to look at what TypeScript
is all about. But first things first.
Let's talk about JavaScript. JavaScript is
the language for the web and is executed
by all browsers. The JavaScript language
specification standard is officially
called ECMAScript, or ES. Up until
recently, the ES versions were defined by
a sequential number. ES3 is supported by
older browsers. ES5 is supported by most
modern browsers. The ES6 specification was
renamed ES2015 and introduced many key new
features, such as classes and arrow
functions, as we'll see later in this
course. Since then, a new version of the
specification has been released each year.
Any newer JavaScript features that we use,
but a browser doesn't support, must first
be transpiled. What does that mean? Newer
JavaScript features in our code must be
compiled by a tool that converts the newer
JavaScript syntax to comparable older
syntax before the browser executes it.
TypeScript is an open source language
developed by Microsoft. It is a superset
of JavaScript, meaning all JavaScript is
valid TypeScript. TypeScript code
transpiles to plain JavaScript. What does
that mean? Code developed with TypeScript
must be compiled and converted to
comparable JavaScript syntax before the
browser executes it. That way we, as
developers, get the benefits of TypeScript
features during development, and the
browser still get code they understand.
One of the key benefits of TypeScript is
at strong typing, meaning that everything
has a data type. Because of the strong
typing, TypeScript has great tooling,
including inline documentation, syntax
checking, code navigation, and advanced
refactorings. So TypeScript helps us
better reason about our code. And
TypeScript implements the ES2015
class‑based object orientation, plus more.
It implements classes, interfaces, and
inheritance. So if you have experience
with an object‑oriented programming
language, such a C#, C++, or Java, using
TypeScript may feel very natural to you.
This course does not require any prior
knowledge of TypeScript. I'll cover what
you need as you need it. But if you want
to learn more about TypeScript, check out
the TypeScript playground. This website
allows you to do live coding with
TypeScript, see the transpiled JavaScript,
and run the result, all without installing
anything. There are also several
TypeScript courses in the Pluralsight
library, including TypeScript: Getting
Started and TypeScript Fundamentals.
Again, you do not have to know TypeScript
for this course. We'll learn it as we go.
Now let's install what we need to get started building our Angular application.