The first step in our journey is to
install what we need, starting with a code
editor. There are many editors that
support TypeScript either out of the box
or with a plugin. We'll select one of the
most common editors used by Angular
developers, Visual Studio Code, often just
called VS Code. You are welcome to use
your editor of choice, but keep in mind
that your experience with TypeScript will
be much more pleasurable if you select an
editor that understands TypeScript. If
your project requires use of Visual
Studio, consider learning Angular using VS
Code first. Then migrate your skills to
Visual Studio. You'll be glad you did. So
what is VS Code? It's a code editor
created by Microsoft. It runs in Linux,
Windows, and OS X on a Mac. It has great
features that support TypeScript coding,
such as auto‑completion, IntelliSense,
syntax checking, and refactorings. It also
integrates well with source control, such
as Microsoft's TFS and GitHub. And it's
free. If you don't have VS Code installed,
you can download and install it from this
URL. Select the install appropriate for
your OS. Consider pausing the course and
installing VS Code now if you don't
already have it. VS Code is easy to use,
and I'll demonstrate its features as we
progress through this course. If you want
to learn more about VS Code, check out
their website or this Pluralsight course.
Now that we have a code editor installed, there is one more thing we need.