As we prepare for our Angular journey,
there is something more to install before
we begin, npm, which stands for Node
package manager. What's that, you ask? You
can think of npm as two things. First,
it's an online registry or repository of
open source and free libraries and
packages. It contains many JavaScript
packages, such as Angular, TypeScript, and
Bootstrap, which is a web‑styling
framework. Second, npm is a command‑line
utility for interacting with that
repository. We can type commands such as
npm install some library name. Npm will
locate the specified library in the
repository and install it on your local
machine in a subfolder of the current
folder named node_modules. In this
illustration, I'm in the user's Deborah
folder and install a specific package, the
fictitious abc package in this example.
After executing the install command, npm
locates the abc package in the repository,
creates a node_modules subfolder in the
current folder, and installs the specified
library and its dependencies in that
subfolder. So npm is a repository and a
command‑line utility you can use to access
that repository. Npm has become the
package manager for JavaScript
applications. With npm, we can install
libraries, packages, and applications,
along with their dependencies. We'll need
npm to install all the libraries for
Angular. The npm command‑line utility can
also execute scripts to perform tasks such
as running our application, as we'll see
shortly. Before we can use npm to install
other things or execute our scripts, we
need to install npm. But we can't install
npm directly. We install it by installing
Node using this link. Let's take a look.
Following this link takes us to the
download page for Node, which installs
npm. Angular minimally requires this
version of npm. Then select the installer
appropriate for your OS. Feel free to
pause the course here and install Node now
if you don't already have it. Installing
Node installs npm. Before we move on,
let's check our npm version. Open a
command window and type npm ‑v, for
version. Be sure you have at least this
version of npm. We now have a code editor
and the required version of npm installed. Do we need anything else?