Now that we have npm installed, we could
use it to install everything else we need.
So what else do we need? Well, we need the
Angular libraries that comprise the
Angular framework. We'll want the Angular
CLI, which is the command line interface
for Angular. We can use the CLI to
generate code, execute our application,
deploy it to production, and much more as
we'll see throughout this course. We need
TypeScript, which is the language we use
with Angular, and we'll want testing
tools, linters, and other supporting
libraries. So, do we need to manually
install each of these with npm? Luckily,
the answer to that question is no, at
least not directly. A more common practice
is to define a package.json file that
lists each package we need for our Angular
application. And as you can see, there are
many of them. We can also specify the
desired version of each package. We then
tell npm to use the package.json file to
install all of the defined packages along
with their dependencies. In the
package.json file, the list of packages is
divided into two parts. The dependencies
list is for the packages we need for
development that must also be deployed.
The devDependencies list is for the
packages we only need for development. The
dependencies list includes the primary
Angular packages, along with supporting
packages, such a RxJS for working with
data. The devDependencies include the
Angular CLI. Here is a linter which
evaluates our code for best practices.
TypeScript is here in the devDependencies
since we transpile the code to JavaScript
before deployment. And many of these are
for unit and end‑to‑end code tests. By
defining a package.json file for our
Angular application, we ensure everyone on
the team installs the appropriate packages
and versions. We'll see how to install all
of the packages in the package.json file as we set up our Angular application next.