I've already set up the package.json file
for the Angular application we'll build
throughout this course. I've also set up
the support files, style sheets, and data.
These files are available in my GitHub
repository at this link. We'll create an
Angular application from scratch later in
this course. For now, using these starter
files allows us to get going quickly
building our Angular application. Let's
download these files now. I've navigated
to my GitHub repository following the URL
from the slide. If you are comfortable
with Git, you can clone this repository.
Otherwise, click this button to download
all of the files as a single ZIP file. The
APM‑Final folder contains the completed
code for our sample application. Use these
files if you want to see the end result.
The APM‑Start folder contains the starter
files. These are the files we will use as
the starting point for building our
Angular application. After downloading the
files, copy or extract the files in the
APM‑Start folder to a working directory
called just APM, Your APM folder should
then look like this. Now let's open the
APM folder with a code editor. I've opened
the APM working folder with VS Code.
First, let's talk about the directory
structure. By convention, all of our
source files are under a folder called
src. Under that folder is an app folder
that contains the source files specific
for our application. We only have a few
folders and files here now, but we'll add
more as we progress through this course.
For applications of any size, we'll have
subfolders under the app folder for each
major feature in the application. The
other files here are configuration and
setup files, often called boilerplate
files. To get us going quickly, we won't
dive into all of these files now. We'll
learn more about them in the building,
testing, and deploying with the CLI module
later in this course. Before we can
execute this code, we need to install all
of the libraries required to develop and
run our application. Where are those
defined? In the package.json file here.
This file contains a list of all of the
application's dependencies. Toward the top
of this file is a set of scripts. We can
execute these scripts using npm. We'll
learn more about these scripts throughout
this course. For now, let's install all of
these libraries. First, open a command
prompt or terminal. VS Code has an
integrated terminal we can use, View,
Terminal. Next, navigate to the folder
containing the package.json file. VS Code
did that for us. Then type npm install.
This installs all of the dependencies
defined in the package.json file, along
with any of their dependencies. Note that
you may see some warnings and messages
during this installation process, like
these. In most cases, you can ignore them.
If you see something like this at the end,
the installation completed successfully.
If you see a message telling you to run a
fix, don't do it. Running a fix will
attempt to update the versions of some of
the packages without updating all of them,
which will cause errors when you try to
run the application. This fix message
tells you that there are vulnerabilities
and libraries that will never be deployed
anyway, like the testing libraries, so
ignore this message. Notice that we now
have a node_modules folder here. This is
where npm installed all our packages. This
folder is large, so you may want to
exclude it when you check your files into
a source control system. Now that we have
the libraries installed for our sample application, let's try running it.