I've included enough additional code with
the starter files to run the sample
application, so let's give it a try.
Remember the scripts area in our
package.json file? Here is the start
script. When we type npm start, it will
execute the command defined here. The ng
executes the Angular CLI. The string after
the ng is the CLI command. The serve
command builds the application and starts
a local web server that allows us to serve
up the application without deploying it.
The ‑o is a command option that opens the
URL in our default browser. The CLI has
many more commands and options. We'll see
more of them as we progress through this
course. Are we ready to make a go? Let's
try out this start script. Back at the
command prompt or terminal, type npm
start. This executes the start script. If
this is the first time using the Angular
CLI, you will be asked if you'd like to
share anonymous usage data with the
Angular team. This can help the team
better understand your usage scenarios.
I'll answer with y, but select whichever
option you prefer. The CLI then builds the
application, starts a web server, and
opens the URL in the default browser,
which in my case is Chrome. If all is
well, the application appears in the
browser and displays some text, as shown
here. If the text does not appear or you
see errors in the console, ensure that you
ran npm install successfully, as defined
in the prior clip. As you can see, our
application doesn't look like much, but
we'll fix that on our journey through
Angular. I've moved the windows around so
that we could see the editor, the browser,
and the terminal window. Let's see what
happens when we make a code change. In the
editor, open the app.component.html file.
Don't worry too much about the syntax here
yet. We'll talk about it shortly. For now,
we'll just change the welcome text. We
immediately see here that our code has
recompiled, the browser refreshes, and or
updated text appears. So any time we make
a change to our application, we'll be able
to immediately see the effect of that
change. That will be helpful. When we are
finished working with our files, we can
close the browser, but the server keeps
running. To stop it, go back to the
command prompt or terminal and press
Ctrl+C or Command+C and Y for Yes. Then
you can exit. Any time you want to run the
application and keep it running to watch
the effect of your code changes, simply
open the terminal and use npm start again.
So now we know how to build and run our
code. Yay! You may have noticed that I
didn't save the file after I made the code
change. When using VS Code, we can set it
to automatically save our changes. Here,
under File, Preferences, Settings,
Workspace settings, I have it set to
automatically save after a short delay.
Before we go any further, let's take a moment and talk about modules.