Module is one of those overloaded terms.
Pluralsight uses the term module to refer
to a chapter of learning content.
JavaScript, specifically ES 2015, uses the
term module for the pieces when splitting
up JavaScript programs. In ES 2015, a
module is a file, and a file is a module.
So when coding in ES 2015, we don't need
to define or name modules. Just create a
file, write some code, export or import
something, and, bang, the file becomes a
module. Angular leverages ES 2015 modules.
So as we create code files and import or
export something, we create the modules
for our application. But wait, there's
more. Angular also has Angular modules.
Angular modules are separate and different
from Angular's implementation of ES 2015
modules. Let's look first at how Angular
makes use of ES 2015 modules. Then we'll
introduce Angular modules. How do ES 2015
modules work? Say we create a code file
called product.ts and export a class named
Product from that file. This file then
becomes a module. Because the class is
exported, we can use that class in any
other module by importing it. So here we
have a file called product‑list.ts, and we
import our Product class. This file also
becomes a module because we imported
something. Notice the syntax here. In
curly braces, we define the name we want
to import, in this case Product, and we
define the file we want to import it from.
Here we want to import from product.js.
Wait. What? The Product class is in
product.ts. But when we compile, the
TypeScript file is transpiled into an ES5
JavaScript file. So at runtime, we are
importing from the .js file. But notice
that we don't list the extension here
anyway. Now let's look at Angular modules.
Angular modules help organize an
application into cohesive blocks of
functionality. Every Angular application
has at least one Angular module by
convention called app module. As an
application gets more features, we can
group those features into their own
feature modules. We can even define shared
or common modules for code used by
multiple Angular modules. This keeps the
code organized and provides a cohesive
unit we can load on Start or lazy load as
it is needed. In each Angular module, we
declare the set of components and other
code files associated with the module and
the dependencies needed by those
components. Each component we create is
declared in and belongs to one and only
one Angular module. We'll talk much more
about Angular modules throughout this
course. Let's clarify the difference
between ES 2015 modules and Angular
modules. ES modules are code files that
import or export something. Angular
modules are code files that organize the
application into cohesive blocks of
functionality. ES modules organize our
code files. Angular modules organize our
application. ES modules modularize our
code. Angular modules modularize our
application. ES modules promote code
reuse. Angular modules promote boundaries
within our application. So ES modules are
about code files, and Angular modules are
about our application. To keep these terms
straight, I'll refer to the ES 2015
modules as ES modules and Angular modules as Angular modules.