In this module, we introduced TypeScript.
TypeScript has all the productivity
features of newer versions of JavaScript,
plus strong typing for better tooling.
Next, we installed what we needed. We
installed VS Code as our code editor, and
installed Node, which installed npm, or
Node package manager. We downloaded the
starter files from my GitHub repository
and used npm to install the packages for
our Angular application, as defined in the
package.json file. We then saw how to open
this sample application in VS Code and use
npm scripts to run that application.
Lastly, we covered ES modules and how
TypeScript uses ES module syntax to export
and import functionality from our ES
modules. We introduced Angular modules and
how they organize our application and
promote application boundaries. Recall the
architecture for the sample application
that we are building that we outlined in
the first module? Since I used the Angular
CLI to create the starter files, it
created the index.html file and our root
AppComponent. In the next module, we'll
examine these files and start writing some Angular code.